<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<documentation>
  <language culture="en" />
  <language culture="de-DE" />
  <introduction lang="en">
    In cryptography, a keyed-hash message authentication code (HMAC) is a specific construction for calculating a message authentication code (MAC) involving a cryptographic hash function in combination with a secret cryptographic key.
    As with any MAC, it may be used to simultaneously verify both the data integrity and the authentication of a message. Any cryptographic hash function, such as MD5 or SHA-1, may be used in the calculation of an HMAC.
    The cryptographic strength of the HMAC depends upon the cryptographic strength of the underlying hash function and on the size and quality of the key.
    <newline /><newline />
    The size of the output of HMAC is the same as that of the underlying hash function (128 or 160 bits in the case of MD5 or SHA-1, respectively).
    <newline /><newline />
    The definition and analysis of the HMAC construction was first published in 1996 by Mihir Bellare, Ran Canetti, and Hugo Krawczyk.
    FIPS PUB 198 generalizes and standardizes the use of HMACs. HMAC-SHA1 and HMAC-MD5 are used within the IPsec and TLS protocols.
  </introduction>
  <introduction lang="de-DE">
    Ein Keyed-Hash Message Authentication Code (HMAC) ist eine Art Message Authentication Code (MAC), dessen Konstruktion auf einer kryptografischen Hash-Funktion in Verbindung mit einem geheimen Schlüssel basiert.
    Wie jeder MAC kann er sowohl die Integrität als auch die Authentizität einer Nachricht gewährleisten. Prinzipiell kann jede kryptografische Hashfunktion für die Berechnung eines HMAC verwendet werden.
    Die kryptografische Stärke des HMAC hängt von der kryptografischen Stärke der zugrunde liegenden Hashfunktion und der Größe und Qualität des verwendeten Schlüssels ab.
    <newline /><newline />
    Die Ausgabe von HMAC hat dieselbe Größe wie die Ausgabe der zugrunde liegenden Hashfunktion (128 Bits für MD5, 160 Bits für SHA-1).
    <newline /><newline />
    Die Definition und Analyse der HMAC-Konstruktion wurde erstmals 1996 von Mihir Bellare, Ran Canetti und Hugo Krawczyk veröffentlicht.
    HMACs werden in RFC 2104 sowie im NIST Standard FIPS 198 spezifiziert und kommen in IPSec und TLS zum Einsatz.
  </introduction>
  <usage lang="en">
    In the settings of the component, you can select the hash function that the HMAC algorithm should use.
    The data of which to calculate the hash value has to be entered at the input "Input stream" as a data stream.
    The key must be provided as a byte array of arbitrary length at the input labeled "Key".
    The calculated hash value is available at the outputs of the component as a data stream and as a byte array.
    The length of the hash value depends on the selected hash function and corresponds to the length of the hash value that this function produces.
  </usage>
  <usage lang="de-DE">
    Wählen Sie in den Einstellungen der Komponente die Hashfunktion aus, auf der der verwendete HMAC-Algorithmus basieren soll.
    Geben Sie die Daten, deren Hashwert berechnet werden soll, als Datenstrom am Eingang "Eingabedatenstrom" ein.
    Der Schlüssel wird als Byte-Array beliebiger Länge am entsprechend benannten Eingang erwartet.
    Der berechnete Hashwert wird an den Ausgängen der Komponente als Datenstrom und als Byte-Array ausgegeben.
    Die Länge des Hashwertes hängt von der ausgewählten Hashfunktion ab und entspricht der Länge des Hashwertes, den diese Hashfunktion produziert.
  </usage>
  <presentation lang="en"></presentation>
  <presentation lang="de-DE"></presentation>
  <references>
    <linkReference id="wikipedia">
      <link url="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Hash-based_message_authentication_code" lang="en" />
      <caption lang="en">Hash-based message authentication code (Wikipedia)</caption>
      <link url="http://de.wikipedia.org/wiki/Keyed-Hash_Message_Authentication_Code" lang="de-DE" />
      <caption lang="en">Keyed-Hash Message Authentication Code (Wikipedia)</caption>
    </linkReference>
    <linkReference id="fips">
      <link url="http://csrc.nist.gov/publications/fips/fips198/fips-198a.pdf" lang="en" />
      <caption lang="en">FIPS: The Keyed-Hash Message Authentication Code (PDF)</caption>
      <link url="http://csrc.nist.gov/publications/fips/fips198/fips-198a.pdf" lang="de-DE" />
      <caption lang="en">FIPS: The Keyed-Hash Message Authentication Code (PDF, englisch)</caption>
    </linkReference>
  </references>
</documentation>