<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<sample>
  <!--- - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - -->
  <!--File name: ADFGX_dictionary_attack.xml-->
  <!--Last edited: 2022.02.08-->
  <!--- - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - -->
  <!--- - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - -->
  <!--Language 'en' starts here:-->
  <!--- - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - -->
  <title lang="en">ADFGVX Dictionary Attack</title>
  <summary lang="en">Attack the <i>ADFGVX</i> cipher using a dictionary</summary>
  <description lang="en">This template demonstrates that one can undo the transposition of the ADFGVX cipher independently of the substitution. In this case, a dictionary attack is performed. As a result, the template provides the transposition key and coincidence index of the intermediate ciphertext where the transposition was undone. This template is only a proof-of-concept. To fully break the ADFGVX cipher, the "ADFGVX Heuristic Analysis" template can be used.</description>
  <keywords>ADFGX, World War, Telegraphy, Polybius, Square, Column, Row, Polybios, Dictionary, Attack, Analysis</keywords>
  <replacements lang="en">
    <replacement key="$Plaintext$" value="Plaintext" />
    <replacement key="$Output (Bestlist)$" value="Output (Bestlist)" />
    <replacement key="$Converter$" value="Converter" />
    <replacement key="$Dictionary$" value="Dictionary" />
    <replacement key="$Concat$" value="Concat" />
    <replacement key="$Cost function$" value="Cost function" />
    <replacement key="$Actual value$" value="Actual value" />
    <replacement key="$Threshold$" value="Threshold" />
    <replacement key="$CoincidenceGate$" value="CoincidenceGate" />
    <replacement key="$KeyGate$" value="KeyGate" />
    <replacement key="$TextGate$" value="TextGate" />
    <replacement key="$Gate$" value="Gate" />
    <replacement key="$infinity$" value="infinity" />
    <replacement key="$message$" value="In cryptography, the ADFGVX cipher was a field cipher used by the German Army on the Western Front during World War I. ADFGVX was in fact an extension of an earlier cipher called ADFGX.&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;Invented by Colonel Fritz Nebel and introduced in March 1918, the cipher was a fractionating transposition cipher which combined a modified Polybius square with a single columnar transposition.&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;The cipher is named after the six possible letters used in the ciphertext: A, D, F, G, V and X. These letters were chosen deliberately because they sound very different from each other when transmitted via Morse code. The intention was to reduce the possibility of operator error.&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;Nebel designed the cipher to provide an army on the move with encryption more convenient than trench codes but still secure. In fact, the Germans believed the ADFGVX cipher was unbreakable.&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;Source: http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/ADFGVX_cipher" />
    <replacement key="$Iterate Dictionary$" value="{\b Iterate Dictionary}" />
    <replacement key="$Generate Output$" value="{\b Generate Output}" />
    <replacement key="$Check transposition$" value="{\b ADFGVX Dictionary Attack} \line\line This template shows how the ADFGVX cipher can be tackled using a dictionary attack. A given text is encrypted with ADFGVX using &quot;ABC&quot; as substitution key (the identical substitution) and &quot;abandonnent&quot; as transposition key. Then for each entry of the dictionary, the transposition is reversed using the standard columnar transposition and the cost function uses the index of coincidence (IoC) based on bigrams (2 letters) for the reverted text. This is possible because the &quot;encrypted&quot; text is a monoalphabetic substitution that has the same IoC as the plaintext. The found text is still not the plaintext, but the transposition is removed.\line\line The bestlist may contain more than one output because it collects all keys that generate an IoC exceeding the given threshold of 0.05. For a random text, the expected IoC is 1/26 (about 0.038). A value bigger than 0.05 indicates that it is probably a meaningful text. Depending on the size of the dictionary it takes several minutes until the execution of this template is completed." />
  </replacements>
  <!--- - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - -->
  <!--Language 'de' starts here:-->
  <!--- - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - -->
  <title lang="de">Wörterbuchangriff auf die ADFGVX-Chiffre</title>
  <summary lang="de">Angriff auf die <i>ADFGVX</i>-Chiffre mit Hilfe eines Wörterbuchs</summary>
  <description lang="de">Diese Vorlage demonstriert, dass man die Transposition der ADFGVX-Chiffre unabhängig von der Substitution rückgängig machen kann. In diesem Fall wird ein Wörterbuchangriff durchgeführt. Als Ergebnis liefert die Vorlage den Tranpositionsschlüssel und den Koinzidenzindex des Zwischen-Geheimtexts, bei dem die Transposition rückgängig gemacht wurde. Diese Vorlage ist nur ein Proof-of-Concept. Um die ADFGVX-Chiffre vollständig zu brechen, kann die "ADFGVX heuristische Analyse"-Vorlage genutzt werden.</description>
  <keywords lang="de">Weltkrieg, Reihe, Spalte, Quadrat, Wörterbuch, Analyse</keywords>
  <replacements lang="de">
    <replacement key="$Plaintext$" value="Klartext" />
    <replacement key="$Output (Bestlist)$" value="Ausgabe (Bestenliste)" />
    <replacement key="$Converter$" value="Konvertierer" />
    <replacement key="$Dictionary$" value="Wörterbuch" />
    <replacement key="$Concat$" value="Konkatenierer" />
    <replacement key="$Cost function$" value="Kostenfunktion" />
    <replacement key="$Actual value$" value="Aktueller Wert" />
    <replacement key="$Threshold$" value="Schwellenwert" />
    <replacement key="$CoincidenceGate$" value="Koinzidenz-Gatter" />
    <replacement key="$KeyGate$" value="Schlüssel-Gatter" />
    <replacement key="$TextGate$" value="Text-Gatter" />
    <replacement key="$Gate$" value="Gatter" />
    <replacement key="$infinity$" value="unendlich" />
    <replacement key="$message$" value="In cryptography, the ADFGVX cipher was a field cipher used by the German Army on the Western Front during World War I. ADFGVX was in fact an extension of an earlier cipher called ADFGX.&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;Invented by Colonel Fritz Nebel and introduced in March 1918, the cipher was a fractionating transposition cipher which combined a modified Polybius square with a single columnar transposition.&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;The cipher is named after the six possible letters used in the ciphertext: A, D, F, G, V and X. These letters were chosen deliberately because they sound very different from each other when transmitted via Morse code. The intention was to reduce the possibility of operator error.&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;Nebel designed the cipher to provide an army on the move with encryption more convenient than trench codes but still secure. In fact, the Germans believed the ADFGVX cipher was unbreakable.&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;Source: http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/ADFGVX_cipher" />
    <replacement key="$Check transposition$" value="{\b Wörterbuchangriff auf die ADFGVX-Chiffre} \line\line Diese Vorlage zeigt, wie eine ADFGVX-Chiffre mit einem Wörterbuchangriff attackiert werden kann. Ein gegebener Text wird mit ADFGVX verschlüsselt: eingestellt ist als Substitutions-Passwort &quot;ABC&quot; und somit die identische Substitution, und als Transpositions-Passwort &quot;abandonnent&quot;. Für jeden Eintrag des Wörterbuches wird dann mit einer einfachen Spaltentransposition die Transposition rückgängig gemacht, und für jedes Resultat die Kostenfunktion berechnet basierend auf dem mittels 2-Grammen (Buchstabenpaaren) berechneten Koinzidenzindex (IoC). Dies ist möglich, da der &quot;verschlüsselte&quot; Text eine monoalphabetische Substitution ist, die denselben IoC wie der Klartext hat. Der gefundene Text ist immer noch nicht der Klartext, aber die Transposition wurde entfernt.\line\line In der Bestenliste werden alle Schlüssel aufgelistet, für die der IoC über dem Schwellenwert 0,05 liegt. Der Schwellenwert ist so gewählt, da der IoC für zufällige Zeichenfolgen 1/26 (etwa 0,038) beträgt. Ein Wert über 0,05 deutet dagegen auf einen sinnvollen Text hin. Abhängig von der Größe des Wörterbuchs dauert es einige Minuten, bis das Template ganz fertig ist." />
    <replacement key="$Iterate Dictionary$" value="\b Durchlaufe Wörterbuch" />
    <replacement key="$Generate Output$" value="\b Generiere Ausgabe" />
  </replacements>
  <!--- - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - -->
  <!--The general section starts here:-->
  <!--- - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - -->
  <icon file="ADFGX_dictionary_attack.png" />
  <relevantPlugins>
    <plugin name="ADFGVX" />
    <plugin name="CrypToolDictionary" />
    <plugin name="CostFunction" />
  </relevantPlugins>
</sample>