<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<sample>
  <!--- - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - -->
  <!--File name: M209 Ciphertext-only attack.xml-->
  <!--Last edited: 2023.09.28-->
  <!--- - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - -->
  <!--- - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - -->
  <!--Language 'en' starts here:-->
  <!--- - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - -->
  <title lang="en">Ciphertext-only attack against the Hagelin M-209</title>
  <summary lang="en">This template shows a ciphertext-only attack against the Hagelin M-209.</summary>
  <description lang="en">This template shows a ciphertext-only attack against the Hagelin M-209.</description>
  <keywords>cryptanalysis, Hagelin, cipher, M209, M-209, ciphertext, ciphertext-only</keywords>
  <replacements lang="en">
    <replacement key="$M209Analyzer$" value="Hagelin M-209 Analyzer" />
    <replacement key="$text$" value = "ME THANK GOD HE CRIED YOU LL DO COME COME WHAT THEN I ASKED COME MAN COME ONLY THREE MINUTES OR IT WON T BE LEGAL I WAS HALF DRAGGED UP TO THE ALTAR AND BEFORE I KNEW WHERE I WAS I FOUND MYSELF MUMBLING RESPONSES WHICH WERE WHISPERED IN MY EAR AND VOUCHING FOR THINGS OF WHICH I KNEW NOTHING AND GENERALLY ASSISTING IN THE SECURE TYING UP OF IRENE ADLER SPINSTER TO GODFREY NORTON BACHELOR IT WAS ALL DONE IN AN INSTANT AND THERE WAS THE GENTLEMAN THANKING ME ON THE ONE SIDE AND THE LADY ON THE OTHER WHILE THE CLERGYMAN BEAMED ON ME IN FRONT IT WAS THE MOST PREPOSTEROUS POSITION IN WHICH I EVER FOUND MYSELF IN MY LIFE AND IT WAS THE THOUGHT OF IT THAT STARTED ME LAUGHING JUST NOW IT SEEMS THAT THERE HAD BEEN SOME INFORMALITY ABOUT THEIR LICENSE THAT THE CLERGYMAN ABSOLUTELY REFUSED TO MARRY THEM WITHOUT A WITNESS OF SOME SORT AND THAT MY LUCKY APPEARANCE SAVED THE BRIDEGROOM FROM HAVING TO SALLY OUT INTO THE STREETS IN SEARCH OF A BEST MAN THE BRIDE GAVE ME A SOVEREIGN AND I MEAN TO WEAR IT ON MY WATCH CHAIN IN MEMORY OF THE OCCASION THIS IS A VERY UNEXPECTED TURN OF AFFAIRS SAID I AND WHAT THEN WELL I FOUND MY PLANS VERY SERIOUSLY MENACED IT LOOKED AS IF THE PAIR MIGHT TAKE AN IMMEDIATE DEPARTURE AND SO NECESSITATE VERY PROMPT AND ENERGETIC MEASURES ON MY PART AT THE CHURCH DOOR HOWEVER THEY SEPARATED HE DRIVING BACK TO THE TEMPLE AND SHE TO HER OWN HOUSE I SHALL DRIVE OUT IN THE PARK AT FIVE AS USUAL SHE SAID AS SHE LEFT HIM I HEARD NO MORE THEY DROVE AWAY IN DIFFERENT DIRECTIONS AND I WENT OFF TO MAKE MY OWN ARRANGEMENTS WHICH ARE SOME COLD BEEF AND A GLASS OF BEER HE ANSWERED RINGING THE BELL I HAVE BEEN TOO BUSY TO THINK OF FOOD AND I AM LIKELY TO BE BUSIER STILL THIS EVENING BY THE WAY DOCTOR I SHALL WANT YOUR CO OPERATION I SHALL BE DELIGHTED YOU DON T MIND BREAKING THE LAW NOT IN THE LEAST NOR RUNNING A CHANCE OF ARREST NOT IN A GOOD CAUSE OH THE CAUSE IS EXCELLENT THEN I AM YOUR MAN I WAS SURE THAT I MIGHT RELY ON YOU BUT WHAT IS IT YOU WISH WHEN MRS TURNER HAS"/>
    <replacement key="$ciphertext$" value="Ciphertext" />
    <replacement key="$textoutput$" value="Decrypted text" />
	<replacement key="$plaintext$" value="Plaintext" />
	<replacement key="$key$" value="Key" />
    <replacement key="$memo$" value="The Hagelin M-209 is a portable rotor encryption machine that was used by the U.S. military mainly during World War II, but as late as the Korean War.\line
Very compact and handy, it is also completely analog and has a larger key space than the Enigma used by the Germans in World War II.
\line
\line
To get encrypted text for attack, you can use the M-209 component. \line
It should be noted that the present attack assumes that one of the known instructions for the key settings was followed when encrypting. \line
These instructions include certain defaults to avoid creating keys that are easily cracked. The following instructions are known: \line \line
- TM 11-380 April 27, 1942 (https://maritime.org/tech/csp1500inst.php) \line
- TM 11-380B September 20, 1943 (http://www.jfbouch.fr/crypto/m209/TM_11-380B_20Sep1943.pdf) \line
- TM 11-380 March 17, 1944 (http://www.jfbouch.fr/crypto/m209/manual.html) \line
- TM 11-380 May 1947 \line
\line
In a ciphertext-only attack, only the encrypted text is available to the attacker. \line
The algorithm used here, uses hill climbing for recovering the lug settings and simulated annealing to search for optimal pin settings. \line"/>
  </replacements>
  <!--- - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - -->
  <!--Language 'de' starts here:-->
  <!--- - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - -->
  <title lang="de">Ciphertext-only-Angriff gegen die Hagelin M-209 </title>
  <summary lang="de">Diese Vorlage zeigt einen Ciphertext-only-Angriff gegen die Hagelin M-209.</summary>
  <description lang="de">Diese Vorlage zeigt einen Ciphertext-only-Angriff gegen die Hagelin M-209.</description>
  <keywords>Kryptoanalyse, Hagelin, cipher, M209, M-209, ciphertext, ciphertext-only</keywords>
  <replacements lang="de">
    <replacement key="$M209Analyzer$" value="Hagelin M-209 Analysator" />
    <replacement key="$text$" value = "ME THANK GOD HE CRIED YOU LL DO COME COME WHAT THEN I ASKED COME MAN COME ONLY THREE MINUTES OR IT WON T BE LEGAL I WAS HALF DRAGGED UP TO THE ALTAR AND BEFORE I KNEW WHERE I WAS I FOUND MYSELF MUMBLING RESPONSES WHICH WERE WHISPERED IN MY EAR AND VOUCHING FOR THINGS OF WHICH I KNEW NOTHING AND GENERALLY ASSISTING IN THE SECURE TYING UP OF IRENE ADLER SPINSTER TO GODFREY NORTON BACHELOR IT WAS ALL DONE IN AN INSTANT AND THERE WAS THE GENTLEMAN THANKING ME ON THE ONE SIDE AND THE LADY ON THE OTHER WHILE THE CLERGYMAN BEAMED ON ME IN FRONT IT WAS THE MOST PREPOSTEROUS POSITION IN WHICH I EVER FOUND MYSELF IN MY LIFE AND IT WAS THE THOUGHT OF IT THAT STARTED ME LAUGHING JUST NOW IT SEEMS THAT THERE HAD BEEN SOME INFORMALITY ABOUT THEIR LICENSE THAT THE CLERGYMAN ABSOLUTELY REFUSED TO MARRY THEM WITHOUT A WITNESS OF SOME SORT AND THAT MY LUCKY APPEARANCE SAVED THE BRIDEGROOM FROM HAVING TO SALLY OUT INTO THE STREETS IN SEARCH OF A BEST MAN THE BRIDE GAVE ME A SOVEREIGN AND I MEAN TO WEAR IT ON MY WATCH CHAIN IN MEMORY OF THE OCCASION THIS IS A VERY UNEXPECTED TURN OF AFFAIRS SAID I AND WHAT THEN WELL I FOUND MY PLANS VERY SERIOUSLY MENACED IT LOOKED AS IF THE PAIR MIGHT TAKE AN IMMEDIATE DEPARTURE AND SO NECESSITATE VERY PROMPT AND ENERGETIC MEASURES ON MY PART AT THE CHURCH DOOR HOWEVER THEY SEPARATED HE DRIVING BACK TO THE TEMPLE AND SHE TO HER OWN HOUSE I SHALL DRIVE OUT IN THE PARK AT FIVE AS USUAL SHE SAID AS SHE LEFT HIM I HEARD NO MORE THEY DROVE AWAY IN DIFFERENT DIRECTIONS AND I WENT OFF TO MAKE MY OWN ARRANGEMENTS WHICH ARE SOME COLD BEEF AND A GLASS OF BEER HE ANSWERED RINGING THE BELL I HAVE BEEN TOO BUSY TO THINK OF FOOD AND I AM LIKELY TO BE BUSIER STILL THIS EVENING BY THE WAY DOCTOR I SHALL WANT YOUR CO OPERATION I SHALL BE DELIGHTED YOU DON T MIND BREAKING THE LAW NOT IN THE LEAST NOR RUNNING A CHANCE OF ARREST NOT IN A GOOD CAUSE OH THE CAUSE IS EXCELLENT THEN I AM YOUR MAN I WAS SURE THAT I MIGHT RELY ON YOU BUT WHAT IS IT YOU WISH WHEN MRS TURNER HAS"/>
    <replacement key="$ciphertext$" value="Verschlüsselter Text" />
	<replacement key="$plaintext$" value="Klartext" />
    <replacement key="$textoutput$" value="Entschlüsselter Text" />
	<replacement key="$key$" value="Schlüssel" />
    <replacement key="$memo$" value="Die Hagelin M-209 ist eine tragbare Rotor-Chiffriermaschine, die hauptsächlich während des Zweiten Weltkriegs, aber noch bis zum Koreakrieg, vom US-Militär eingesetzt wurde.\line
Sie ist sehr kompakt und handlich, zudem vollständig analog und hat einen größeren Schlüsselraum als die Enigma, die von den Deutschen im zweiten Weltkrieg verwendet wurde.
\line
\line
Um verschlüsselten Text für den Angriff zu erhalten, wird hier die Komponente M-209 verwendet. \line
Zu beachten ist, dass der vorliegende Angriff annimmt, dass man sich beim Verschlüsseln an eine der bekannten Anleitungen für die Schlüsseleinstellungen hielt. \line
Diese Anleitungen beinhalten bestimmte Vorgaben, um keine leicht zu knackenden Schlüssel zu erzeugen. Folgende Anleitungen sind bekannt: \line \line
- TM 11-380 27. April 1942 (https://maritime.org/tech/csp1500inst.php) \line
- TM 11-380B 20.September 1943 (http://www.jfbouch.fr/crypto/m209/TM_11-380B_20Sep1943.pdf) \line
- TM 11-380 17.März 1944 (http://www.jfbouch.fr/crypto/m209/manual.html) \line
- TM 11-380 Mai 1947 \line
\line
Bei einem Ciphertext-only-Angriff steht dem Angreifer nur der verschlüsselte Text zur Verfügung. \line
Der hier verwendete Algorithmus, nutzt Hill-Climbing zur Ermittlung der Lug-Einstellungen und Simulated-Annealing um nach optimalen Pin-Einstellungen zu suchen. \line
" />
  </replacements>
  <!--- - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - -->
  <!--The general section starts here:-->
  <!--- - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - -->
  <icon file="M209Analyzer.png" />
  <relevantPlugins>
    <plugin name="M209Analyzer" />
  </relevantPlugins>
</sample>
