<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<documentation>
  <language culture="en" />
  <language culture="zh-CN" />
  <language culture="ru" />
  <language culture="de-DE" />
  <introduction lang="en"> 
    This component checks whether the given number is a prime number.
  </introduction>
  <introduction lang="zh-CN">该组件检查给定数字是否为质数。</introduction>
  <introduction lang="ru">Этот компонент проверяет, является ли данное число простым числом.</introduction>
  <introduction lang="de-DE">
    Diese Komponente testet, ob die eingegebene Zahl eine Primzahl ist.
  </introduction>
  <usage lang="en">
    The input to the component is the number whose primality is to be checked. First, it uses trial division to check if the number has
    a small prime factor. If it has no small factor, it then uses the Miller-Rabin primality test, that
    can determine whether a given number is a prime number with a very high probability. The result of the test is presented
    as a boolean value at the output of the component. When the result is 'false', the number is definitely composite.
    When the result is 'true', the number is a prime number with a very high probability.
  </usage>
  <usage lang="zh-CN">组件的输入是要检查其素数的数字。首先，它使用试算法检查数字是否有小的素数。如果不小的因素，则使用Miller-Rabin素数检验，该检验可以确定给定数是否是极高概率的素数。测试结果在组件的输出处显示为布尔值。当结果为“假”时，数字肯定是复合的。当结果为“真”时，该数字是极有可能的质数。</usage>
  <usage lang="ru">Вход в компонент - это число, чья первичность должна быть проверена. Во-первых, он использует пробное деление, чтобы проверить, имеет ли число небольшой первичный коэффициент. Если он не имеет большого значения, он использует тест примитива Миллера-Рабина, который может определить, является ли данное число простым числом с очень высокой вероятностью. Результат теста представлен как логическое значение на выходе компонента. Когда результат «false», число определенно составлено. Когда результат «истина», число представляет собой простое число с очень высокой вероятностью.</usage>
  <usage lang="de-DE">
    Diese Komponente erwartet als einzige Eingabe die zu testende Zahl. Zuerst wird geprüft, ob die zu untersuchende Zahl 
    einen kleinen Primfaktor hat. Hat sie keinen kleinen Faktor, so wird der Miller-Rabin-Test ausgeführt, der
    mit hoher Wahrscheinlichkeit feststellen kann, ob eine Zahl eine Primzahl ist oder nicht. Das Ergebnis des Tests wird am
    Ausgang der Komponente als boolescher Wert ausgegeben. Wird 'falsch' ausgegeben, so ist die Zahl auf jeden Fall zusammengesetzt.
    Wird 'wahr' ausgegeben, so ist die Zahl mit sehr hoher Wahrscheinlichkeit eine Primzahl.
  </usage>
  <references>
    <linkReference>
      <link lang="en" url="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Miller–Rabin_primality_test" />
      <caption lang="en">Miller–Rabin primality test</caption>
      <link lang="de-DE" url="http://de.wikipedia.org/wiki/Miller-Rabin-Test" />
      <caption lang="de-DE">Miller-Rabin-Test</caption>
    </linkReference>
  </references>
</documentation>