<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<documentation>
  <language culture="en" />
  <language culture="de-DE" />
  <introduction lang="en">
    This plugin generates either a random prime number of an assignable magnitude or the prime number immediately preceding or following a given number.
  </introduction>
  <introduction lang="de-DE">
    Dieses Plugin erzeugt entweder eine zufällige Primzahl einer vorgebbaren Größenordnung oder die einer gegebenen Zahl unmittelbar vorhergehende oder nachfolgende Primzahl.
  </introduction>
  <usage lang="en">
    The magnitude of the prime number to be generated can be chosen in two different ways in the settings tab of the plugin.
    <newline /><newline />
    When you choose 'prime number with at most n bits', the parameter n is interpreted as the maximum bitsize of the generated prime, i.e.
    the maximum number of bits that the binary representation of the generated prime requires.
    The result is then a random prime that is smaller than 2^n, or, in other words, a random prime in the interval [ 2, 2^n [.
    The bitsize must be greater than 1.
    <newline /><newline />
    When you choose 'prime number with exactly n bits', the generated prime number will be bigger than or equal to 2^(n-1) and smaller than 2^n,
    i.e. it will lie in the interval [ 2^(n-1), 2^n [.
    The bitsize must be greater than 1.
    <newline /><newline />
    When you choose 'prime number less than or equal to n', the parameter n is an upper limit for the generated prime.
    The result is then a random prime that is smaller than or equal to n, i.e. a random prime in the interval [ 2, n ].
    <newline /><newline />
    When you choose 'Search next smaller prime number', the biggest prime number that is smaller than the given number n, is sent to the output.
    Analogously, the smallest prime number that is bigger than the given number n, is output if you choose 'Search next bigger prime number'.
  </usage>
  <usage lang="de-DE">
    Die Größenordnung der zu erzeugenden Primzahl kann in den Plugin-Einstellungen auf zwei Arten gewählt werden.
    <newline /><newline />
    Wählt man die Methode 'Primzahl mit höchstens n Bits', so kann man als Parameter die maximale Bitgröße der zu erzeugenden Zahl angeben
    (d.h. die Anzahl der Bits, die für die Binärdarstellung der Primzahl höchstens benötigt werden). Die erzeugte Primzahl ist dann
    eine zufällige Primzahl, die größer oder gleich 2 und kleiner als 2^n ist, d.h. eine Primzahl aus dem Intervall [ 2, 2^n [.
    Die Bitgröße muss größer als 1 bit sein.
    <newline /><newline />
    Wählt man die Methode 'Primzahl mit genau n Bits', so wird eine Primzahl erzeugt, deren Binärdarstellung genau n Bits benötigt und die
    damit größer oder gleich 2^(n-1) und kleiner als 2^n ist, d.h. im Intervall [ 2^(n-1), 2^n [ liegt.
    Die Bitgröße muss größer als 1 bit sein.
    <newline /><newline />
    Wählt man die Methode 'Primzahl kleiner oder gleich n', so stellt der Parameter n eine obere Schranke für die zu erzeugende
    Primzahl dar. Die resultierende Primzahl ist dann eine zufällige Primzahl, die höchstens gleich n ist und somit im Intervall [ 2, n ] liegt.
    <newline /><newline />
    Wählt man die Methode 'Suche nächstkleinere Primzahl', so wird die größte Primzahl, die kleiner als die angegebene Zahl n ist, ausgegeben.
    Analog wird die kleinste Primzahl, die größer als die angegebene Zahl n ist, ausgegeben, wenn man die Methode 'Suche nächstgrößere Primzahl' wählt.
  </usage>
  <references>
    <linkReference>
      <link lang="en" url="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Prime_number" />
      <caption lang="en">Prime numbers</caption>
      <link lang="de-DE" url="http://de.wikipedia.org/wiki/Primzahl" />
      <caption lang="de-DE">Primzahlen</caption>
    </linkReference>
  </references>
</documentation>