<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<documentation>
  <language culture="en" />
  <language culture="de-DE" />
  <introduction lang="en">
    This component can convert a byte sequence to a string. The interpretation of the byte sequence and the resulting formatting of the string can be adjusted in the settings of the component.
  </introduction>
  <introduction lang="de-DE">
    Diese Komponente konvertiert eine Bytesequenz in eine Zeichenkette. Die Interpretation der Bytesequenz und die resultierende Formatierung der Zeichenkette kann in den Einstellungen der Komponente variiert werden.
  </introduction>
  <usage lang="en">
    In the settings of the component you can select the format into which the input should be converted. Depending on the chosen format, different options will be available in the settings.
    <newline /><newline />
    If you choose the format <b>Text</b>, the input byte sequence will be interpreted as a string based upon the chosen input data encoding. The result is sent to the output of the component.
    If the input contains a byte sequence that has no representation as a character in the selected encoding scheme, the string will contain a question mark at this position.
    <newline /><newline /><b>Example:</b> If you enter the byte sequence <i>61 62 63 ff</i> and select ASCII as input data encoding, the resulting string is <i>abc?</i>.
  <newline /><newline />
    If you choose the format <b>Binary</b>, the bytes of the input will be converted to binary format and, for better readability of the output, concatenated with a space character.
    <newline /><newline /><b>Example:</b> The input <i>61 62 63 ff</i> produces the output string <i>01100001 01100010 01100011 11111111</i>.
    <newline /><newline />
    The options <b>Octal</b>, <b>Decimal</b> and <b>Hexadecimal</b> work in the same way as the option <b>Binary</b>. The bytes are converted to the appropriate number system
    and the strings are concatenated, separated by a space character.
    <newline /><newline />
    If you choose the format <b>Base64</b>, the input is encoded in Base64 format and the resulting string is sent to the output.
    <newline /><newline /><b>Example:</b> The input <i>43 72 79 70 54 6F 6F 6C</i> will produce the string <i>Q3J5cFRbb2w=</i>. The input is the numeric ASCII representation of the word "CrypTool".
  </usage>
  <usage lang="de-DE">
    Wählen Sie in den Einstellungen der Komponente, in welches Format die Eingabe konvertiert werden soll. Abhängig vom gewählten Format werden unterschiedliche
    Optionen in den Einstellungen angezeigt.
    <newline /><newline />
    Wird die Option <b>Text</b> gewählt, so wird die Eingabe als eine Zeichenkette basierend auf der in den Einstellungen gewählten Zeichenkodierung interpretiert und am Ausgang der Komponente ausgegeben.
    Enthält die Eingabe Bytefolgen, denen in der gewählten Kodierung kein Zeichen entspricht, so wird in der resultierenden Zeichenkette an dieser Stelle ein Fragezeichen erscheinen.
    <newline /><newline /><b>Beispiel:</b> Wird als Eingabe die Bytesequenz <i>61 62 63 ff</i> eingegeben und ASCII als Zeichenkodierung der Eingabe gewählt, so ist das Ergebnis die Zeichenkette <i>abc?</i>.
    <newline /><newline />
    Wird die Option <b>Binär</b> gewählt, so werden die Bytes der Eingabe in ihre Binärdarstellung konvertiert und zur besseren Lesbarkeit der Ausgabe durch ein Leerzeichen getrennt aneinandergehängt.
    <newline /><newline /><b>Beispiel:</b> Die Eingabe <i>61 62 63 ff</i> erzeugt die Zeichenkette <i>01100001 01100010 01100011 11111111</i>.
    <newline /><newline />
    Bei den Optionen <b>Oktal</b>, <b>Dezimal</b> und <b>Hexadezimal</b> werden die Bytes der Eingabe dementsprechend in das angegebene Zahlensystem konvertiert und durch Leerzeichen getrennt ausgegeben.
    <newline /><newline />
    Wird die Option <b>Base64</b> gewählt, so wird die Eingabe im Base-64-Format kodiert und die resultierende Zeichenkette ausgegeben.
    <newline /><newline /><b>Beispiel:</b> Die Eingabe <i>43 72 79 70 54 6F 6F 6C</i> erzeugt die Zeichenkette <i>Q3J5cFRbb2w=</i>. Die Eingabe ist die numerische ASCII-Darstellung des Wortes "CrypTool".
  </usage>
  <presentation lang="en"></presentation>
  <presentation lang="de-DE"></presentation>
  <references>
    <linkReference>
      <link lang="en" url="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Character_encoding" />
      <caption lang="en">Character encoding</caption>
      <link lang="de-DE" url="http://de.wikipedia.org/wiki/Zeichenkodierung" />
      <caption lang="de-DE">Zeichenkodierung</caption>
    </linkReference>
    <linkReference>
      <link lang="en" url="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Binary_numeral_system" />
      <caption lang="en">Binary numeral system</caption>
      <link lang="de-DE" url="http://de.wikipedia.org/wiki/Dualsystem" />
      <caption lang="de-DE">Dualsystem (Binärsystem)</caption>
    </linkReference>
    <linkReference>
      <link lang="en" url="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Octal" />
      <caption lang="en">Octal</caption>
      <link lang="de-DE" url="http://de.wikipedia.org/wiki/Oktalsystem" />
      <caption lang="de-DE">Oktalsystem</caption>
    </linkReference>
    <linkReference>
      <link lang="en" url="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Decimal" />
      <caption lang="en">Decimal</caption>
      <link lang="de-DE" url="http://de.wikipedia.org/wiki/Dezimalsystem" />
      <caption lang="de-DE">Dezimalsystem</caption>
    </linkReference>
    <linkReference>
      <link lang="en" url="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Hexadecimal" />
      <caption lang="en">Hexadecimal</caption>
      <link lang="de-DE" url="http://de.wikipedia.org/wiki/Hexadezimalsystem" />
      <caption lang="de-DE">Hexadezimalsystem</caption>
    </linkReference>
    <linkReference>
      <link lang="en" url="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Base64" />
      <caption lang="en">Base64</caption>
      <link lang="de-DE" url="http://de.wikipedia.org/wiki/Base64" />
      <caption lang="de-DE">Base64</caption>
    </linkReference>
  </references>
</documentation>