<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!-- You can edit this file manually or with the Util/CrypDocumentationEditor -->
<documentation>
  <language culture="en" />
  <language culture="zh-CN" />
  <language culture="ru" />
  <language culture="de-DE" />
  <introduction lang="en">   
		The function HKDF SHA-256 [1][2] is a key generation function (KDF). The method uses the keyed hash message authentication codes (HMAC) as a pseudorandom function (PRF). The key to be generated is generated in 2 steps. Step 1 generates a pseudorandom key (prk). Step 2 successively generates the key by repeating the HMAC. The hKDF method uses an 8-bit counter, which limits the key length to be generated (255 * hash length, the counter in step 2 starts at 1). In the configuration of the plug-in, you can choose between the standardized variant (with 8-bit counter) and a variant with 32-bit counter. The 32-bit variant can generate much longer outputs.  
  	  	<section headline="Inputs and outputs"><list><item><b>Source Key Material:</b> Specifies the source key material. It is used for the calculation of the prk.</item><item><b>Salt:</b> The salt is used for the calculation of the prk as key in the HMAC. It can be an empty string.</item><item><b>Context Information:</b> It is a application specific constant (CTXInfo). It can be an empty string.</item><item><b>Length of the key material (in Byte):</b> Specifies the length of the output key material.</item><item><b>Key Material</b>: After the calculation, the generated key material is visible in this text field.</item><item><b>Calculation steps:</b> The intermediate steps of the calculation are displayed in this text field.</item></list></section><section headline="Pseudorandom functions and theoretical background">
	  The basics of pseudorandom functions can be found in this <internal ref="../Common/Key derivation functions based on pseudorandom functions_en.html">article</internal> within the CT2 online help.
	  </section></introduction>
  <introduction lang="zh-CN">函数HKDF SHA-256 [1] [2]是密钥生成函数（KDF）。该方法使用键控哈希消息认证码（HMAC）作为伪随机函数（PRF）。分两步生成要生成的密钥。步骤1生成一个伪随机密钥（prk）。步骤2通过重复HMAC连续生成密钥。 hKDF方法使用8位计数器，该计数器限制了要生成的密钥长度（255 *哈希长度，步骤2中的计数器从1开始）。在插件的配置中，可以在标准变量（带8位计数器）和32位计数器的变量之间进行选择。 32位变量可以生成更长的输出。源密钥材料：指定源密钥材料。盐：用于HMAC中密钥的prk的计算。它可以是一个空字符串。上下文信息：它是一个应用程序特定的常量（CTXInfo）。它可以是一个空字符串。密钥材料的长度（以字节为单位）：指定输出密钥材料的长度。密钥材料：计算后，生成的密钥材料在此文本字段中可见。计算步骤：中间步骤计算结果将显示在此文本字段中。伪随机函数的基础知识可以在本文的CT2在线帮助中找到。</introduction>
  <introduction lang="ru">Функция HKDF SHA-256 [1] [2] является функцией генерации ключей (KDF). Метод использует коды аутентификации хэш-кода с ключами (HMAC) в качестве псевдослучайной функции (PRF). Генерируемый ключ генерируется в 2 этапа. Шаг 1 генерирует псевдослучайный ключ (prk). Шаг 2 последовательно генерирует ключ, повторяя HMAC. Метод hKDF использует 8-битный счетчик, который ограничивает длину ключа, который должен быть сгенерирован (длина хэш-байта 255 *, счетчик на шаге 2 начинается с 1). В конфигурации плагина вы можете выбрать стандартизованный вариант (с 8-битным счетчиком) и вариант с 32-разрядным счетчиком. 32-битный вариант может генерировать гораздо более длинные выходы. Исходный ключевой материал: указывает исходный ключевой материал. Он используется для расчета prk.Salt: соль используется для вычисления prk как ключа в HMAC. Это может быть пустая строка. Контекстная информация. Это константа приложения (CTXInfo). Это может быть пустая строка. Длина ключевого материала (в байте): определяет длину выходного ключевого материала. Материал: после вычисления в этом текстовом поле видны сгенерированный материал ключа. Происхождения: промежуточные этапы вычисление отображается в этом текстовом поле. Основы псевдослучайных функций можно найти в этой статье.</introduction>
  <introduction lang="de-DE">
     Die Funktion HKDF SHA-256 [1][2] ist eine Schlüsselgenerierungs-Funktion (Key Derivation Function, KDF). Das Verfahren verwendet als Pseudozufallsfunktion (Pseudorandom Function, PRF) den Keyed-Hash Message Authentication Codes (HMAC). Der zu generierende Schlüssel wird in 2 Schritten generiert. Schritt 1 generiert einen Pseudozufallsschlüssel (PRK). Schritt 2 erzeugt sukzessive den Schlüssel durch wiederholte Ausführung des HMAC. Das HKDF-Verfahren verwendet einen 8 Bit Zähler, wodurch die zu generierende Schlüssellänge begrenzt ist (255 * Hashlänge, der Zähler in Schritt 2 beginnt bei 1 zu zählen). In der Konfiguration des Plugins kann zwischen der standardisierten Variante (mit 8-Bit Zähler) und einer Variante mit 32-Bit Zähler gewählt werden. Mit der 32-Bit-Variante lassen sich wesentlich längere Ausgaben erzeugen.
        <section headline="Eingaben und Ausgaben"><list><item><b>Quellschlüssel-Material:</b> Spezifiziert das Quellschlüssel-Material (Source Key Material, SKM). Dieses wird zur Generierung des Pseudo-Zufallsschlüssel (Pseudorandom Key, PRK) verwendet.</item><item><b>Salt:</b> Salt wird bei der generierung des PRK als Schlüssel verwendet. Kann leer sein.</item><item><b>Kontext-Information:</b> Ist eine anwendungsspezifische Konstante CTXInfo (Context Information, CTXInfo). Kann leer sein.</item><item><b>Länge des Schlüsselmaterials (in Byte):</b> Spezifiziert die Länge des zu generierenden Schlüsselmaterials.</item><item><b>Schlüsselmaterial:</b> Nach der Berechnung ist das generierte Schlüsselmaterial (Key Material, KM) in diesem Textfeld zu sehen.</item><item><b>Zwischenschritte der Berechnung:</b> Die Zwischenschritte der Berechnung werden in diesem Textfeld angezeigt.</item></list></section><section headline=" Pseudozufallsfunktionen und theoretischer Hintergrund">
	  Die Grundlagen zu Pseudozufallsfunktionen können in diesem <internal ref="../Common/Key derivation functions based on pseudorandom functions_de.html">Artikel</internal> in der CT2 Online-Hilfe gefunden werden.
	</section></introduction>
  <usage lang="en">
	The usable inputs and outputs will be explained in the presentation view of the component.
  </usage>
  <usage lang="zh-CN">可用的输入和输出将在组件的显示视图中进行说明。</usage>
  <usage lang="ru">Полезные входы и выходы будут объяснены в представлении о компоненте. р</usage>
  <usage lang="de-DE">
	Die verwendeten Ein- und Ausgaben werden zu Beginn in der Präsentations-Ansicht der Komponente erklärt.
  </usage>
  <presentation lang="en">
	By double-clicking on the component "HKDF SHA-256" in the workspace, you can activate the visualization of the calculation. The design and operation of the function will be explained step by step.
  </presentation>
  <presentation lang="zh-CN">通过双击工作区中的组件“ HKDF SHA-256”，可以激活计算的可视化。该功能的设计和操作将逐步说明。</presentation>
  <presentation lang="ru">Дважды щелкнув по компоненту «HKDF SHA-256» в рабочей области, вы можете активировать визуализацию вычисления. Конструкция и функционирование функции будут объясняться шаг за шагом.</presentation>
  <presentation lang="de-DE">
	Durch Doppelklick auf die Komponente "HKDF SHA-256" in der Arbeitsfläche können Sie die Visualisierung der Berechnung aktivieren. Dabei wird die ikonifizierte Komponente zu einem Fenster vergrößert, in dem die Konstruktion und die Arbeitsweise der Funktion Schritt für Schritt erklärt werden.
  </presentation>
  <references>
    <linkReference>
      <link url="https://tools.ietf.org/html/rfc5869" lang="en" />
      <caption lang="en">RFC 5869: Extract-and-Expand HKDF. Accessed 01-04-2018</caption>
      <link url="https://tools.ietf.org/html/rfc5869" lang="de-DE" />
      <caption lang="de-DE">RFC 5869: Extract-and-Expand HKDF. Aufgerufen am 01-04-2018</caption>
    </linkReference>
    <linkReference>
      <link url="https://eprint.iacr.org/2010/264.pdf" lang="en" />
      <caption lang="en">Cryptographic Extraction and Key Derivation: The HKDF Scheme. Accessed 01-04-2018</caption>
      <link url="https://eprint.iacr.org/2010/264.pdf" lang="de-DE" />
      <caption lang="de-DE">Cryptographic Extraction and Key Derivation: The HKDF Scheme. Aufgerufen am 01-04-2018</caption>
    </linkReference>
  </references>
</documentation>