<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!-- You can edit this file manually or with the Util/CrypDocumentationEditor -->
<documentation>
  <language culture="en" />
  <language culture="zh-CN" />
  <language culture="ru" />
  <language culture="de-DE" />
  <introduction lang="en">    
    
    MiniTreyfer is the mini-version of Treyfer cipher with only 16-bit plaintext and 16-bit key. 
    It is primarily developed to automatically acquire a slid-pair for further use in the slide attacks.
    
  </introduction>
  <introduction lang="zh-CN">MiniTreyfer是Treyfer密码的迷你版本，只有16位纯文本和16位密钥。它的主要开发目的是自动获取一个滑副，以进一步用于滑行攻击。</introduction>
  <introduction lang="ru">MiniTreyfer - это мини-версия шифрования Treyfer с 16-разрядным открытым текстом и 16-разрядным ключом. В основном он разработан для автоматического получения слайдовой пары для дальнейшего использования в слайд-атаках.</introduction>
  <introduction lang="de-DE"></introduction>
  <usage lang="en">
    
    The MiniTreyfer works by first creating a random 16-bit key as a reference. This key is generated using random number generator.
    Then the plugin starts generating pairs of plaintext and ciphertext such that the plaintext is encrypted using Treyfer cipher into ciphertext bits.
    The plugin terminates when it finds a pair of plaintext-ciphertext that uses the previously generated key for encryption. This pair is nothing but a slid pair and is the output of the plugin.
    
  </usage>
  <usage lang="zh-CN">MiniTreyfer的工作方式是首先创建一个随机的16位密钥作为参考。该密钥是使用随机数生成器生成的。然后，插件开始生成成对的明文和密文，以便使用Treyfer密文将明文加密为密文位。插件在找到一对使用先前生成的密钥进行加密的纯文本-密文时终止。这对只是滑动对，是插件的输出。</usage>
  <usage lang="ru">MiniTreyfer работает, сначала создавая случайный 16-битный ключ в качестве ссылки. Этот ключ генерируется с использованием генератора случайных чисел. Затем плагин начинает генерировать пары открытого текста и зашифрованного текста таким образом, что открытый текст зашифровывается с использованием Treyfer-шифра в биты зашифрованного текста. Плагин завершается, когда он находит пару незашифрованного шифрованного текста, который использует ранее сгенерированный ключ для шифрования. Эта пара - не что иное, как скользкая пара и является выходом плагина.</usage>
  <usage lang="de-DE"></usage>
  <presentation lang="en"></presentation>
  <presentation lang="de-DE"></presentation>
  <references>.
  </references>
</documentation>