<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<documentation>
  <language culture="en" />
  <language culture="zh-CN" />
  <language culture="ru" />
  <introduction lang="en">
    Grain v1 is one of seven symmetric stream ciphers that was chosen for the final eSTREAM portfolio of the ECRYPT Stream Cipher Project.
    The cipher is designed to have a low hardware complexity and is based on two shift registers and a non-linear output function.
    The key size is 80 bits and the size of the initialization vector is 64 bits. No attack faster than brute-force has been identified so far.
  </introduction>
  <introduction lang="zh-CN">Grain v1是为ECRYPT流密码项目的最终eSTREAM产品组合选择的七个对称流密码之一。该密码被设计为具有较低的硬件复杂度，并且基于两个移位寄存器和一个非线性输出功能。密钥大小为80位，初始化向量的大小为64位。到目前为止，还没有发现比蛮力还要快的攻击。</introduction>
  <introduction lang="ru">Grain v1 является одним из семи симметричных потоковых шифров, который был выбран для окончательного портфеля eSTREAM проекта ECHREPT Stream Cipher. Шифр имеет низкую аппаратную сложность и основан на двух сдвиговых регистрах и нелинейной функции вывода. Размер ключа - 80 бит, а размер вектора инициализации - 64 бита. До сих пор не было обнаружено атаки быстрее, чем грубая сила.</introduction>
  <usage lang="en">
    After dragging the Grain v1 component onto your workspace, you will
    have to attach the three input connectors 'Input', 'Key' and 'IV' to data sources.

    Additionally you have to connect a text output component to the 'Output' connector.
  </usage>
  <usage lang="zh-CN">将Grain v1组件拖到工作区后，必须将三个输入连接器“输入”，“键”和“ IV”连接到数据源。另外，您必须将文本输出组件连接到“输出”连接器。</usage>
  <usage lang="ru">После перетаскивания компонента Grain v1 в рабочее пространство вам необходимо будет подключить три входных разъема «Вход», «Ключ» и «IV» к источникам данных. Кроме того, вам необходимо подключить компонент вывода текста к разъему «Выход».</usage>
  <language culture="de" />
  <introduction lang="de">
    Grain v1 ist eine von sieben symmetrischen Stromchiffren, die für das finale eSTREAM Portfolio des ECRYPT Stream Cipher Project gewählt wurden.
    Die Chiffre ist so entworfen, dass sie eine geringe Hardwarekomplexität aufweist und sie basiert auf zwei Schieberegistern und einer nicht-linearen
    Ausgabefunktion. Die Schlüssellänge beträgt 80 Bits und die Länge des Initialisierungsvektors ist 64 Bits. Es wurde bisher kein Angriff gefunden,
    der schneller als Brute-Force ist.
  </introduction>
  <usage lang="de-DE">
    Nachdem Sie die Grain v1-Komponente auf den Arbeitsbereich gezogen
    haben, müssen Sie die Eingänge 'Eingabe', 'Schlüssel' und 'IV' mit Datenquellen verbinden.

    Außerdem muss der Ausgang mit einer Textausgabe-Komponente verbunden werden.
  </usage>
  <references>
    <linkReference>
      <link url="http://www.ecrypt.eu.org/stream/grainpf.html" lang="en" />
      <caption lang="en">Grain v1 at the eSTREAM Project</caption>
      <link url="http://www.ecrypt.eu.org/stream/grainpf.html" lang="de-DE" />
      <caption lang="de-DE">Grain v1 beim eSTREAM Project (englisch)</caption>
    </linkReference>
    <linkReference>
      <link url="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Grain_(cipher)" lang="en" />
      <caption lang="en">Grain v1 at Wikipedia</caption>
      <link url="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Grain_(cipher)" lang="de-DE" />
      <caption lang="de-DE">Grain v1 bei Wikipedia (englisch)</caption>
    </linkReference>
  </references>
</documentation>