<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<documentation>
  <language culture="en" />
  <introduction lang="en">
    Grain v1 is one of seven symmetric stream ciphers that was chosen for the final eSTREAM portfolio of the ECRYPT Stream Cipher Project.
    The cipher is designed to have a low hardware complexity and is based on two shift registers and a non-linear output function.
    The key size is 80 bits and the size of the initialization vector is 64 bits. No attack faster than brute-force has been identified so far.
  </introduction>
  <usage lang="en">
    After dragging the Grain v1 component onto your workspace, you will
    have to attach the three input connectors 'Input', 'Key' and 'IV' to data sources.

    Additionally you have to connect a text output component to the 'Output' connector.
  </usage>
  <language culture="de" />
  <introduction lang="de">
    Grain v1 ist eine von sieben symmetrischen Stromchiffren, die für das finale eSTREAM Portfolio des ECRYPT Stream Cipher Project gewählt wurden.
    Die Chiffre ist so entworfen, dass sie eine geringe Hardwarekomplexität aufweist und sie basiert auf zwei Schieberegistern und einer nicht-linearen
    Ausgabefunktion. Die Schlüssellänge beträgt 80 Bits und die Länge des Initialisierungsvektors ist 64 Bits. Es wurde bisher kein Angriff gefunden,
    der schneller als Brute-Force ist.
  </introduction>
  <usage lang="de-DE">
    Nachdem Sie die Grain v1-Komponente auf den Arbeitsbereich gezogen
    haben, müssen Sie die Eingänge 'Eingabe', 'Schlüssel' und 'IV' mit Datenquellen verbinden.

    Außerdem muss der Ausgang mit einer Textausgabe-Komponente verbunden werden.
  </usage>
  <references>
    <linkReference>
      <link url="http://www.ecrypt.eu.org/stream/grainpf.html" lang="en" />
      <caption lang="en">Grain v1 at the eSTREAM Project</caption>
      <link url="http://www.ecrypt.eu.org/stream/grainpf.html" lang="de-DE" />
      <caption lang="de-DE">Grain v1 beim eSTREAM Project (englisch)</caption>
    </linkReference>
    <linkReference>
      <link url="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Grain_(cipher)" lang="en" />
      <caption lang="en">Grain v1 at Wikipedia</caption>
      <link url="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Grain_(cipher)" lang="de-DE" />
      <caption lang="de-DE">Grain v1 bei Wikipedia (englisch)</caption>
    </linkReference>
  </references>
</documentation>