<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!-- You can edit this file manually or with the Util/CrypDocumentationEditor -->
<documentation>
  <!--EN-->
  <language culture="en" />
  <language culture="zh-CN" />
  <language culture="ru" />
  <introduction lang="en">
    Fialka M-125 is a rotor machine using an electromechanical construction. There are two known versions of the machine: standard (M-125) and extended
    (M-125-3). Each version also had a country-specific variant. It is known that it was used in the (former) Soviet Union, Poland, Czechoslovakia, Hungary and East Germany (GDR).
    <newline />
    The design of the Fialka M-125 is largely based on the well-known cipher machine Enigma. There are some major differences in the machine’s construction that can
    be regarded as an effort to correct known Enigma weaknesses.
    <newline /><newline />
    A keyboard containing 30 keys serves as input for the cipher machine. Pressing a key sends an electrical signal from the key into the output of
    the cipher machine through several electromechanical components of the device.
    The cryptographic security of Fialka relies on the use of several rotors, where each rotor implements a monoalphabetic substitution.
    The machine contains a special card reader that allows for the use of punched cards as a fixed permutation of the input alphabet.
    The result is printed on a paper tape.
    After encrypting a letter, rotors are moved into new positions, so in the next step a different permutation of the input alphabet is realized.
    <newline /><newline />
    Fialka has the following operation flow:
    <list><item> A key is pressed on the keyboard. </item><item> The electrical circuit is connected through the card reader into the entry disc.</item><item> The circuit continues from the entry disc through a set of ten rotors into the reflector.</item><item> The signal is reflected by the reflector and returned through the components listed above, in reverse order, into the printer.</item></list><newline />
    The reflector's wiring in Fialka differs from the Enigma reflector: the substitution is not involutoric - it contains one cycle of length 3 and one cycle of length 1.
    This entails that a different operation mode must be used for decryption. The cycle of length 1 enables self-encryption of the input letter.
    <newline /><newline />
    The main differences between Enigma and Fialka are summarized in the following table:
    <table border="1"><tr><th></th><th>Enigma</th><th>Fialka</th></tr><tr><td>Rotor count</td><td>3 or 4</td><td>10</td></tr><tr><td>Letter count</td><td>26</td><td>30</td></tr><tr><td>Rotor stepping</td><td>simple</td><td>blocking pin based</td></tr><tr><td>Rotor stepping direction</td><td>one-directional</td><td>adjacent rotors in opposite direction</td></tr><tr><td>Letter self-encryption</td><td>impossible</td><td>possible</td></tr></table><newline /><newline />
    The Fialka component is fully compatible with the real Fialka machine. It allows to set up:
    <list><item>Different machine models (M-125 and M-125-3).</item><item>Different rotor models (PROTON I and PROTON II) and different country specific rotor wirings (3K : Poland, 5K : Hungary, 6K : Czechoslovakia).</item><item>Different (country specific) keyboard layouts and print heads.</item><item>Different operation modes (Encrypt, Decrypt, Plain text mode).</item><item>All possible key settings (rotor order, rotor offsets, ring offset, punch card substitution, core order, core offsets, core sides).</item><item>In case of M-125-3 different text operation modes (letters only, numbers only (special characters) and mixed mode).</item><item>In case of M-125-3 special numbers only encryption mode (NumLock 10).</item></list></introduction>
  <introduction lang="zh-CN">Fialka M-125是采用机电结构的转子机械。本机有两种已知版本：标准（M-125）和扩展（M-125-3）。每个版本还具有针对特定国家/地区的变体。众所周知，它曾用于（前）苏联，波兰，捷克斯洛伐克，匈牙利和东德（GDR）。 Fialka M-125的设计主要基于著名的密码机Enigma。机器结构上有一些主要差异，可以认为是纠正已知的Enigma弱点的一种尝试。包含30个键的键盘用作密码机的输入。按下按键会将电信号从按键通过设备的多个机电组件发送到密码机的输出中。 Fialka的密码安全性依赖于多个转子的使用，其中每个转子都执行单字母替代。本机包含一个特殊的读卡器，可以将打孔的卡用作输入字母的固定排列。结果打印在纸带上。加密字母后，转子将移动到新位置，因此在下一步中，将实现输入字母的不同排列。 Fialka具有以下操作流程：按下键盘上的一个键。电路通过读卡器连接到入口光盘中。电路从进入盘通过一组十个转子进入反射器。信号被反射器反射，并以相反的顺序通过上面列出的组件返回打印机。 Fialka中的反射器布线与Enigma反射器不同：替换不是强制性的-它包含一个长度为3的循环和一个长度为1的循环。这意味着必须使用不同的操作模式进行解密。长度为1的循环可对输入字母进行自我加密。下表总结了Enigma和Fialka之间的主要区别：EnigmaFialkaRotor count3或410Letter count2630基于步进步进简单阻塞销的转子步进方向相反的单向相邻转子不可能自我加密的信息Fialka组件与真正的Fialka机器完全兼容。它可以设置：不同的机器型号（M-125和M-125-3）。不同的转子型号（PROTON I和PROTON II）以及不同国家/地区的特定转子接线（3K：波兰，5K：匈牙利，6K：捷克斯洛伐克）不同的（特定于国家的）键盘布局和打印头不同的操作模式（加密，解密，纯文本模式）所有可能的键设置（转子顺序，转子偏移，环偏移，打孔卡替换，核心顺序，核心偏移，核心在M-125-3不同的文本操作模式下（仅字母，仅数字（特殊字符）和混合模式）。在M-125-3特殊数字情况下仅加密模式（NumLock 10）。</introduction>
  <introduction lang="ru">Fialka M-125 - это роторная машина, использующая электромеханическую конструкцию. Существуют две известные версии машины: стандартные (M-125) и расширенные (M-125-3). Каждая версия также имела вариант, специфичный для каждой страны. Известно, что он использовался в (бывшем) Советском Союзе, Польше, Чехословакии, Венгрии и Восточной Германии (ГДР). Конструкция Fialka M-125 во многом основана на известной шифровой машине Enigma. Существуют некоторые существенные различия в конструкции машины, которые можно расценивать как попытку исправить известные слабости Энигмы. Клавиатура, содержащая 30 клавиш, служит в качестве входа для шифровальной машины. Нажатие клавиши посылает электрический сигнал от ключа на выход шифратора через несколько электромеханических компонентов устройства. Криптографическая безопасность Fialka основана на использовании нескольких роторов, где каждый ротор реализует моноалфавитную замену. Машина содержит специальный считыватель карт, который позволяет использовать перфокарты как фиксированную перестановку входного алфавита. Результат печатается на бумажной ленте. После шифрования буквы роторы перемещаются в новые позиции, поэтому на следующем этапе реализуется другая перестановка входного алфавита. Фиалка имеет следующий рабочий поток: клавиша нажата на клавиатуре. Электрическая схема подключается через считыватель карт к входному диску. Схема продолжается от входного диска через набор из десяти роторов в отражатель. Сигнал отражается рефлектором и возвращается через перечисленные выше компоненты в обратном порядке в принтер. Провод рефлектора в Fialka отличается от отражателя Enigma: замена не является инволюционной - она ​​содержит один цикл длины 3 и один цикл длины 1. Это означает, что для дешифрования необходимо использовать другой режим работы. Цикл длины 1 позволяет самошифровать входную букву. Основные отличия между Enigma и Fialka приведены в следующей таблице: EnigmaFialkaRotor count3 или 410Letter count2630Ростовые степпингспинговый штифт на основеРоторное направление шага однонаправленные смежные роторы в противоположном направлении. Самонашибочное самозакрывание возможно. Компонент Fialka полностью совместим с реальной машиной Fialka. Он позволяет настраивать: различные модели машин (M-125 и M-125-3). Различные модели роторов (PROTON I и PROTON II) и различные витые по стране роторные вилки (3K: Польша, 5K: Венгрия, 6K: Чехословакия) Разнообразные (для конкретной страны) раскладки клавиатуры и печатающие головки. Различные режимы работы (Шифрование, Расшифровка, Обычный текстовый режим). Все возможные настройки клавиш (порядок ротора, смещения ротора, смещение кольца, замена перфокарты, порядок сердечника, смещения сердечника, сердечник стороны). В случае M-125-3 различные режимы работы текста (только буквы, только цифры (специальные символы) и смешанный режим). В случае только для специальных номеров M-125-3 только для шифрования (NumLock 10).</introduction>
  <usage lang="en">
    In the settings of the component, you can select from several settings group.
    <newline /><newline />
    In the 'Workspace' menu you find settings for the handling of unknown symbols and the time period of restoring the initial key (saved before the PLAY button is pressed).
    <newline />
    If the input text contains a symbol that is not supported for a selected charset (specified by the print head and country layout), you can choose whether that symbol should be removed, ignored, or replaced by the letter '@'.
    If it is ignored, it will be added unmodified to the output text.
    <newline />
    The machine settings are saved every time before the PLAY button is pressed. If the save period is set to:
    <newline />
    "After execution" - the saved key is restored after the encryption process is finished;
    <newline />
    "Stop pressed" - the saved key is restored only when the Stop button is pressed; if you modify the input before pressing Stop, the changed key is applied;
    <newline />
    "Input changed" - the saved key is restored each time before the encryption is called;
    <newline />
    "Never" - the saved key is never restored.
    <newline /><newline />
    The 'Fialka machine settings' menu contains the main machine settings.
    <newline />
    You can set the machine model (M-125 / M-125-3), rotor type (PROTON I / PROTON II), country specific layouts and rotor series.
    In this menu you can also find the print head mapping, num lock type and text operation modes.
    The num lock and text operation modes are available only for the M-125-3 machine type.
    <newline />
    The operation mode specifies whether the machine is used to encrypt or decrypt the input message. This mode can be also set to plaintext mode -- without any encryption.
    <newline /><newline />
    The rest of the available settings forms the machine's key based on the selected rotor type.
    <newline /><newline /><section headline="PROTON I key settings">
      In the 'Rotor series' part of the 'Fialka machine settings' menu, you can choose the country specific rotor series.
      The available set of rotors depends on the chosen rotor series. The rotors are unique (different permutations and different pin positions) for all countries.
      <newline /><newline />
      In the 'Rotor order' menu, you can determine the position of the rotors on the spindle. The positions are marked from 1 to 10 from the reflector.
      Each rotor contains a unique wiring (substitution) and pin positions (responsible for rotor stepping).
      <newline />
      The following table contains the rotor labels (Cyrillic and numeric values):
      <table border="1"><tr><th>А</th><th>Б</th><th>В</th><th>Г</th><th>Д</th><th>Е</th><th>Ж</th><th>З</th><th>И</th><th>К</th></tr><tr><th>1</th><th>2</th><th>3</th><th>4</th><th>5</th><th>6</th><th>7</th><th>8</th><th>9</th><th>10</th></tr></table><newline />
      If you want to order the rotors into base position (1 .. 10), press the button 'Base positions'.
      <newline /><newline />
      In the 'Rotor offsets' menu, you can determine the initial offset on each of the rotors. Rotor [x] offset specifies the offset for the rotor placed in position (Rotor order) [x].
      <newline />
      If you want to reset the offsets, press the button 'Null offsets'. The 'Base positions' button sets increasing offsets for the rotors (1 .. 10).
      <newline /><newline />
      In the 'Ring offsets' menu, you can determine the offset of the ring on each of the rotors.
      <newline />
      If you want to reset the offsets, press the button 'Null offsets'.
      <newline /><newline />
      In the 'Punch card' menu, you can configure a punch card substitution.
      If you want to reset (remove) the punch card, press the button 'Set identity'.
      <newline /><newline /></section><section headline="PROTON II additional key settings">
      The PROTON II rotor type contains some additional settings.
      <newline />
      The core of the rotors (the wiring) can be rotated, flipped or exchanged with another rotor.
      <newline />
      If the cores are in the same order as rotors, inserted in side I and with 0 offsets, the PROTON II rotors are the same as the PROTON I rotors.
      <newline /><newline />
      In the 'Core order' menu, you can determine the position of cores in the rotors. Core [x] order specifies the core placed into the rotor at position [x].
      If the core is inserted into a new position, the pin position on the rotor remains the same, but the rotor wiring is changed.
      <newline />
      The following table contains the core labels (Cyrillic and numeric values):
      <table border="1"><tr><th>А</th><th>Б</th><th>В</th><th>Г</th><th>Д</th><th>Е</th><th>Ж</th><th>З</th><th>И</th><th>К</th></tr><tr><th>1</th><th>2</th><th>3</th><th>4</th><th>5</th><th>6</th><th>7</th><th>8</th><th>9</th><th>10</th></tr></table><newline /><newline />
      In the 'Core offsets' menu, you can determine the initial offset of each core. Core [x] offset specifies the offset for the core placed into the rotor at position [x].
      <newline />
      If you want to reset the offsets, press the button 'Null offsets'.
      <newline /><newline />
      In the 'Core sides' menu, you can determine if the cores are flipped. Core [x] side specifies the side for the core placed into the rotor at position [x].
      <newline />
      The 'Default core sides' button sets side I for all cores.
      <newline /><newline /></section><section headline="M-125-3 specific settings">
      The M-125-3 model allows to select between different text operation modes.
      <newline />
      Each key on the machine's keyboard contains a letter and a special character for both the Cyrillic and the Latin print head.
      Selecting the 'Print head mapping' you can choose whether the Cyrillic or the Latin layout is used (for input and output).
      The Latin layout is country specific and can be set in the 'Country layout' part of the 'Fialka machine settings'.
      <newline />
      The allowed charsets of the available layouts are presented in <ref id="Cryptomuseum" />.
      <newline /><newline />
      If you want to use letters, select the 'Letters' option in the 'Text operation mode'.
      The 'Letters' mode is compatible with the older M-125 device.
      <newline /><newline />
      For special characters select the 'Numbers' option.
      <newline /><newline />
      There is also an option to use both letters and special characters. To set this mode, select the 'Mixed' option.
      In this case two keys are given up to switch between the 'Letters' and 'Numbers' modes.
      <newline />
      When a letter shift character ('[','5','Ж') is present in the input, the 'Letters' mode will be used for the next input.
      <newline />
      When a number shift character (']','7','A','Ф') is present in the input, the 'Numbers' mode will be used for the next input.
      <newline />
      It is also necessary to select the corresponding letter/number shift character based on the selected print head and on the selected country layout.
      To make this process easier the '[' and ']' characters can be used in all cases.
      <newline /><newline />
      The M-125-3 model can be used to encrypt only numerical data (numbers 0,1,..9).
      If you want to use this mode, set the 'NumLock' settings to 'NumLock 10', in all other cases use the 'NumLock 30' option.
      <newline />
      On the real Fialka machine this mode is only available when the 'Text operation mode' is set to 'Numbers' and the 'Print head mapping' is set to 'Cyrillic'.
      <newline />
      Selecting the 'NumLock 10' mode automatically sets the required 'Text operation mode' and the 'Print head mapping'. In this case the non-numeric inputs are invalid.
      <newline /></section></usage>
  <usage lang="zh-CN">在组件的设置中，可以从多个设置组中进行选择。在“工作区”菜单中，您可以找到用于处理未知符号的设置以及恢复初始键的时间段（在按下PLAY按钮之前保存的时间）。如果输入文本包含所选字符集不支持的符号（由打印头和国家/地区布局指定），则可以选择是删除，忽略还是用字母“ @”代替该符号。如果忽略它，它将被原样添加到输出文本中。每次按下PLAY按钮之前，机器设置都会被保存。如果保存期限设置为：“执行后”-加密过程完成后，将恢复保存的密钥； “停止按下”-仅在按下“停止”按钮时才恢复保存的键；如果在按“停止”之前修改输入，则应用更改后的键； “输入已更改”-每次调用加密之前都会恢复保存的密钥； “从不”-保存的密钥永远不会恢复。 “ Fialka机器设置”菜单包含主要机器设置。您可以设置机器型号（M-125 / M-125-3），转子类型（PROTON I / PROTON II），国家/地区特定的布局和转子系列。在此菜单中，您还可以找到打印头映射，数字锁定类型和文本操作模式。 num锁定和文本操作模式仅适用于M-125-3机器类型。操作模式指定使用机器对输入消息进行加密还是解密。也可以将此模式设置为纯文本模式-不进行任何加密。其余的可用设置根据所选的转子类型构成机器的钥匙。在“ Fialka机器设置”菜单的“转子系列”部分中，您可以选择特定国家/地区的转子系列。可用的转子组取决于所选的转子系列。转子在所有国家都是唯一的（不同的排列和不同的销钉位置）。在“转子顺序”菜单中，可以确定转子在主轴上的位置。这些位置在反射镜上标记为1到10。每个转子都包含唯一的接线（替代）和插针位置（负责转子步进）。下表包含转子标签（西里尔字母和数字值）：АБВГДЕЖЗИК12345678910如果要将转子定在基本位置（1 .. 10），请按“基本位置”按钮。在“转子偏移”菜单中，您可以确定每个转子的初始偏移。转子[x]偏移量指定放置在位置（转子顺序）[x]的转子的偏移量。如果要重置偏移量，请按“零偏移量”按钮。 “基本位置”按钮为转子（1 .. 10）设置增加的偏移量。在“环偏移”菜单中，您可以确定每个转子上环的偏移。如果要重置偏移量，请按“零偏移量”按钮。在“打孔卡”菜单中，您可以配置打孔卡替代。如果要重置（删除）打孔卡，请按“设置身份”按钮。 PROTON II转子类型包含一些其他设置。转子的芯（布线）可以旋转，翻转或与另一个转子互换。如果铁心与插入到I侧且偏移量为0的转子的顺序相同，则PROTON II转子与PROTON I转子相同。在“铁心顺序”菜单中，您可以确定铁心在转子中的位置。铁心[x]顺序指定了放置在位置[x]的转子中的铁心。如果将磁芯插入新位置，则转子上的插针位置保持不变，但是转子接线改变了。下表包含核心标签（西里尔字母和数字值）：АБВГДЕЖЗИК12345678910在“核心偏移”菜单中，您可以确定每个核心的初始偏移。铁心[x]偏移量指定了放置在转子上位置[x]处的铁心的偏移量。如果要重置偏移量，请按“零偏移量”按钮。在“核心侧面”菜单中，您可以确定核心是否翻转。铁芯[x]侧指定了放置在位置[x]的转子中铁芯的一面。 “默认内核侧面”按钮将所有内核设置为“ I”。 M-125-3模型允许在不同的文本操作模式之间进行选择。机器键盘上的每个键都包含一个字母和一个特殊字符，分别用于西里尔字母和拉丁字母的打印头。选择“打印头映射”，您可以选择使用西里尔字母还是拉丁字母布局（用于输入和输出）。拉丁布局是特定于国家/地区的，可以在“ Fialka机器设置”的“国家/地区布局”部分中进行设置。可用布局的允许字符集显示在中。如果要使用字母，请在“文本操作模式”中选择“字母”选项。 “信”模式与较旧的M-125设备兼容。对于特殊字符，请选择“数字”选项。还可以同时使用字母和特殊字符。要设置此模式，请选择“混合”选项。在这种情况下，将放弃两个键以在“字母”和“数字”模式之间切换。当输入中存在字母移位字符（“ [”，“ 5”，“Ж”）时，下一个输入将使用“字母”模式。如果输入中存在数字移位字符（&amp;#39;]&amp;#39;，&amp;#39;7&amp;#39;，&amp;#39;A&amp;#39;，&amp;#39;Ф&amp;#39;），则“数字”模式将用于下一个输入。还必须根据所选的打印头和所选的国家/地区布局选择相应的字母/数字移位字符。为了简化此过程，可以在所有情况下使用&amp;#39;[&amp;#39;和&amp;#39;]&amp;#39;字符。 M-125-3模型只能用于加密数字数据（数字0,1，.. 9）。如果要使用此模式，请将“ NumLock”设置设置为“ NumLock 10”，在所有其他情况下，请使用“ NumLock 30”选项。在实际的Fialka机器上，仅当“文本操作模式”设置为“数字”且“打印头映射”设置为“西里尔”时，此模式才可用。选择“ NumLock 10”模式会自动设置所需的“文本操作模式”和“打印头映射”。在这种情况下，非数字输入无效。</usage>
  <usage lang="ru">В настройках компонента вы можете выбрать одну из нескольких групп настроек. В меню «Рабочая область» вы найдете настройки для обработки неизвестных символов и период времени восстановления исходного ключа (сохраняется до нажатия кнопки PLAY). Если входной текст содержит символ, который не поддерживается для выбранной кодировки (заданной печатающей головкой и макетом страны), вы можете выбрать, должен ли этот символ быть удален, проигнорирован или заменен буквой «@». Если он игнорируется, он будет добавлен немодифицированный в выходной текст. Настройки аппарата сохраняются каждый раз до нажатия кнопки PLAY. Если для периода сохранения установлено значение: «После выполнения» - сохраненный ключ восстанавливается после завершения процесса шифрования; «Стоп нажата» - сохраненная клавиша восстанавливается только при нажатии кнопки «Стоп»; если вы изменяете ввод до нажатия Стоп, применяется измененная клавиша; «Input changed» - сохраненный ключ восстанавливается каждый раз перед вызовом шифрования; «Никогда» - сохраненный ключ никогда не восстанавливается. Меню «Настройки машины Fialka» содержит основные настройки машины. Вы можете установить модель машины (M-125 / M-125-3), тип ротора (PROTON I / PROTON II), макеты по конкретным странам и серии роторов. В этом меню вы также можете найти отображение печатающей головки, тип num lock и текстовые режимы работы. Режим блокировки num и текстового режима доступен только для типа машины M-125-3. Режим работы указывает, используется ли машина для шифрования или дешифрования входного сообщения. Этот режим также может быть установлен в режим открытого текста - без шифрования. Остальные доступные настройки формируют ключ машины на основе выбранного типа ротора. В разделе «Ряд ротора» в меню «Параметры машины Fialka» вы можете выбрать серию роторных серий для конкретной страны. Доступный набор роторов зависит от выбранной серии роторов. Роторы уникальны (разные перестановки и разные позиции контактов) для всех стран. В меню «Порядок ротора» вы можете определить положение роторов на шпинделе. Позиции отмечены от 1 до 10 от отражателя. Каждый ротор содержит уникальную проводку (подстановку) и положения штырей (отвечающие за степпинг ротора). В следующей таблице указаны метки ротора (кириллические и числовые значения): АБВГДЕЖЗИК12345678910 Если вы хотите заказать роторы в базовое положение (1 .. 10), нажмите кнопку «Базовые позиции». В меню «Смещение ротора» вы можете определить начальное смещение на каждом из роторов. Смещение ротора [x] задает смещение для ротора, помещенного в положение (порядок ротора) [x]. Если вы хотите сбросить смещения, нажмите кнопку «Нулевые смещения». Кнопка «Базовые позиции» устанавливает увеличение смещений для роторов (1 ... 10). В меню «Кольцевые смещения» вы можете определить смещение кольца на каждом из роторов. Если вы хотите сбросить смещения, нажмите кнопку «Нулевые смещения». В меню «Перфокарта» вы можете настроить замену перфокарты. Если вы хотите сбросить (удалить) перфокарту, нажмите кнопку «Установить личность». Тип ротора PROTON II содержит некоторые дополнительные настройки. Ядро роторов (проводку) можно вращать, переворачивать или заменять другим ротором. Если сердечники находятся в том же порядке, что и роторы, вставленные в сторону I и с 0 смещениями, роторы PROTON II такие же, как роторы PROTON I. В меню «Основной заказ» вы можете определить положение сердечников в роторах. Core [x] order определяет сердечник, помещенный в ротор в положении [x]. Если сердечник вставлен в новое положение, положение штифта на роторе остается прежним, но проводка ротора изменяется. В следующей таблице указаны основные метки (кириллические и числовые значения): АБВГДЕЖЗИК12345678910 В меню «Зазоры сердечника» вы можете определить начальное смещение каждого ядра. Смещение сердечника [x] задает смещение для сердечника, помещенного в ротор в положении [x]. Если вы хотите сбросить смещения, нажмите кнопку «Нулевые смещения». В меню «Основные стороны» вы можете определить, перевернуты ли ядра. Соединительная сторона [x] указывает сторону для сердечника, помещенного в ротор в положении [x]. Кнопка «Основные стороны ядра» задает сторону I для всех ядер. Модель M-125-3 позволяет выбирать между различными режимами работы с текстом. Каждый ключ на клавиатуре аппарата содержит букву и специальный символ для кириллицы и латинской печатающей головки. При выборе «Печать печатающей головки» вы можете выбрать, используется ли кириллица или латинский макет (для ввода и вывода). Латинский макет является специфичным для страны и может быть установлен в разделе «Макет страны» в настройках машины Fialka. Разрешенные кодировки доступных макетов представлены в. Если вы хотите использовать буквы, выберите вариант «Письма» в «Текстовом режиме работы». Режим «Письма» совместим с более старым устройством M-125. Для специальных символов выберите параметр «Числа». Существует также возможность использовать как буквы, так и специальные символы. Чтобы установить этот режим, выберите параметр «Смешанный». В этом случае две клавиши передаются для переключения между режимами «Письма» и «Числа». Когда на входе присутствует символ сдвига буквы (&amp;#39;[&amp;#39;, &amp;#39;5&amp;#39;, &amp;#39;Ж&amp;#39;), для следующего ввода будет использоваться режим «Письма». Когда на входе присутствует символ смены номера (&amp;#39;]&amp;#39;, &amp;#39;7&amp;#39;, &amp;#39;A&amp;#39;, &amp;#39;Ф&amp;#39;), для следующего ввода будет использоваться режим «Числа». Также необходимо выбрать соответствующий символ смещения букв / цифр на основе выбранной печатающей головки и на выбранном макете страны. Чтобы облегчить этот процесс, символы &amp;#39;[&amp;#39; и &amp;#39;]&amp;#39; могут использоваться во всех случаях. Модель M-125-3 может использоваться для шифрования только числовых данных (числа 0,1, ... 9). Если вы хотите использовать этот режим, установите для параметра «NumLock» значение «NumLock 10», во всех остальных случаях используйте параметр «NumLock 30». На реальной машине Fialka этот режим доступен только в том случае, если для параметра «Режим работы с текстом» установлено значение «Числа», а «Печать печатающей головки» - «Кириллица». При выборе режима «NumLock 10» автоматически устанавливается необходимый «режим работы с текстом» и «печать печатающей головки». В этом случае нечисловые входы недействительны.</usage>
  <presentation lang="en"></presentation>
  <!--DE-->
  <language culture="de-DE" />
  <introduction lang="de-DE">
    Die Fialka M-125 ist eine elektromechanische Rotor-Chiffriermaschine. Es sind zwei Varianten der Maschine bekannt: Standard (M-125) und erweitert (M-125-3).
    Von beiden Varianten gibt es auch noch länderspezifische Versionen. Es ist bekannt, dass sie in der (ehemaligen) Sowjetunion, Polen, der Tschechoslowakei, Ungarn und der DDR eingesetzt wurde.
    <newline />
    Das Design der Fialka M-125 basiert größtenteils auf der bekannten Chiffriermaschine Enigma. Es gibt allerdings einige wichtige Unterschiede im Aufbau der Maschine, die als Versuch angesehen werden können,
    die bekannten Schwächen der Enigma zu vermeiden.
    <newline /><newline />
    Die Eingabe in die Chiffriermaschine geschieht über die aus 30 Tasten bestehende Tastatur. Wenn eine Taste gedrückt wird, geht ein elektrisches Signal von der Taste durch mehrere elektromechanische Komponenten
    der Maschine bis zu deren Ausgang.
    Die kryptographische Sicherheit der Fialka basiert auf der Verwendung mehrerer Rotoren, wobei jeder einzelne Rotor eine monoalphabetische Substitution realisiert.
    Die Maschine enthält einen Lochkartenleser, mit dem man die feste Permutation des Eingabealphabets mittels einer Lochkarte eingeben kann.
    Die Ausgabe wird auf einen Papierstreifen gedruckt.
    Wenn ein Zeichen verschlüsselt wurde, rotieren die Rotoren in neue Positionen und implementieren daher im nächsten Schritt eine neue Permutation.
    <newline /><newline />
    Fialka hat den folgenden Operationsablauf:
    <list><item> Eine Taste der Tastatur wird gedrückt. </item><item> Der elektrische Stromkreis wird durch den Kartenleser in den Eingangsrotor geleitet.</item><item> Der Stromkreis geht durch die 10 Rotoren und danach zum Reflektor.</item><item> Das Signal wird von Reflektor umgekehrt und durch die oben aufgelisteten Komponenten in umgekehrter Reihenfolge zurückgeschickt und dann ausgedruckt.</item></list><newline />
    Die Verdrahtung des Reflektors der Fialka unterscheidet sich von der Umkehrwalze der Enigma: die realisierte Substitution ist nicht involutorisch, sie enthält einen Zyklus der Länge 3 und einen der Länge 1.
    Das bedeutet, dass, anders als bei der Enigma, für die Entschlüsselung eine andere Operation als für die Verschlüsselung notwendig wird. Der Zyklus der Länge 1 ermöglicht, dass ein Zeichen auch auf sich selbst abgebildet werden kann.
    <newline /><newline />
    Die wichtigsten unterschiede zwischen Enigma und Fialka werden in der folgenden Tabelle zusammengefasst:
    <table border="1"><tr><th></th><th>Enigma</th><th>Fialka</th></tr><tr><td>Rotoranzahl</td><td>3 oder 4</td><td>10</td></tr><tr><td>Alphabetgröße</td><td>26</td><td>30</td></tr><tr><td>Rotorweiterschaltung</td><td>einfach</td><td>basierend auf Blockadepin</td></tr><tr><td>Rotationsrichtung</td><td>alle Rotoren in eine Richtung</td><td>benachbarte Rotoren in entgegengesetzte Richtungen</td></tr><tr><td>Selbstverschlüsselung</td><td>unmöglich</td><td>möglich</td></tr></table><newline /><newline />
    Die Fialka-Komponente ist voll kompatibel zur realen Fialka-Maschine. Sie erlaubt folgende Einstellungen:
    <list><item>Verschiedene Maschinenmodelle (M-125 und M-125-3).</item><item>Verschiedene Rotorensätze (PROTON I und PROTON II) und verschiedene länderspezifische Rotorverdrahtungen (3K : Polen, 5K : Ungarn, 6K : Tschechoslowakei).</item><item>Verschiedene (länderspezifische) Tastaturbelegungen und Typenräder.</item><item>Verschiedene Operationsmodi (Verschlüsseln, Entschlüsseln, Klartextmodus).</item><item>Alle möglichen Schlüsseleinstellungen (Rotorreihenfolge, Rotoroffsets, Ringoffsets, Lochkartensubstitution, Kernreihenfolge, Kernoffsets, Kernorientierungen).</item><item>Verschiedene Text-Operationsmodi für die M-125-3 (nur Buchstaben, nur Zahlen (Sonderzeichen) und gemischter Modus).</item><item>Für die M-125-3 ein besonderer Verschlüsselungsmodus, bei dem die Eingabe nur aus Ziffern besteht (NumLock 10).</item></list></introduction>
  <usage lang="de-DE">
    In den Einstellungen der Komponente kann man zwischen verschiedenen Optionsgruppen auswählen.
    <newline /><newline />
    In der Gruppe "Workspace" befinden sich die Einstellungen für die Behandlung unbekannter Zeichen und für den Zeitpunkt, wann der Schlüssel wieder auf den initialen Schlüssel
    (der gesichert wird, wenn der Start-Button gedrückt wird) gesetzt werden soll.
    <newline />
    Enthält die Eingabe ein Zeichen, das nicht in dem durch das gewählte Typenrad und das Länderlayout bestimmten Zeichensatz vorhanden ist, kann das Zeichen entweder entfernt, ignoriert oder durch '@' ersetzt werden.
    Wird es ignoriert, so wird es unverändert an die Ausgabe weitergegeben.
    <newline />
    Die Maschineneinstellungen werden jedesmal gespeichert, wenn der Start-Button gedrückt wird. Der Schlüssel kann zu verschiedenen Zeitpunkten wiederhergestellt werden:
    <newline />
    "nach Ausführung" - der gespeicherte Schlüssel wird wiederhergestellt, wenn die Verschlüsselung beendet ist;
    <newline />
    "nach Stop" - der gespeicherte Schlüssel wird erst wiederhergestellt, wenn der Stop-Button gedrückt wurde; wird die Eingabe vor Drücken von Stop verändert, wird der geänderte Schlüssel verwendet;
    <newline />
    "bei Änderung der Eingabe" - der gespeicherte Schlüssel wird vor jeder Änderung der Eingabe wiederhergestellt;
    <newline />
    "nie" - der gespeicherte Schlüssel wird nie wiederhergestellt.
    <newline /><newline />
    Die Gruppe "Maschineneinstellungen" enthält die wichtigsten Einstellungsmöglichkeiten der Maschine.
    <newline />
    Man kann das Maschinenmodell (M-125 / M-125-3), den Rotorensatz (PROTON I / PROTON II), länderspezifische Layouts und die Rotoranordnung festlegen.
    Man findet hier auch das Typenrad des Druckers, den NumLock-Typ und die Text-Operationsmodi.
    NumLock und die Text-Operationsmodi sind nur für die M-125-3 möglich.
    <newline />
    Der Operationsmodus gibt an, ob die Maschine die Eingabe verschlüsseln oder entschlüsseln soll. Wird der Klartextmodus gewählt, so wird die Eingabe unverändert an die Ausgabe weitergegeben.
    <newline /><newline />
    Die restlichen Einstellungen bilden, basierend auf dem ausgewählten Rotorensatz, den Schlüssel der Maschine.
    <newline /><newline /><section headline="Schlüsselparameter für PROTON I">
      In der Gruppe "Rotorensatz" kann man den länderspezifischen Rotorensatz auswählen.
      Die verfügbaren Rotoren hängen vom ausgewählten Rotorensatz ab. Die Rotoren sind für alle Länder einzigartig (d.h. unterschiedliche Permutationen und unterschiedliche Pinpositionen).
      <newline /><newline />
      In der Gruppe "Rotoranordnung" kann man die Positionen der Rotoren auf der Spindel festlegen. Die Positionen werden, beginnend beim Reflektor, von 1 bis 10 nummeriert.
      Jeder Rotor enthält eine einzigartige Verdrahtung (Substitution) und Pinpositionen, die für die Weiterschaltung der Rotoren verantwortlich sind.
      <newline />
      Die folgende Tabelle zeigt die Rotorzeichnungen (kyrillische Buchstaben und Ziffern):
      <table border="1"><tr><th>А</th><th>Б</th><th>В</th><th>Г</th><th>Д</th><th>Е</th><th>Ж</th><th>З</th><th>И</th><th>К</th></tr><tr><th>1</th><th>2</th><th>3</th><th>4</th><th>5</th><th>6</th><th>7</th><th>8</th><th>9</th><th>10</th></tr></table><newline />
      Um die Rotoren in der Basisreihenfolge (1 .. 10) anzuordnen, drücken Sie die Schaltfläche "Grundpositionen".
      <newline /><newline />
      In der Gruppe "Rotoroffsets" können Sie die initialen Offsets für jeden Rotor festlegen. Rotor [x] Offset spezifiziert dabei den Offset des Rotors in Position [x] der Rotoranordnung.
      <newline />
      Klicken Sie auf "Nulloffsets", um die Offsets zurückzusetzen. Der Button "Grundpositionen" setzt die Offsets auf die Werte 1-10.
      <newline /><newline />
      In der Gruppe "Ringoffsets" können Sie den Offset des Ringes jedes Rotors bestimmen.
      <newline />
      Klicken Sie auf "Nulloffsets", um die Ringoffsets zurückzusetzen.
      <newline /><newline />
      In der Gruppe "Lochkarte" können Sie die durch die Lochkarte definierte Substitution festlegen.
      Klicken Sie auf den Button "Identität", um die Lochkarte zu entfernen bzw. die Substitution auf die identische Substitution zurückzusetzen.
      <newline /><newline /></section><section headline="Zusätzliche Schlüsselparameter für PROTON II">
      Für den PROTON II-Rotorensatz gibt es einige zusätzliche Einstellungsmöglichkeiten.
      <newline />
      Der Kern der Rotoren (d.h. die Verdrahtung) kann rotiert, umgedreht oder durch einen anderen Kern ersetzt werden.
      <newline />
      Wenn die Kerne in der gleichen Reihenfolge wie die Rotoren angeordnet sind, dieselbe Orientierung und Offset 0 haben, sind die PROTON II-Rotoren identisch zu den PROTON I-Rotoren.
      <newline /><newline />
      In der Gruppe "Kernanordnung" können Sie festlegen, an welcher Position ein Kern eingesetzt werden soll. Kernposition [x] bedeutet, dass der Kern in den Rotor an Position [x] eingesetzt wird.
      Wenn ein Kern in eine neue Position gesetzt wird, bleibt die Pinposition unverändert und nur die Verdrahtung wird gewechselt.
      <newline />
      Die folgende Tabelle zeigt die Bezeichnung der Kerne (kyrillisch und Zahlen):
      <table border="1"><tr><th>А</th><th>Б</th><th>В</th><th>Г</th><th>Д</th><th>Е</th><th>Ж</th><th>З</th><th>И</th><th>К</th></tr><tr><th>1</th><th>2</th><th>3</th><th>4</th><th>5</th><th>6</th><th>7</th><th>8</th><th>9</th><th>10</th></tr></table><newline /><newline />
      In der Gruppe "Kernoffsets" kann man den initialen Offset für jeden Kern eingeben. Kernoffset [x] spezifiziert den Offset für den Kern, der im Rotor an der Position [x] eingesetzt ist.
      <newline />
      Um die Kernoffsets zurückzusetzen, drücken Sie den Button "Nulloffsets".
      <newline /><newline />
      In der Gruppe "Kernorientierung" können Sie festlegen, ob die Kerne normal oder um 180 Grad gedreht eingesetzt werden sollen.
      Kernorientierung [x] spezifiziert die Orientierung für den Kern, der in dem Rotor an Position [x] eingesetzt ist.
      <newline />
      Drücken Sie "Kernorientierungen zurücksetzen", um alle Kerne auf Seite I zu orientieren.
      <newline /><newline /></section><section headline="Spezifische Einstellungen für die M-125-3">
      Im Modell M-125-3 kann man zwischen verschiedenen Text-Operationsmodi wählen.
      <newline />
      Auf jeder Taste der Tastatur der Maschine sind ein Buchstabe und ein Sonderzeichen für das kyrillische und das lateinische Typenrad.
      In der Einstellung "Typenrad" können Sie auswählen, ob das kyrillische oder das lateinische Layout (für Eingabe und Ausgabe) verwendet werden soll.
      Das lateinische Layout ist länderspezifisch und kann in der Einstellung "Länderspezifisches Layout" angepasst werden.
      <newline />
      Die verwendeten Zeichensätze der vorhandenen Layouts werden auf dieser Seite aufgelistet: <ref id="Cryptomuseum" /><newline /><newline />
      Wenn Sie nur Buchstaben verschlüsseln wollen, wählen Sie den Operationsmodus "Buchstaben".
      Diese Betriebsart ist kompatibel zu dem älteren Modell M-125.
      <newline /><newline />
      Für Sonderzeichen wählen Sie den Operationsmodus "Zahlen".
      <newline /><newline />
      Buchstaben und Sonderzeichen können auch gemeinsam verwendet werden. Wählen Sie dazu den Operationsmodus "Gemischt".
      In diesem Fall werden zwei besondere Zeichen benutzt, um zwischen den Modi "Buchstaben" und "Zahlen" umzuschalten.
      <newline />
      
      Wenn eines der Umschaltzeichen ('[','5','Ж') in der Eingabe vorkommt, wird der Buchstabenmodus für die folgenden Eingabezeichen aktiviert.
      <newline />
      Wenn eines der Umschaltzeichen (']','7','A','Ф') in der Eingabe vorkommt, wird der Zahlenmodus für die folgenden Eingabezeichen aktiviert.
      <newline />
      Die zu verwendenden Umschaltzeichen hängen vom gewählten Typenrad und dem gewählten Länderlayout ab. Um die Umschaltung zu vereinfachen, können in allen Fällen
      die Zeichen '[' und ']' als Umschaltzeichen benutzt werden.
      <newline /><newline />
      Mit dem Modell M-125-3 kann man Eingabedaten, die nur aus Ziffern bestehen, verschlüsseln. Stellen Sie dazu die Einstellung "NumLock" auf "NumLock 10".
      Verwenden Sie "NumLock 30" in allen anderen Fällen.
      <newline />
      In der realen Fialka ist dieser Modus nur verfügbar, wenn der Text-Operationsmodus auf "Zahlen" und das Typenrad auf "kyrillisch" eingestellt ist.
      <newline />
      Wenn "NumLock 10" ausgewählt wird, werden der Text-Operationmodus und das Typenrad automatisch auf die erforderlichen Werte gesetzt. In diesem Fall sind nichtnumerische Eingaben ungültig.
      <newline /></section></usage>
  <presentation lang="de-DE"></presentation>
  <!--REFERENCES-->
  <references>
    <linkReference>
      <link url="http://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/01611194.2014.915264" />
      <caption lang="en">Key Space and Period of Fialka M-125 Cipher Machine (Cryptologia)</caption>
      <caption lang="de">Key Space and Period of Fialka M-125 Cipher Machine (Cryptologia) (englisch)</caption>
    </linkReference>
    <linkReference id="Cryptomuseum">
      <link url="http://www.cryptomuseum.com/crypto/fialka/" />
      <caption lang="en">Fialka (Cryptomuseum)</caption>
      <caption lang="de">Fialka (Cryptomuseum) (englisch)</caption>
    </linkReference>
    <linkReference>
      <link url="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Fialka" lang="en" />
      <caption lang="en">Fialka (Wikipedia)</caption>
      <link url="https://de.wikipedia.org/wiki/Fialka_(Maschine)" lang="de" />
      <caption lang="de">Fialka (Wikipedia)</caption>
    </linkReference>
  </references>
</documentation>