<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<documentation>
  <language culture="en" />
  <language culture="zh-CN" />
  <language culture="ru" />
  <language culture="de-DE" />
  <introduction lang="en">
    This WEP component allows you to encrypt or decrypt the input data according to the Wired Equivalent Privacy (WEP) protocol.
    Developed and published by the Institute of Electrical and Electronics Engineers (IEEE) in 1999, the WEP protocol was the first
    protocol for security matters within a Wireless Local Area Network (WLAN). The main features are encryption and decryption of
    transmitted packets and an Integrity Check Value (ICV) which is used to detect transmission errors within the packets.<newline /><newline />
        According to the protocol a key is used which consists of either 5, 13 or 29 bytes. In the WEP component there are only key sizes of 5 and 13 bytes supported. This key is called RootKey (RK). The RK is concatenated with a packet individual Initialization Vector(IV) consisting of 3 bytes.
        So the key K, which is in fact used to encrypt or decrypt a packet i is:
      <newline /><newline />
    K of packet i = (IV of packet i || RK)<newline /><newline />
    The packets are encrypted / decrypted with the RC4 algorithm, a simple stream cipher algorithm.<newline /><newline />
    The user can choose if the component is going to encrypt or to decrypt.<newline /><newline />
    If the packets are going to be encrypted an individual ICV is computed for each packet. This is called Cyclic Redundancy Check (CRC) and it is
    based on a polynomial division with a well defined 32 bit polynom. The result is a checksum of 32 bit which protects the packet
    against transmission errors but not against manipulation. This checksum is added to the packet and then the packet will be encrypted.
    This step is missing within the decryption. Instead, the ICV is removed from the packet. In a real world scenario the receiver of a packet
    would compute the ICV himself again and compare the two ICVs. If they are not equal the packet would be requested from the sender again.
  </introduction>
  <introduction lang="zh-CN">该WEP组件使您可以根据有线等效保密（WEP）协议对输入数据进行加密或解密。 WEP协议由电气和电子工程师协会（IEEE）于1999年开发和发布，是无线局域网（WLAN）中涉及安全问题的第一个协议。主要功能是对传输的数据包进行加密和解密，以及用于检测数据包内传输错误的完整性检查值（ICV）。根据协议，使用的密钥由5、13或29个字节组成。在WEP组件中，仅支持5和13字节的密钥大小。此密钥称为RootKey（RK）。 RK与包含3个字节的单个数据包初始化矢量（IV）串联。因此，实际上用于加密或解密数据包i的密钥K为：数据包i的K =（数据包i || RK的IV）数据包使用RC4算法（一种简单的流密码算法）进行加密/解密。用户可以选择组件是要加密还是要解密。如果要对数据包进行加密，则会为每个数据包计算一个单独的ICV。这称为循环冗余校验（CRC），它基于具有定义明确的32位多项式的多项式除法。结果是一个32位的校验和，可以保护数据包免受传输错误的侵害，但不能保护其免受操纵。将此校验和添加到数据包，然后将对数据包进行加密。解密中缺少此步骤。而是从包中删除了ICV。在现实世界中，数据包的接收者将自己再次计算ICV并比较两个ICV。如果它们不相等，则将再次向发送方请求该分组。</introduction>
  <introduction lang="ru">Этот компонент WEP позволяет шифровать или расшифровывать входные данные в соответствии с протоколом Wired Equivalent Privacy (WEP). Разработанный и опубликованный Институтом инженеров по электротехнике и электронике (IEEE) в 1999 году, протокол WEP стал первым протоколом по вопросам безопасности в беспроводной локальной сети (WLAN). Основными функциями являются шифрование и дешифрование переданных пакетов и значение проверки целостности (ICV), которое используется для обнаружения ошибок передачи в пакетах. Согласно протоколу используется ключ, который состоит из 5, 13 или 29 байтов. В WEP-компоненте поддерживаются только ключевые размеры в 5 и 13 байт. Этот ключ называется RootKey (RK). РК объединяется с индивидуальным вектором инициализации пакета (IV), состоящим из 3 байтов. Таким образом, ключ K, который на самом деле используется для шифрования или дешифрования пакета i, это: K пакета i = (IV пакета i || RK). Пакеты шифруются / дешифруются с помощью алгоритма RC4, простого алгоритма шифрования потока. Пользователь может выбрать, будет ли компонент шифроваться или расшифровываться. Если пакеты будут зашифрованы, для каждого пакета вычисляется индивидуальный ICV. Это называется Cyclic Redundancy Check (CRC), и оно основано на полиномиальном делении с хорошо определенным 32-битным полиномом. Результатом является контрольная сумма в 32 бит, которая защищает пакет от ошибок передачи, но не от манипуляции. Эта контрольная сумма добавляется к пакету, а затем пакет будет зашифрован. Этот шаг отсутствует в расшифровке. Вместо этого ICV удаляется из пакета. В сценарии реального мира получатель пакета снова вычислил ICV и сравнил два ICV. Если они не равны, пакет будет запрошен у отправителя.</introduction>
  <introduction lang="de-DE">
    Mit der WEP-Komponente kann man die Eingabedaten nach dem WEP-Protokoll ("Wired Equivalent Privacy Protocol") ver- und entschlüsseln.
    Entwickelt und veröffentlicht vom "Institute of Electrical and Electronics Engineering" (IEEE) im Jahr 1999, war WEP das erste Protokoll 
    für Sicherheit innerhalb eines Drahtlosen Netzwerkes (WLAN). Die hauptsächlichen Aufgaben sind das Ver- und Entschlüsseln von übertragenen
    Paketen und ein "Integrity Check Value" (ICV), welcher verwendet wird, um Übertragungsfehler innerhalb des Pakets zu entdecken. <newline /><newline />
    Je nach Protokoll besteht der Schlüssel aus 5, 13 oder 29 Bytes. In der WEP-Komponente kann nur ein Schlüssel mit einer Größe von 5 oder 13 Bytes genutzt werden. Dieser Schlüssel wird RootKey genannt (RK). Der RootKey wird mit einem individuellen Initialisierungsvektor (IV), der aus 3 Bytes besteht, konkateniert.
    Das bedeutet, dass der Schlüssel K, der dann tatsächlich ein Paket i ver- oder entschlüsselt, folgendermaßen aussieht:
    <newline /><newline />
    K von Paket i = (IV of packet i || RK)<newline /><newline />
    Die Pakete werden mit dem RC4-Algorithmus ver-/entschlüsselt. RC4 ist ein einfacher Stromverschlüsselungs-Algorithmus.<newline /><newline />
    Der Benutzer kann auswählen, ob die Komponente ver- oder entschlüsseln soll.<newline /><newline />
    Wenn die Pakete verschlüsselt werden, wird ein individueller ICV für jedes Paket berechnet. Der ICV ("Integrity Check Value") wird auch als "Cyclic Redundancy Check" (CRC) bezeichnet
    und basiert auf einer Polynomdivision mit einem definierten 32-Bit-Polynom. Das Ergebnis ist eine Prüfsumme von 32 Bit (4 Byte) Länge, die das Paket zwar vor Übertragungsfehlern schützt, aber nicht vor Manipulation. Diese Checksumme wird dem Paket angehängt und anschließend wird alles verschlüsselt. Dieser
    Schritt wird in der Implementierung dieser Komponente bei der Entschlüsselung nicht durchgeführt. Stattdessen wird der ICV einfach vom Paket entfernt. In realen Applikationen bestimmt der Empfänger
    den ICV ebenfalls und vergleicht ihn mit dem empfangenen ICV. Sind die beiden ICVs nicht gleich, wird das Paket verworfen und neu vom Sender angefordert.
  </introduction>
  <usage lang="en">
    To use the WEP component the user has to put it onto the workspace. A 40bit key has to be provided. The WEP component offers to encrypt or to
    decrypt packets which have to be provided using an CrypToolStream. To generate test packets an IFrame Generator component is suitable. Depending
    on the users choice to encrypt or to decrypt the WEP component delivers encrypted or decrypted packets using the provided key.
  </usage>
  <usage lang="zh-CN">要使用WEP组件，用户必须将其放在工作区中。必须提供一个40位的密钥。 WEP组件提供加密或解密必须使用CrypToolStream提供的数据包的功能。要生成测试数据包，可以使用IFrame Generator组件。根据用户的选择，加密或解密WEP组件使用提供的密钥传递加密或解密的数据包。</usage>
  <usage lang="ru">Чтобы использовать компонент WEP, пользователь должен поместить его в рабочую область. Должен быть предоставлен 40-битный ключ. Компонент WEP предлагает шифровать или расшифровывать пакеты, которые должны быть предоставлены с использованием CrypToolStream. Для генерации тестовых пакетов подходящим является компонент генератора IFrame. В зависимости от выбора пользователя для шифрования или дешифрования WEP-компонент поставляет зашифрованные или дешифрованные пакеты с использованием предоставленного ключа.</usage>
  <usage lang="de-DE">
    Um die WEP-Komponente zu verwenden, muss der Benutzer diese auf den Arbeitsplatz ziehen. Als Input werden benötigt: Erstens ein 40-Bit-Schlüssel, und zweitens Pakete in Form eines CrypToolStream. WEP-Pakete können mit dem IFRame-Generator erzeugt werden.
    Je nach Wahl des Benutzers liefert die WEP-Komponente aus dem Input ver- oder entschlüsselte WEP-Pakete unter Nutzung des angegebenen Schlüssels.
  </usage>
  <presentation lang="en"></presentation>
  <presentation lang="de-DE"></presentation>
  <references>
    <linkReference id="wikipedia">
      <link url="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Wired_Equivalent_Privacy" lang="en" />
      <caption lang="en">WEP (Wikipedia)</caption>
      <link url="http://de.wikipedia.org/wiki/Wired_Equivalent_Privacy" lang="de-DE" />
      <caption lang="de-DE">WEP (Wikipedia)</caption>
    </linkReference>
  </references>
</documentation>