<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<documentation>
  <language culture="en" />
  <language culture="zh-CN" />
  <language culture="ru" />
  <language culture="de-DE" />
  <introduction lang="en">
        By using the ArrayOperation module, various transformations on arrays of arbitrary element type can be performed. 
    </introduction>
  <introduction lang="zh-CN">通过使用ArrayOperation模块，可以对任意元素类型的数组执行各种转换。</introduction>
  <introduction lang="ru">To be written yet</introduction>
  <introduction lang="de-DE">
        Array-Operationen ermöglichen es, Arrays umzuformen oder über deren Inhalt einen Wert zu berechnen, unabhängig vom Typ der Array-Elemente.<br /></introduction>
  <usage lang="en">
        An Array operation module has various inputs to accommodate the different possible operations:
        <ul><li><b>Array</b>-typed inputs, here called A1, A2 and A3
            </li><li><b>Object</b>-typed inputs, here called O1, O2
            </li><li><b>Integer (Int32)</b>-typed inputs, here called I1 and I2
            </li></ul>

        When providing the input values, three primary inputs of type "Array" can be used and are referred to as A1, A2 and A3. To make it easier to specify simple arrays, A2 and A3 can be specified by alternatively providing a single value for the generically "Object"-typed inputs O1 and O2, respectively. For example, if A2 is not specified, but O1 is, then the second array is assumed as {O1}, the one-element array that contains the value O1. <br /> Integer values are provided through inputs I1 and I2.
        Therefore, when "A2" is referenced in the following descriptions of the operations, unless explicitely noted, O2 can be provided instead to specify a single-argument array.
        <br /><br />
        Output of an array operation can either be an array R or an integer r.

        <enum><item><b>Set-Union:</b>From inputs A1 and A2, R is produced so that all elements that appear in A1 and A2 are contained. No element is present more than once in R.
            </item><item><b>Set-Complement (Difference):</b>From inputs A1 and A2, R is produced so that all elements that appear in A1 and not in A2 are contained in R. No element is present more than once in R.
            </item><item><b>Set-Intersection</b> From inputs A1 and A2, R is produced so that all elements that appear in A1 and at the same time appear in A2 are contained in R. No element is present more than once in R.
            </item><item><b>Concatenate</b>A1 and A2 are appended to each other to yield R. The length of R is then the sum of the lengths of A1 and A2.
            </item><item><b>Equals: </b>A1 and A2 are tested for element-wise equality: If they have the same length, and do contain the same elements in the same order, then the output r is true (bool value), else, it is false.
            </item><item><b>Unique: </b>A1 is stripped of all duplicate elements into the output array R.</item><item><b>Length</b>The output r (integer value) is the length of A1.
            </item><item><b>Replace: </b>Every occurrence of the array A2 in the array A1 is replaced with the array A3. Single-element replacement can comfortably be specified with the one-element-array specification of the second and third arrays through inputs O1 and O2.
            </item><item><b>Sort (Ascending): </b>The array A1 is sorted in ascending order and returned as output R.
            </item><item><b>Sort (Descending): </b>The array A1 is sorted in descending order and returned as output R.
            </item><item><b>Reverse</b>Reverts the order of the elements of A1 and stores it in
                the output R.
            </item><item><b>Subarray: </b>Stores in output R a sub-array of A1. The integer input I1 specifies the zero-based index of the first element to be selected into R. The input I2 specifies the length of the sub-array.
            </item><item><b>IndexOf: </b> Stores in output r the zero-based index of the object from input O1 in the array A1. A1 value of -1 is stored if O1 is not present in A1
            </item><item><b>Contains: </b>Stores in output r the boolean value of whether the object from input O1 is present in the array A1
            </item></enum></usage>
  <usage lang="zh-CN">数组操作模块具有各种输入以适应不同的可能操作：数组类型的输入，在此称为A1，A2和A3对象类型的输入，在此称为O1，O2整数（Int32）类型的输入，在此称为I1和I2如果提供输入值，则可以使用类型为“ Array”的三个主要输入，分别称为A1，A2和A3。为了使指定简单数组更容易，可以通过分别为通用“对象”类型的输入O1和O2提供一个值来指定A2和A3。例如，如果未指定A2，但指定了O1，则将第二个数组假定为{O1}，即包含值O1的单元素数组。通过输入I1和I2提供整数值。因此，当在以下操作说明中引用“ A2”时，除非明确指出，否则可以提供O2来指定单参数数组。数组运算的输出可以是数组R或整数r。 Set-Union：从输入A1和A2产生R，以便包含出现在A1和A2中的所有元素。 R中没有元素存在一次以上。Set-Complement（Difference）：从输入A1和A2产生R，以便所有出现在A1中而不是在A2中的元素都包含在R中。没有元素存在一次以上从输入A1和A2产生集合R，以便在A1中出现并且同时在A2中出现的所有元素都包含在R中。在R中不存在一次以上的元素。ConcatenateA1和A2是彼此相加得到R。R的长度就是A1和A2的长度之和。相等：对A1和A2进行元素方式相等性测试：如果它们具有相同的长度，并且确实包含相同顺序的相同元素，则输出r为true（布尔值），否则为false。唯一：将A1的所有重复元素都剥离到输出数组R中。长度输出r（整数值）是A1的长度。替换：数组A1中每次出现的数组A2都替换为数组A3。可以轻松地通过输入O1和O2用第二个阵列和第三个阵列的一个元素数组规范指定单个元素替换。排序（升序）：数组A1升序排序并作为输出R返回。排序（降序）：数组A1降序排序并作为输出R返回。反向反转A1元素的顺序并将其存储在子数组：在输出R中存储A1的子数组。整数输入I1指定要选择到R中的第一个元素的从零开始的索引。输入I2指定子数组的长度。 IndexOf：在输出r中存储来自数组A1中输入O1的对象的从零开始的索引。如果A1中不存在O1，则存储-1的A1值包含：将输出O1中的对象是否存在于数组A1中的布尔值存储在输出r中</usage>
  <usage lang="ru">У StringOperations есть два текстовых ввода и два ввода номера. В зависимости от используемой функции эти входы имеют различное использование. Он также имеет текстовый вывод, вывод текстового массива и вывод номера. Конкатенация: требуется только текстовые входы. Объединение заданных текстов в одну новую строку. Требуется первые текстовые входы и оба ввода номера (X, Y). Возвращает подстроку из X с длиной Y в тексте outputTo-Lowercase: преобразует заданный текст первого текстового ввода в текст только с строчными буквами. To-Uppercase: преобразует заданный текст первого текстового ввода в текст только с прописными буквамиLengthOf : Возвращает длину текста первого ввода текста на номере outputCompareTo: сравнивает оба заданных текста и возвращает 0, если они равны, -1, если текст один «меньше», чем текст 2, и 1, если текст один больше &amp;#39;than text twoTrim: удаляет пробелы с начала и конца (вкладка Leerzeichen) текста ввода текста один и возвращает этот текст в текст outputIndexOf: дает первый индекс заполнения текста текстового ввода два в тексте ввод текста один в число outputEquals: возвращает 1 на выходе номера, если тексты равны, в противном случае 0Replace: заменяет все подстроки первой входной строки, которые равны второй входной строке третьей входной строкой и возвращает новую строку RegexReplace: Заменяет все подстроки первой входной строки, которые соответствуют регулярному выражению, предоставленному второй входной строкой, третьей входной строкой и возвращает новую строкуSplit: разделяет текст первого ввода на строку, указанную во втором текстовом вводе ( или в новых строках, если ввод пуст) и возвращает полученные подстроки в выходном массивеBlock: Форматирует заданную строку в блоки (используя параметр «Размер блока») после удаления всех символов пробелов. Обороты: Обрабатывает заданный текст первого ввода текста. Заменяет пароль. : Добавляет пароль спереди или хвосту строки и удаляет все возникающие символы этого пароля в остальной части stringDistinct: удаляет все двойные вхождения одних и тех же символов из строкиLevenshtein Distance: вычисляет расстояние Levenshtein двух заданных строк</usage>
  <usage lang="de-DE">
        Verschiedene Eingaben sind für die Array-Operationen notwendig. Nicht alle müssen immer mit Werten belegt werden.
        <ul><li><b>Array</b>-Typ Eingaben: A1, A2 und A3
            </li><li><b>Object</b>-Typ Eingaben: O1 und O2
            </li><li><b>Integer (Int32)</b>-Typ Eingaben, I1 und I2
            </li></ul>

        Wenn Array-Werte für die Eingaben A2 und A3 angegeben werden müssen, können auch alternativ Werte für jeweils O1 und O2 angegeben werden. Es wird dann ein ein-elementiges Array anstelle des fehlenden Array-Wertes verwendet. Wenn zum Beispiel beide Eingaben A2 und O1 belegt sind, hat der Array-Wert Vorrang. Wenn A2 jedoch nicht belegt ist, so wird das Array {O1} angenommen.

        <br /><br />
        Die Ausgabe der Array-Operationen erfolgt über den Array-Typ-Ausgang (hier R genannt) und einen Ausgang vom Typ Object, welcher für alle nicht-Array-Rückgabewerte verantwortlich ist.

        <enum><item><b>Mengen-Vereinigung:</b>Bildet die Vereinigung der Mengen A1 und A2 und gibt diese in R aus. Lässt keine doppelten Elemente im Ergebnis.
            </item><item><b>Mengen-Komplement (Differenz):</b>Bildet die Mengen-Differenz (Komplement) von A1 und A2 und gibt diese in R aus. Lässt keine doppelten Elemente im Ergebnis.
            </item><item><b>Mengen-Schnitt: </b> Bildet die Schittmenge aus A1 und A2 und gibt diese in R aus. Lässt keine doppelten Elemente im Ergebnis.
            </item><item><b>Konkatenation: </b>Reiht die Arrays A1 und A2 aneinander und gibt dies in R aus.
            </item><item><b>Gleichheit: </b>Testet, ob A1 und A2 gleich sind (gleiche Elemente beinhalten) und gibt den bool-Wert in r aus.
            </item><item><b>Keine Duplikate:</b>Löscht Duplikate aus A1 und gibt das Ergebnis in R aus.</item><item><b>Länge: </b>Gibt die Länge von A1 in r aus.
            </item><item><b>Ersetzen: </b>Ersetzt Vorkommnisse von A2 in A1 durch A3 und gibt das Ergebnis in R aus.
            </item><item><b> Sortieren (Aufsteigend): </b>Sortiert A1 aufsteigend und gibt das Ergebnis in R aus.
            </item><item><b>Sortieren (Absteigend): </b> Sortiert A1 absteigend und gibt das Ergebnis in R aus.
            </item><item><b>Umkehren: </b>Kehrt die Reihenfolge der Elemente in A1 um und gibt das Ergebnis in R aus.
            </item><item><b>Subarray: </b>Das Subarray, welches in A1 mit dem Null-basierten Index I1 beginnt und die Länge I2 hat, wird in R abgelegt.
            </item><item><b>IndexOf: </b>Das Array A2 wird in A1 gesucht und dessen Null-basierter Index wird in r abgelegt. Wenn A2 nicht in A1 vorkommt, wird der Wert -1 in r abgelegt.
            </item><item><b>Enthält: </b>Gibt den boolschen Wert in r aus, der aussagt, ob das Array A2 in A1 vorkommt
            </item></enum></usage>
  <presentation lang="en"></presentation>
  <presentation lang="de-DE"></presentation>
  <references></references>
</documentation>