<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<documentation>
  <language culture="en" />
  <language culture="de-DE" />
  <introduction lang="en">
    The Kasiski test is a method of attacking a Vigenère cipher in order to find out the length of the keyword.
    <newline /><newline />
    The method was first developed by Charles Babbage and later by Prussian infantry officer Friedrich Wilhelm Kasiski, who also published the method in 1863.
    The Kasiski examination involves looking for strings of characters that are repeated in the ciphertext.
    Then, the distances between consecutive occurrences of the strings are likely to be multiples of the length of the keyword.
    The reason this test works is that if a repeated string occurs in the plaintext, and the distance between the repetitions is a multiple of the keyword length, the keyword letters will line up in the same way with both occurrences of the string.
  </introduction>
  <introduction lang="de-DE">
    Mit dem Kasiski-Test kann man die Schlüssellänge einer Vigenère-Chiffre ermitteln.
    <newline /><newline />
    Der Test wurde von Charles Babbage entwickelt und vom preußischen Offizier Friedrich Wilhelm Kasiski 1863 erstmals veröffentlicht.
    Der Kasiski-Test untersucht einen Geheimtext nach sich wiederholenden Zeichenfolgen. Die Wahrscheinlichkeit, dass die Distanzen zwischen zwei Wiederholungen ein Vielfaches der Schlüssellänge sind, ist sehr groß,
    und um so größer, je länger die sich wiederholenden Zeichenfolgen sind.
    Der Grund dafür ist, dass sich wiederholende Zeichenfolgen im Klartext, deren Distanz ein Vielfaches der Schlüssellänge ist, bei der Vigenère-Verschlüsselung auch mit demselben Teil des Schlüssels verschlüsselt werden
    und daher auch gleiche Zeichenfolgen im Geheimtext bilden.
  </introduction>
  <usage lang="en">
    Enter the text, that is to be analyzed, at the input of the component.
    It should be a ciphertext that was generated by encrypting a plaintext with the Vigenère cipher.
    <newline /><newline />
    In the settings, you can adjust some parameters for the Kasiski test.
    <newline /><newline />
    The "Gram length" setting is used to set the maximum length of grams (short strings of characters) between which we count distances.
    The default value is three, but setting a higher value improves the precision of the algorithm.
    <newline /><newline />
    The "Maximum factor size" setting is used to set the maximum factor (hence maximum probable key length) which the algorithm should take into consideration.
    The default value is 20.
    <newline /><newline />
    The "Case sensitivity" setting is used to determine if the algorithm should analyze the input with or without any changes to the case of letters.
    The default value is "Yes 'a' should equal 'A'", i.e. the algorithm will set all letters of the input string to lower case.
    <newline /><newline />
    The "Unknown symbol handling" setting is used to determine whether or not unknown and/or special symbols (numbers, umlauts, space, new lines etc.) should be left in the input string for consequent analysis.
    Default value is "Remove", meaning that all unknown symbols (in our case symbols that are not part of the Latin/English alphabet) are removed.
    <newline /><newline />
    On the text output of the component you will get numbers sorted in two columns. The two columns are divided by the column (":") sign. The left column contains all factors (and therefore keylengths) the component took into consideration.
    Each value on the right corresponds to a factor on the left and represents the number of times this particular factor was encountered during the examination of the input string.
    The factors are also output as an integer array, where the index corresponds to the examined factor, and the entry at that index is the frequency with which the factor occured.
  </usage>
  <usage lang="de-DE">
    Geben Sie den zu analysierenden Text am Eingang der Komponente an. Der Text muss ein mit dem Vigenère-Verfahren verschlüsselter Geheimtext sein.
    <newline /><newline />
    In den Einstellungen der Komponente können Sie einige Parameter für den Kasiski-Test angeben:
    <newline /><newline />
    Sie können die maximale Länge der N-Gramme angeben, nach denen der Geheimtext untersucht werden soll (Minimum und Default: 3).
    <newline /><newline />
    Die Einstellung "Maximale Schlüssellänge" bestimmt den größten Faktor (und damit auch die größte mögliche Schlüssellänge), den der Algorithmus bei der Untersuchung der Distanzen in Betracht ziehen soll.
    <newline /><newline />
    Außerdem können Sie angeben, wie unbekannte Zeichen in der Eingabe behandelt werden sollen. Unbekannte Zeichen sind alle Zeichen, die nicht Teil des Alphabets sind.
    Diese können entweder in der Eingabe belassen (und somit bei der Analyse berücksichtigt) werden, oder sie können vor der Analyse entfernt werden.
    <newline /><newline />
    Weiterhin können Sie angeben, ob die Groß-/Kleinschreibung der Buchstaben der Eingabe bei der Analyse eine Rolle spielen soll oder nicht.
    Als Voreinstellung ist angegeben, die Groß-/Kleinschreibung nicht zu beachten. Dadurch werden z.B. 'a' und 'A' als derselbe Buchstabe interpretiert.
  </usage>
  <presentation lang="en">
    In the presentation view of the component, you can see a histogram that displays the encountered factors.
    At the bottom of each bar appears the corresponding factor and the height of the bar symbolizes, how often that factor was encountered in the analysis.
  </presentation>
  <presentation lang="de-DE">
    In der Präsentationsansicht wird ein Histogramm dargestellt, das die Verteilung der festgestellten Faktoren anzeigt.
    An der Basis eines Balkens wird dabei der Faktor angegeben, und seine Höhe gibt die Häufigkeit des Auftretens an.
  </presentation>
  <references>
    <linkReference id="wikipedia">
      <link url="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Kasiski_examination" lang="en" />
      <caption lang="en">Kasiski's Test (Wikipedia)</caption>
      <link url="http://de.wikipedia.org/wiki/Kasiski-Test" lang="de-DE" />
      <caption lang="de-DE">Kasiski-Test (Wikipedia)</caption>
    </linkReference>
    <linkReference>
      <link url="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Vigen%C3%A8re_cipher" lang="en" />
      <caption lang="en">Vigenère in Wikipedia</caption>
      <link url="http://de.wikipedia.org/wiki/Vigen%C3%A8re-Chiffre" lang="de-DE" />
      <caption lang="de-DE">Vigenère in Wikipedia</caption>
    </linkReference>
  </references>
</documentation>