<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<documentation>
  <language culture="en" />
  <language culture="de-DE" />
  <introduction lang="en">
    HIGHT is a block cipher proposed by Deukjo Hong et al. which is working on a 64-bit block length and a 128-bit key length. It was proposed to be used at ubiquitous computing devices such as a sensor in ubiquitous sensor networks (USN) or a RFID tag at CHES ’06. The specialty of HIGHT is its use of simple operations such as exclusive-or, addition mod 2^8, and bitwise rotation. HIGHT is designed for being implemented in hardware to have a low cost of gates.
    <newline />
    The cipher is a variant of a generalized Feistel network. It consists of an initial transformation, 32 rounds using 4 subkeys at a time, a final transformation and a key schedule producing 128 subkeys. HIGHT's key schedule algorithm is designed to keep the original value of the master key after generating all whitening keys and all subkeys. Therefore the subkeys are generated on the fly for encryption and decryption.
    <newline /><img src="HIGHT/DetailedDescription/Images/HIGHT.png" /></introduction>
  <introduction lang="de-DE"></introduction>
  <usage lang="en">
    The use of this component is pretty straightforward.
  </usage>
  <usage lang="de-DE"></usage>
  <presentation lang="en"></presentation>
  <presentation lang="de-DE"></presentation>
  <references>
    <linkReference id="ietf">
      <link url="http://tools.ietf.org/html/draft-kisa-hight-00" lang="en" />
      <caption lang="en">The HIGHT Encryption Algorithm (IETF Draft)</caption>
      <link url="http://tools.ietf.org/html/draft-kisa-hight-00" lang="de-DE" />
      <caption lang="en">The HIGHT Encryption Algorithm (IETF Draft, englisch)</caption>
    </linkReference>
    <linkReference id="ietf">
      <link url="http://www.iacr.org/cryptodb/archive/2006/CHES/04/04.pdf" lang="en" />
      <caption lang="en">HIGHT: A New Block Cipher Suitable for Low-Resource Device (PDF)</caption>
      <link url="http://www.iacr.org/cryptodb/archive/2006/CHES/04/04.pdf" lang="de-DE" />
      <caption lang="en">HIGHT: A New Block Cipher Suitable for Low-Resource Device (PDF, englisch)</caption>
    </linkReference>
  </references>
</documentation>