<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!-- You can edit this file manually or with the Util/CrypDocumentationEditor -->
<documentation>
  <language culture="en" />
  <language culture="zh-CN" />
  <language culture="ru" />
  <language culture="de-DE" />
  <introduction lang="en">
    Slide attack on Feistel cipher is a cryptographic attack where a slid pair is used along with the known round function to extract the unknown key.
  </introduction>
  <introduction lang="zh-CN">Feistel密码上的滑动攻击是一种加密攻击，其中使用滑动对和已知的回合函数来提取未知密钥。</introduction>
  <introduction lang="ru">Атака слайдов на шифр Фейстеля - это криптографическая атака, в которой с помощью известной функции раунда используется скользящая пара для извлечения неизвестного ключа.</introduction>
  <introduction lang="de-DE"></introduction>
  <usage lang="en">
    The plugin for performing a slide attack on Feistel takes two
    inputs: the plain text and the corresponding ciphertext which together
    are called "slid pair" if they are one-round encrypted.
    The slid pair can be any alphanumeric character (within ASCII range).
    When the plugin is run with proper inputs, it generates the unknown key as output.
  </usage>
  <usage lang="zh-CN">用于对Feistel进行滑行攻击的插件需要两个输入：纯文本和相应的密文（如果它们是单次加密的，则一起称为“滑对”）。滑动对可以是任何字母数字字符（在ASCII范围内）。当插件以正确的输入运行时，它将生成未知密钥作为输出。</usage>
  <usage lang="ru">Плагин для выполнения слайд-атаки на Feistel принимает два входа: обычный текст и соответствующий зашифрованный текст, которые вместе называются «скользкой парой», если они шифруются одним раундом. Скользящая пара может быть любым буквенно-цифровым символом (в пределах диапазона ASCII). Когда плагин запускается с соответствующими входами, он генерирует неизвестный ключ в качестве вывода.</usage>
  <usage lang="de-DE"></usage>
  <presentation lang="en"></presentation>
  <presentation lang="de-DE"></presentation>
  <references>
    <bookReference>
      <author lang="en">David Wagner, Alex Biryukov</author>
      <name lang="en">Slide Attacks (1999)</name>
    </bookReference>
  </references>
</documentation>