<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<documentation>
  <language culture="en" />
  <language culture="zh-CN" />
  <language culture="ru" />
  <language culture="de-DE" />
  <introduction lang="en">
    This component can convert strings, that are formatted according to certain rules, to data streams and byte arrays.
  </introduction>
  <introduction lang="zh-CN">该组件可以将根据某些规则格式化的字符串转换为数据流和字节数组。</introduction>
  <introduction lang="ru">Этот компонент может преобразовывать строки, форматированные в соответствии с определенными правилами, в потоки данных и массивы байтов.</introduction>
  <introduction lang="de-DE">
    Diese Komponente kann Zeichenketten, die nach gewissen Regeln formatiert sind, in Datenströme und Byte-Arrays konvertieren.
  </introduction>
  <usage lang="en">
    In the settings of the component you can select the format of the given input string. Depending on the chosen format, different options will be available in the settings.
    <newline /><newline />
    If you choose the format <b>Text</b>, the input string will be interpreted as a UTF-8 encoded string.
    The string is then converted to a byte sequence, based on your selection in the settings for the output data encoding.
    The byte sequence is sent to the outputs of the component as a data stream and as a byte array.
    <newline /><newline /><b>Example:</b> If you enter the word <i>über</i> and select UTF-8 encoding for the output, the resulting byte sequence is <i>C3 BC 62 65 72</i>.
    If you choose ISO8859-15 as output encoding, the result is <i>FC 62 65 72</i>. The difference is caused by the different byte representations of the letter 'ü' in the two encodings.
    <newline /><newline />
    If you choose the format <b>Binary</b>, the input string must consist of the characters '0' and '1'. It is split into blocks of 8 characters, that are interpreted as bytes in binary notation.
    The output of the component consists of the resulting byte sequence. For improving the readibility, the input can be interspersed with separator characters. Check the appropriate checkbox in the settings to
    activate the separator characters. The default separators are the space character and the comma, but you can provide your own set of characters in the settings.
    <newline /><newline /><b>Example:</b> The input <i>1000000001000001</i> will produce the byte sequence <i>80 41</i>. If separator characters are used, <i>10000000 01000001</i> will generate the same byte sequence,
    but the input <i>100000 0001000 001</i> will generate <i>20 08 01</i>.
    So be aware that the position of the separator characters can change the interpretation of the input.
    <newline /><newline />
    Apart from the character sets that the input may consist of, the options <b>Octal</b>, <b>Decimal</b> and <b>Hexadecimal</b> work in the same way as the option <b>Binary</b>.
    <b>Octal</b> accepts only inputs consisting of the digits '0' to '7', <b>Decimal</b> accepts the digits '0' to '9', and <b>Hexadecimal</b> accepts '0' to '9' and 'A' to 'F'.
    <newline /><newline />
    If you choose the format <b>Base64</b>, the input has to be a string in Base64 format. The component decodes the input and sends the resulting byte sequence to the output.
    If the input string is not in Base64 format, an error message will be issued and the execution is halted.
    <newline /><newline /><b>Example:</b> The input <i>Q3J5cFRbb2w=</i> will produce the byte sequence <i>43 72 79 70 54 6F 6F 6C</i>. This is the numeric ASCII representation of the word "CrypTool".
  </usage>
  <usage lang="zh-CN">在组件的设置中，您可以选择给定输入字符串的格式。根据选择的格式，设置中将提供不同的选项。如果选择“文本”格式，则输入字符串将被解释为UTF-8编码的字符串。然后根据您在输出数据编码设置中的选择，将字符串转换为字节序列。字节序列作为数据流和字节数组发送到组件的输出。示例：如果输入单词über并为输出选择UTF-8编码，则结果字节序列为C3 BC 62 6572。如果选择ISO8859-15作为输出编码，则结果为FC 62 65 72。由两种编码中字母“ü”的不同字节表示引起的。如果选择二进制格式，则输入字符串必须由字符“ 0”和“ 1”组成。它分为8个字符的块，以二进制表示形式解释为字节。组件的输出由结果字节序列组成。为了提高可读性，可以在输入中插入分隔符。选中设置中的相应复选框以激活分隔符。默认的分隔符是空格字符和逗号，但是您可以在设置中提供自己的字符集。示例：输入1000000001000001将生成字节序列8041。如果使用分隔符，则10000000 01000001将生成相同的字节序列，但是输入100000 0001000 001将生成20 0801。因此请注意，分隔符的位置可以更改输入的解释。除了输入可能包含的字符集之外，八进制，十进制和十六进制选项的工作方式与二进制选项相同。八进制仅接受由数字“ 0”至“ 7”组成的输入，十进制接受数字“ 0”至“ 9”，而十六进制接受“ 0”至“ 9”和“ A”至“ F”。如果选择格式Base64，则输入必须是Base64格式的字符串。该组件对输入进行解码，并将结果字节序列发送到输出。如果输入的字符串不是Base64格式，将发出错误消息，并中止执行。示例：输入Q3J5cFRbb2w =将产生字节序列43 72 79 70 54 6F 6F 6C。这是单词“ CrypTool”的数字ASCII表示形式。</usage>
  <usage lang="ru">В настройках компонента вы можете выбрать формат данной входной строки. В зависимости от выбранного формата в настройках будут доступны разные параметры. Если вы выберете формат Text, строка ввода будет интерпретирована как кодированная строка UTF-8. Затем строка преобразуется в последовательность байтов, основываясь на вашем выборе в настройках для кодирования выходных данных. Последовательность байтов отправляется на выходы компонента как поток данных и как массив байтов. Пример. Если вы вводите слово über и выбираете кодировку UTF-8 для выхода, результирующая последовательность байтов - C3 BC 62 65 72. Если вы выберете ISO8859-15 в качестве выходного кодирования, результатом будет FC 62 65 72. Разница заключается в том, вызванных различными байтовыми представлениями буквы «ü» в двух кодировках. Если вы выберете формат Binary, входная строка должна состоять из символов «0» и «1». Он разбивается на блоки из 8 символов, которые интерпретируются как байты в двоичной нотации. Вывод компонента состоит из полученной последовательности байтов. Для улучшения читаемости ввод может быть чередован с символами разделителя. Установите соответствующий флажок в настройках, чтобы активировать символы разделителя. По умолчанию разделители являются символом пробела и запятой, но вы можете предоставить свой собственный набор символов в настройках. Пример: вход 1000000001000001 будет генерировать последовательность байтов 80 41. Если используются символы разделителя, 10000000 01000001 будет генерировать одну и ту же последовательность байтов, но вход 100000 0001000 001 будет генерировать 20 08 01. Поэтому имейте в виду, что положение разделительных символов может изменить интерпретацию ввода. Помимо наборов символов, которые может содержать вход, параметры Octal, Decimal и Hexadecimal работают так же, как опция Binary. Octal принимает только входы, состоящие из цифр от 0 &amp;#39;до&amp;#39; 7 &amp;#39;, Decimal принимает цифры от 0&amp;#39; до &amp;#39;9&amp;#39;, а шестнадцатеричный принимает &amp;#39;0&amp;#39; до &amp;#39;9&amp;#39; и &amp;#39;А&amp;#39; до &amp;#39;F&amp;#39;. Если вы выберете формат Base64, вход должен быть строкой в ​​формате Base64. Компонент декодирует вход и отправляет полученную последовательность байтов на выход. Если входная строка не в формате Base64, будет выдано сообщение об ошибке, и выполнение будет остановлено. Пример: вход Q3J5cFRbb2w = будет генерировать последовательность байтов 43 72 79 70 54 6F 6F 6C. Это числовое ASCII-представление слова «CrypTool».</usage>
  <usage lang="de-DE">
    Wählen Sie in den Einstellungen der Komponente, in welchem Format die Eingabe vorliegt. Abhängig vom gewählten Format werden unterschiedliche
    Optionen in den Einstellungen angezeigt.
    <newline /><newline />
    Wird die Option <b>Text</b> gewählt, so wird die Eingabe als Zeichenkette in UTF-8-Kodierung interpretiert.
    Die Zeichenkette wird dann, basierend auf der in den Einstellungen gewählten Zeichenkodierung, in eine Bytesequenz konvertiert.
    Diese wird an den Ausgängen der Komponente als Byte-Array und als Datenstrom ausgegeben.
    <newline /><newline /><b>Beispiel:</b> Wird als Eingabe das Wort <i>Tür</i> angegeben und UTF-8 als Zeichenkodierung der Ausgabe gewählt, so ist das Ergebnis die Bytesequenz <i>54 C3 BC 72</i>. 
    Wird als Zeichenkodierung ISO8859-15 gewählt, so ist die resultierende Bytesequenz <i>54 FC 72</i>.
    Der Unterschied kommt durch die verschiedene Repräsentation des Buchstabens 'ü' in den beiden Kodierungen zustande.
    <newline /><newline />
    Wird die Option <b>Binär</b> gewählt, so wird als Eingabe eine Zeichenkette erwartet, die nur aus '0' und '1' besteht. Diese wird in Blöcke von 8 Zeichen zerlegt, die jeweils als ein Byte in Binärdarstellung interpretiert werden.
    Die Ausgabe besteht dann aus der so entstandenen Bytesequenz. Die Eingabe kann zur besseren Lesbarkeit auch mit Trennzeichen formatiert werden. Aktivieren Sie dazu in den Einstellungen das zugehörige Kontrollkästchen.
    Die Trennzeichen, die zur Formatierung verwendet werden dürfen, können ebenfalls angegeben werden. Voreingestellt sind das Leerzeichen und das Komma.
    <newline /><newline /><b>Beispiel:</b> Die Eingabe <i>1000000001000001</i> erzeugt die Bytesequenz <i>80 41</i>. Bei Verwendung von Trennzeichen erzeugt <i>10000000 01000001</i> dieselbe Bytesequenz, aber die Eingabe <i>100000 0001000 001</i> erzeugt <i>20 08 01</i>.
    Die Position der Trennzeichen kann die Interpretation der Eingabe also verändern.
    <newline /><newline />
    Für die Optionen <b>Oktal</b>, <b>Dezimal</b> und <b>Hexadezimal</b> gilt, abgesehen von dem Zeichenvorrat, aus dem die Eingabe bestehen darf, dasselbe wie für die Option <b>Binär</b>. 
    Bei <b>Oktal</b> darf die Eingabe aus den Ziffern '0' bis '7' bestehen, bei <b>Dezimal</b> aus den Ziffern '0' bis '9', und bei <b>Hexadezimal</b> aus den Zeichen '0' bis '9' und 'A' bis 'F'.
    <newline /><newline />
    Wird die Option <b>Base64</b> gewählt, so wird als Eingabe eine Zeichenkette im Base-64-Format erwartet. Die Komponente dekodiert die Eingabe und gibt die resultierende Bytesequenz aus.
    Ist die Eingabe nicht im Base-64-Format, so wird eine Fehlermeldung ausgegeben und die Ausführung beendet.
    <newline /><newline /><b>Beispiel:</b> Die Eingabe <i>Q3J5cFRbb2w=</i> erzeugt die Bytesequenz <i>43 72 79 70 54 6F 6F 6C</i>. Dies ist die numerische ASCII-Darstellung des Wortes "CrypTool".
  </usage>
  <presentation lang="en"></presentation>
  <presentation lang="de-DE"></presentation>
  <references>
    <linkReference>
      <link lang="en" url="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Character_encoding" />
      <caption lang="en">Character encoding</caption>
      <link lang="de-DE" url="http://de.wikipedia.org/wiki/Zeichenkodierung" />
      <caption lang="de-DE">Zeichenkodierung</caption>
    </linkReference>
    <linkReference>
      <link lang="en" url="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Binary_numeral_system" />
      <caption lang="en">Binary numeral system</caption>
      <link lang="de-DE" url="http://de.wikipedia.org/wiki/Dualsystem" />
      <caption lang="de-DE">Dualsystem (Binärsystem)</caption>
    </linkReference>
    <linkReference>
      <link lang="en" url="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Octal" />
      <caption lang="en">Octal</caption>
      <link lang="de-DE" url="http://de.wikipedia.org/wiki/Oktalsystem" />
      <caption lang="de-DE">Oktalsystem</caption>
    </linkReference>
    <linkReference>
      <link lang="en" url="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Decimal" />
      <caption lang="en">Decimal</caption>
      <link lang="de-DE" url="http://de.wikipedia.org/wiki/Dezimalsystem" />
      <caption lang="de-DE">Dezimalsystem</caption>
    </linkReference>
    <linkReference>
      <link lang="en" url="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Hexadecimal" />
      <caption lang="en">Hexadecimal</caption>
      <link lang="de-DE" url="http://de.wikipedia.org/wiki/Hexadezimalsystem" />
      <caption lang="de-DE">Hexadezimalsystem</caption>
    </linkReference>
    <linkReference>
      <link lang="en" url="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Base64" />
      <caption lang="en">Base64</caption>
      <link lang="de-DE" url="http://de.wikipedia.org/wiki/Base64" />
      <caption lang="de-DE">Base64</caption>
    </linkReference>
  </references>
</documentation>