<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!-- You can edit this file manually or with the Util/CrypDocumentationEditor -->
<documentation>
  <language culture="en" />
  <language culture="zh-CN" />
  <language culture="ru" />
  <language culture="de-DE" />
  <introduction lang="en">
    Feistel cipher (also commonly known as a Feistel network) is a symmetric structure used in the construction of block ciphers.
    The Feistel structure has the advantage that encryption and decryption operations are very similar, even identical in some cases, requiring only a reversal of the key schedule.
    Therefore, the size of the code or circuitry required to implement such a cipher is nearly halved.
    A Feistel network is an iterated cipher with an internal function called the Round function which operates on half of the input and a key.
  </introduction>
  <introduction lang="zh-CN">Feistel密码（也称为Feistel网络）是一种在构造分组密码时使用的对称结构。 Feistel结构的优点是加密和解密操作非常相似，甚至在某些情况下甚至是相同的，只需要逆转密钥计划即可。因此，实现这种密码所需的代码或电路的大小几乎减少了一半。 Feistel网络是一种迭代密码，其内部函数称为Round函数，该函数对输入和密钥的一半进行操作。</introduction>
  <introduction lang="ru">Фейстельный шифр (также известный как сеть Фейстеля) представляет собой симметричную структуру, используемую при построении блочных шифров. Структура Feistel имеет то преимущество, что операции шифрования и дешифрования очень схожи, даже в некоторых случаях идентичны, требуя только отмены ключевого расписания. Поэтому размер кода или схемы, необходимых для реализации такого шифрования, почти вдвое меньше. Сеть Feistel представляет собой итерированный шифр с внутренней функцией, называемой функцией Round, которая работает на половине входа и ключа.</introduction>
  <introduction lang="de-DE"></introduction>
  <usage lang="en">
    The plugin for Feistel cipher is fairly simple to use. It takes three inputs; the plain text, the key and an integer value for number of rounds.
    After providing the necessary inputs and running the plugin, the output is the cipher text produced by the Feistel network.
  </usage>
  <usage lang="zh-CN">Feistel cipher的插件使用起来非常简单。它需要三个输入；纯文本，键和回合数的整数值。提供必要的输入并运行插件后，输出就是Feistel网络产生的密文。</usage>
  <usage lang="ru">Плагин для шифрования Feistel довольно прост в использовании. Он принимает три входа; простой текст, ключ и целочисленное значение для числа раундов. После предоставления необходимых входов и запуска плагина, выход представляет собой шифрованный текст, созданный сетью Feistel.</usage>
  <usage lang="de-DE"></usage>
  <presentation lang="en"></presentation>
  <presentation lang="de-DE"></presentation>
  <references></references>
</documentation>