<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<documentation>
  <language culture="en" />
  <language culture="de-DE" />
  <introduction lang="en">
    Decimalization is the process of creating a decimal number from a binary number. Furthermore certain characteristics of the 
    binary data should be transferred to the decimal, e.g. a uniform distribution of the digits and unpredictability of the digits. This plugin realizes
    different decimalization processes within the CrypTool 2 environment.
  </introduction>
  <usage lang="en">
    The form of the input data is a byte array. The output formats are a string and an integer array.
    Each field of the integer array contains a digit of the output decimal.
    The decimalication process and the number of decimal output digits can be adjusted in the configuration panel.  
    If there is not enough binary input data to generate a decimal with a certain amount of digits, the CrypTool 2
    environment gets a message from the plugin.
  </usage>
  <presentation lang="en">
    The plugin offers the following decimalization methods:
    <newline /><newline /><b>(1) Visa</b><newline />
    The first step of the Visa method is the conversion of the binary input to a sequence of hexadecimals.
    After this conversion each digit of the sequence is considered from left to right and if it is below A it will
    be appended to the output until the required number of output digits is reached.
    If there are too few hexadecimal digits below A, the sequence of hexadecimals is treated another time. This time all digits 
    above or equal A are considered. The value of the digit will be subtracted by A and it gets appended to the output until 
    the claimed nummber of decimal digits is reached. This step only creates digits between 0 and 5. <newline />
    If the binary input is too short to create the requested amount of decimal 
    digits a warning will be sent to the CrypTool 2 environment.<newline />
    A variant of the Visa method is the modified Visa method. If the binary input is too short another binary input is requested
    to get the required amount of decimals. This decimalization method is not implemented yet.
    <newline /><newline /><u>Example</u><newline /><newline />
    Binary Number: 1011 1001 0100 0101 1111 1010<newline />
    Hexadecimal: B945FA<newline />
    Decimal: 9451<newline /><newline />
    This example of the Visa method creates a decimal with 4 digits from the given binary data.
    The first step consists of the transformation of the binary data into a hexadecimal. This process is done from left
    to right and 4 bits yield a hexadecimal digit. The result of the transformation is B945FA.
    Starting with the most left hexadecimal digit, each hexadecimal digit of the sequence, which has a value below A, is considered
    for the decimal. The following number is created: 945. Due to a lack of enough hexadecimal digits, which 
    have a value below A, the intermediate decimal has only 3 instead of 4 digits. Now, the hexadecimal digits, which are
    above or equal A, are considered to get the last decimal digit. Thus, the digit B is choosen, it is reduced by A, and it is appended
    to the decimal. The result is the decimal 9451.
    <newline /><newline /><b>(2) IBM</b><newline />
    The IBM method is similar to the Visa method. The binary input is converted to a sequence of hexadecimals.
    Starting from the beginning of the sequence each digit will be added to the output until the claimed number of
    decimal digits is reached. If the value of a hexadecimal digit is above or equal A it will be mapped to a digit in the 
    range from 0 to 9. This mapping is done according to a table. This table can be adjusted within the configuration panel 
    of the plugin. <newline />
    The plugin sends a warning to the CrypTool 2 environment if the binary input is too short to realize the 
    requested number of decimal numbers.
    <newline /><newline /><u>Example</u><newline /><newline />
    Binary Number: 1011 1001 0100 0101 1111 1010<newline />
    Hexadecimal: B945FA<newline />
    Decimal: 1945<newline /><newline />
    This example of the IBM method creates a decimal with 4 digits from the given binary data.
    The first step consists of the transformation of the binary data into a hexadecimal. This process is done from left
    to right and 4 bits yield a hexadecimal digit. The result of the transformation is B945FA. Starting with the most left 
    hexadecimal digit, each hexadecimal digit of the sequence is considered for the decimal. The first 4 
    hexadecimal digits yield the decimal. All hexadecimal digits above
    or equal A are mapped on a digit below A. In this case the mapping is A to 0, B to 1, C to 2, D to 3, E to 4, and F to 5.
    The result is the decimal 1945.
    <newline /><newline /><b>(3) Modulo</b><newline />
    The modulo method considers the binary input as positive integer. This number will be reduced modulo 10^k, where k 
    represents the requested number of decimal digits. The result of the calculation is the output. <newline />
    The plugin sends an error notification to the CrypTool 2 environment if the binary input or an intermediate result
    exceeds the range of the used BigInteger implementation. If the binary input is too short to realize the
    requested number of decimal numbers a warning notification is sent.
    <newline /><newline /><u>Example</u><newline /><newline />
    Binary Number: 1011 1001 0100 0101 1111 1010<newline />
    Integer: 12142074<newline />
    Decimal: 2074<newline /><newline />
    This example of the modulo method creates a decimal with 4 digits from the given binary data.
    The binary input is considered as positive integer 12142074. The reduction of the integer by 10^4 yields 2074.
    Therefore the result is 2074.
    <newline /><newline /><b>(4) Multiplication</b><newline />
    The multiplication method considers the binary input as positive integer. This number is divided by 2^n, where n represents
    the number of bits of the binary input. The result is then multiplied by 10^k, where k represents the requested number
    of decimal digits. The rounded down result is the decimal output.
    The plugin sends an error notification to the CrypTool 2 environment if the binary input or an intermediate result
    exceeds the range of the used BigInteger implementation.
    <newline /><newline /><u>Example</u><newline /><newline />
    Binary Number: 1011 1001 0100 0101 1111 1010<newline />
    Integer: 12142074<newline />
    Decimal: 7237<newline /><newline />
    This example of the multiplication method creates a decimal with 4 digits from the given binary data.
    The binary input is considered as positive integer 12142074. This integer is divided by 2^24. The quotient
    is multiplied by 10^4 and adjusted downward. Thus, the result is 7237.
    <newline /><newline /><newline /><b>Quality of Decimalization Methods</b><newline />
    The quality of the decimalization methods is measured by the deviation from a uniform distribution of the decimals.
    A condition is that the binary input is uniform distributed. Therefore, an ideal decimalization method would create
    all decimals of k-arity with the same probability.<newline />
    On that note the quality of the IBM method is low because decimals with mapped digits have a higher probability.
    The same conclusion can be made for the Visa method if there is only a short amount of binary input. However,
    if the amount of binary input is big enough, no hexadecimal digits are mapped. Therefore, no decimal digit has a
    higher probability than another one and the Visa method achieves a high quality. <newline />
    Furthermore the modulo and the multiplication method have a high quality. <newline />
    A detailed evaluation of the quality of the single decimalization methods can be found in the referenced paper.<ref id="Dec" /></presentation>
  <introduction lang="de-DE">
    Der Prozess der Dezimalisierung erstellt Dezimalzahlen aus binären Zahlen. Dabei sollen gewisse Eigenschaften, 
    beispielsweise eine Gleichverteilung oder die Nichtvorhersagbarkeit der Ziffern, von der binären Zahl auf 
    die Dezimalzahl übertragen werden. Dieses Plugin ermöglicht den Einsatz verschiedener Verfahren der Dezimalisierung 
    innerhalb der CrypTool 2-Umgebung.
  </introduction>
  <usage lang="de-DE">
    Das Dezimalisierungs-Plugin nimmt die binären Eingabedaten in Form eines Byte-Arrays entgegen. Als Ausgabeformate stehen einerseits 
    ein String mit der Dezimalzahl und andererseits ein Integer-Array zur Verfügung. Die einzelnen Felder des Integer-Arrays 
    enthalten die Ziffern der erstellten Dezimalzahl. Im Einstellungspanel lässt sich die Anzahl der Ziffern der zu 
    erstellenden Dezimalzahl sowie das zu verwendende Dezimalisierungsverfahren einstellen. Stehen nicht genügend Binärdaten 
    als Eingabe des Plugins für die Größe der Dezimalzahl zur Verfügung, wird eine Warnung ausgegeben.
  </usage>
  <presentation lang="de-DE">
    Die folgenden vier Verfahren können zur Dezimalisierung von Binärzahlen verwendet werden:
    <newline /><newline /><b>(1) Visa</b><newline />
    Bei dem Visa-Verfahren werden im ersten Schritt die binären Eingabedaten in hexadezimale Ziffern überführt. 
    Nach dieser Konvertierung werden der Reihe nach Ziffern, die kleiner als A sind, aus der Folge der hexadezimalen 
    Ziffern ausgewählt und nacheinandner als Ziffern der Dezimalzahl übernommen. Besitzt die Dezimalzahl nach diesem Schritt noch
    nicht die gewünschte Anzahl von Ziffern, wird die hexadezimale Zahlenfolge ein weiteres Mal der Reihe nach und
    von vorne beginnend betrachtet. Diesmal werden nur Ziffern, die einen Wert größer gleich A haben ausgewählt, um
    den Wert A verringert und an das Ende der Dezimalzahl übernommen. In diesem zweiten Schritt können nur die Ziffern
    0 bis 5 erzeugt werden. <newline />
    Liefern die binären Eingabedaten eine zu kleine 
    hexadezimale Ziffernfolge für die gewünschte Anzahl von dezimalen Ziffern, wird der CrypTool 2-Umgebung eine Warnung<newline />
    Eine Variante des Visa-Verfahrens ist das modifizierte Visa-Verfahren. Diese Methode erfordert eine weitere Menge
    binärer Eingabedaten falls die ersten Binärdaten nicht genügend hexadezimale Ziffern kleiner A liefern. Das modifzierte
    Visa-Verfahren wurde noch nicht implementiert.
    gesendet.
    <newline /><newline /><u>Beispiel</u><newline /><newline />
    Binärzahl: 1011 1001 0100 0101 1111 1010 <newline />
    Hexadezimalzahl: B945FA <newline />
    Dezimalzahl: 9451 <newline /><newline />
    In diesem Beispiel zum Visa-Verfahren soll aus der gegebenen Binärzahl eine 4-stellige Dezimalzahl erstellt werden.
    Dazu werden im ersten Schritt von links nach rechts jeweils 4 Bits der Binärzahl in eine hexadezimale Ziffer umgewandelt.
    Das Ergebnis lautet B945FA. Nun werden von der hexadezimalen Zahl von links nach rechts Ziffern, die einen Wert kleiner als
    A haben, ausgewählt. Es entsteht folgende Dezimalzahl: 945. Da die Dezimalzahl bis jetzt nur 3 anstatt 4 Ziffern aufweist und
    die hexadezimale Zahl keine weiteren Ziffern kleiner A besitzt, werden nun die Ziffern größer gleich A der 
    hexadezimalen Zahl von links nach rechts betrachtet. Dadurch wird die Ziffer B um A reduziert und an die bisherige 
    Dezimalzahl angefügt. Die Dezimalzahl 9451 ist das Ergebnis.
    <newline /><newline /><b>(2) IBM</b><newline />
    Das IBM-Verfahren ähnelt dem Visa-Verfahren. Die binären Eingabedaten werden in eine hexadezimale Ziffernfolge konvertiert.
    Aus der Ziffernfolge werden von vorne beginnend und der Reihe nach Ziffern in die zu erstellende Dezimalzahl übernommen.
    Ist der Wert der hexadezimalen Ziffer größer gleich A, wird anhand einer Tabelle dieser Wert in einen Wert kleiner A
    überführt. Diese Abbildungstabelle lässt sich im Einstellungspanel des Plugins bearbeiten. <newline />
    Liefern die binären Eingabedaten 
    eine zu kleine hexadezimale Ziffernfolge für die gewünschte Anzahl von dezimalen Ziffern, wird der CrypTool 2-Umgebung 
    eine Warnung gesendet.
    <newline /><newline /><u>Beispiel</u><newline /><newline />
    Binärzahl: 1011 1001 0100 0101 1111 1010 <newline />
    Hexadezimalzahl: B945FA <newline />
    Dezimalzahl: 1945 <newline /><newline />
    In diesem Beispiel zum IBM-Verfahren soll aus der gegebenen Binärzahl eine 4-stellige Dezimalzahl erstellt werden.
    Dazu werden im ersten Schritt von links nach rechts jeweils 4 Bits der Binärzahl in eine hexadezimale Ziffer umgewandelt.
    Das Ergebnis lautet B945FA. Die ersten 4 Ziffern der hexadezimalen Zahl ergeben die gesuchte 4-stellige Dezimalzahl. 
    Dabei werden die hexadezimalen Ziffern A auf 0, B auf 1, C auf 2, D auf 3, E auf 4 und F auf 5 abgebildet. Das Ergebnis
    der Dezimalisierung is 1945.
    <newline /><newline /><b>(3) Modulo</b><newline />
    Das Modulo-Verfahren betrachtet die binären Eingabedaten als positive Ganzzahl. Diese Zahl wird Modulo 10^k gerechnet, wobei
    k die Anzahl der gewünschten Ziffern der Dezimalzahl repräsentiert. Das Ergebnis dieser Berechnung wird 
    als Dezimalzahl ausgegeben. <newline /> 
    Überschreiten die binären Eingabedaten den Wertebereich der genutzten BigInteger Implementierung
    oder wird während einer Berechnung dieser Wertebereich überschritten, wird der CrypTool 2-Umgebung eine Fehlermeldung gesendet.
    Bei unzureichender Größe des binären Inputs für die gewünschte Anzahl dezimaler Ziffern wird eine Warnung ausgegeben.
    <newline /><newline /><u>Beispiel</u><newline /><newline />
    Binärzahl: 1011 1001 0100 0101 1111 1010 <newline />
    Ganzzahl: 12142074 <newline />
    Dezimalzahl: 2074 <newline /><newline />
    In diesem Beispiel zum Modulo-Verfahren soll aus der gegebenen Binärzahl eine 4-stellige Dezimalzahl erstellt werden.
    Die binären Eingabedaten werden als ganze Zahl 12142074 aufgefasst. Danach wird 12142074 Modulo 10^4 gerechnet. Als
    Ergebnis erhält man die Dezimalzahl 2074.
    <newline /><newline /><b>(4) Multiplikation</b><newline />
    Das Multiplikationsverfahren betrachtet die binären Eingabedaten als positive Ganzzahl. Diese Zahl wird durch 2^n dividiert, 
    wobei n die Größe der Eingabedaten in Bits repräsentiert. Anschließend wird das Ergebnis dieser Berechnung mit 10^k multipliziert,
    wobei k die Anzahl der Ziffern der gewünschten Dezimalzahl darstellt. Das abgerundetete Resultat wird als
    Dezimalzahl ausgegeben. <newline />
    Überschreiten die binären Eingabedaten den Wertebereich der genutzten BigInteger Implementierung
    oder wird während einer Berechnung dieser Wertebereich überschritten, wird der CrypTool 2-Umgebung eine Fehlermeldung gesendet.
    <newline /><newline /><u>Beispiel</u><newline /><newline />
    Binärzahl: 1011 1001 0100 0101 1111 1010 <newline />
    Ganzzahl: 12142074 <newline />
    Dezimalzahl: 7237 <newline /><newline />
    In diesem Beispiel zum Modulo-Verfahren soll aus der gegebenen Binärzahl eine 4-stellige Dezimalzahl erstellt werden.
    Die binären Eingabedaten werden als ganze Zahl 12142074 aufgefasst. Anschließend wird 12142074 durch 2^24 geteilt.
    Der Quotient wird mit 10^4 multipliziert und abgerundet. Als Ergebnis erhält man die Dezimalzahl 7237.
    <newline /><newline /><newline /><b>Qualität der Dezimalisierungsverfahren</b><newline />
    Die Qualität der Dezimalisierungsverfahren soll durch den Grad der Gleichverteilung der Dezimalzahlen, ausgehend von der 
    Annahme, dass die binären Eingabedaten gleichverteilt sind, bestimmt werden. Bei einer idealen Methode zur Dezimalisierung
    von Binärdaten wären alle k-stelligen Dezimalzahlen gleich wahrscheinlich. <newline />
    In diesem Sinne hat das IBM-Verfahren eine geringe Qualität, da Dezimalzahlen mit Ziffern auf die, die hexadezimalen Ziffern
    A - F abgebildet werden, eine höhere Wahrscheinlichkeit haben. Diesselbe Schlussfolgerung trifft auf das Visa-Verfahren zu,
    falls eine geringe Menge an binären Eingabedaten zur Verfügung steht. Ist dagegen die Menge der binären Eingabedaten
    groß genug, muss keine hexadezimale Ziffer aus dem Bereich A - F in den Bereich 0 - 9 abgebildet werden. Dadurch tritt keine
    dezimale Ziffer mit einer höheren Wahrscheinlichkeit auf und das Visa-Verfahren erreicht eine hohe Qualität. <newline />
    Des Weiteren weisen das Modulo- und das Multiplikationsverfahren eine hohe Qualität auf. <newline />
    Eine genaue Betrachtung der Wahrscheinlichkeiten und der einzelnen Verfahren zur Dezimalisierung befindet sich in der
	 Ausarbeitung auf das im Abschnitt <b>Referenzen</b> verwiesen wird.<ref id="Dec" /></presentation>
  <references lang="de-DE">
    <linkReference id="Dec">
      <caption lang="de-DE">Koy, H./ Blank, M.: Qualität von Dezimalisierungsverfahren. Januar 2010.</caption>
      <caption lang="en">Koy, H./ Blank, M.: Qualität von Dezimalisierungsverfahren (Quality of Decimalization Methods). Januar 2010.</caption>
    </linkReference>
  </references>
</documentation>