<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<documentation>
  <language culture="en" />
  <language culture="zh-CN" />
  <language culture="ru" />
  <language culture="de-DE" />
  <introduction lang="en">    
  
    Grain v1 is a symmetric stream cipher which is based on two shift registers and a non-linear output function. 
    The key size is 80 bits and the size of the initialization vector is 64 bits.
    According to the attack, we need to set the internal state of the LFSR in the final clock to zero state and then select NFSR randomly.
    Then in reverse we compute the keystream, LFSR, NFSR.
    Attack terminates if the LFSR bits in positions 64 to 79 are 1.
    The same attack algorithm is applied to Grain v0 cipher as well; the difference between these two ciphers is in the terms of the variables
    in equations that define the NFSR and the filter function (the function that defines the LFSR is the same for both of the ciphers).
  
  </introduction>
  <introduction lang="zh-CN">粒度v1是基于两个移位寄存器和非线性输出函数的对称流密码。密钥大小为80位，初始化向量的大小为64位。根据攻击，我们需要将最终时钟中的LFSR的内部状态设置为零状态，然后随机选择NFSR。然后相反地，我们计算密钥流LFSR，NFSR。如果位置64到79的LFSR位为1，则攻击终止。这两个密码的区别在于定义NFSR和滤波器函数的方程式中的变量（两个密码的定义LFSR的函数相同）。</introduction>
  <introduction lang="ru">Grain v1 - симметричный потоковый шифр, основанный на двух регистрах сдвига и нелинейной выходной функции. Размер ключа - 80 бит, а размер вектора инициализации - 64 бита. Согласно атаке, нам нужно установить внутреннее состояние LFSR в последние часы на нулевое состояние, а затем выбрать NFSR случайным образом. Затем в обратном порядке мы вычисляем ключевой поток, LFSR, NFSR. Атака прекращается, если бит LFSR в положениях с 64 по 79 равен 1. Тот же алгоритм атаки применяется к шифру Grain v0; разница между этими двумя шифрами заключается в терминах переменных в уравнениях, которые определяют NFSR и функцию фильтра (функция, которая определяет LFSR, одинакова для обоих шифров).</introduction>
  <introduction lang="de-DE"></introduction>
  <usage lang="en">
    After dragging the GrainV1Attack component onto your workspace, you will have to attach a "Random Generator" to data sources, which is used to
    generate the NFSR in the final clocking randomly. 
    
    Then you have to connect three text output components to the 'Output' connectors, which correspond to: the LFSR at the initial state, 
    NFSR at the initial state, and NFSR in the 160th clocking.
    NFSR bits in the output component indicate the secret key.
    LFSR bits from positions 0 to 63 in the output component indicate the IV.

  </usage>
  <usage lang="zh-CN">将GrainV1Attack组件拖到您的工作区后，您将必须在数据源上附加一个“随机生成器”，用于在最终时钟中随机生成NFSR。然后，您必须将三个文本输出组件连接到“输出”连接器，它们分别对应于：初始状态的LFSR，初始状态的NFSR和第160个时钟的NFSR。输出组件中的NFSR位指示密钥。输出组件中位置0至63的LFSR位指示IV。</usage>
  <usage lang="ru">После перетаскивания компонента GrainV1Attack на ваше рабочее пространство вам нужно будет подключить «Random Generator» к источникам данных, который используется для генерации NFSR в конечном такте в случайном порядке. Затем вам нужно подключить три текстовых выходных компонента к разъемам «Выход», которые соответствуют: LFSR в начальном состоянии, NFSR в исходном состоянии и NFSR в 160-м такте. Биты NFSR в выходном компоненте указывают секретный ключ. Биты LFSR от позиций 0 до 63 в выходном компоненте указывают на IV.</usage>
  <usage lang="de-DE"></usage>
  <presentation lang="en"></presentation>
  <presentation lang="de-DE"></presentation>
  <references>
    <linkReference>
      <link url="https://eprint.iacr.org/2009/109.pdf" lang="en" />
      <caption lang="en">Cryptanalysis of Stream Cipher Grain Family</caption>
    </linkReference>
  </references>
</documentation>