<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<documentation>
  <language culture="en" />
  <language culture="zh-CN" />
  <language culture="ru" />
  <language culture="de-DE" />
  <introduction lang="en">
    The StringOperations offer the possibility to manipulate strings.
    By using the StringOperations a string may be converted to a lower-case or to an upper-case one. The user can separate substrings from
    a string or merge (concatenate) different strings. StringOperations may also be used to calculate the length of a given string.
    The position of a substring may be calculated. Parts of a string may be replaced by another string (using a regex is supported).
    The input string can be split into substrings using a separator string.
    The user can check if two strings are equal and reverse the string.
  </introduction>
  <introduction lang="zh-CN">StringOperations提供了操作字符串的可能性。通过使用StringOperations，可以将字符串转换为小写或大写。用户可以从字符串中分离子字符串，也可以合并（连接）不同的字符串。 StringOperations也可以用于计算给定字符串的长度。可以计算子串的位置。字符串的一部分可以被另一个字符串替换（支持使用正则表达式）。可以使用分隔符字符串将输入字符串拆分为子字符串。用户可以检查两个字符串是否相等，然后反转该字符串。</introduction>
  <introduction lang="ru">StringOperations предлагает возможность манипулировать строками. Используя StringOperations, строка может быть преобразована в нижний регистр или в верхний регистр. Пользователь может отделить подстроки от строки или объединить (объединить) разные строки. StringOperations также может использоваться для вычисления длины данной строки. Позиция подстроки может быть рассчитана. Части строки могут быть заменены другой строкой (поддерживается регулярное выражение). Входную строку можно разбить на подстроки с использованием строки разделителя. Пользователь может проверить, равны ли две строки и изменить строку.</introduction>
  <introduction lang="de-DE">
    Die Zeichenketten-Operationen ermöglichen das Manipulieren von Zeichenketten (Strings).
    So können mit Hilfe der Operationen Zeichenketten in ihrer Groß- oder Kleinschreibung verändert werden. Es können
    einzelne Teile entnommen werden oder mehrere Zeichenketten als eine zusammengefasst werden (Konkatenation). Außerdem
    ermöglichen die Zeichenketten-Operationen die Bestimmung der Länge einer übergebenen Zeichenkette. Es kann der Index, also
    die Position, einer Zeichenkette innerhalb einer anderen bestimmt werden. Teile einer Zeichenkette können durch eine weitere
    Zeichenkette ersetzt werden (auch mittels eines regulären Ausdrucks). Zeichenketten können mittels eines Trennstrings in Teilstrings zerlegt werden.
    Außerdem kann man überprüfen, ob zwei übergebene Zeichenketten identisch sind, und die Zeichenkette umkehren.
  </introduction>
  <usage lang="en">
    The StringOperations has two text inputs and two number inputs. Depending on the used function these inputs have different usage.
    It has also a text output, a text array output and a number output.
    <enum><item><b>Concatenate:</b> Needs only the text inputs. Merges the given texts to one new</item><item><b>Substring:</b> Needs the first text inputs and both number inputs (X,Y). Returns the substring from X with length Y at the text output</item><item><b>To-Lowercase:</b> Converts the given text of the first text input to a text with only lowercase characters</item><item><b>To-Uppercase:</b> Converts the given text of the first text input to a text with only uppercase characters</item><item><b>LengthOf:</b> Returns the length of the text of the first text input at the number output</item><item><b>CompareTo:</b> Compares both given texts and returns 0 if they are equal, -1 if text one is 'smaller' than text two, and 1 if text one is 'bigger' than text two</item><item><b>Trim:</b> Removes whitespaces from beginning and end (tab, space) of the text of text input one and returns this text in the text output</item><item><b>IndexOf:</b> Gives the first index of the occurance of the text of text input two in the text of text input one in the number output</item><item><b>Equals:</b> Returns 1 at the number output if the texts are equal, otherwise 0</item><item><b>Replace:</b> Replaces all substrings of the first input string which are equal to the second input string by the third input string and returns the new string</item><item><b>RegexReplace:</b> Replaces all substrings of the first input string which match to the regular expression provided by the second input string by the third input string and returns the new string</item><item><b>Split:</b> Splits the text of the first input at the string given at the second text input (or into characters, if second input is empty) and returns the resulting substrings at the output array</item><item><b>Block:</b> Formats the given string into blocks (using the setting "Block size") after removing all whitespace characters</item><item><b>Reverse:</b> Reverses the given text of the first text input</item><item><b>Password Replace:</b> Adds a password at the front or tail of the string and removes all occuring characters of this password in the rest of the string</item><item><b>Distinct:</b> Removes all double occurences of same symbols from the string</item><item><b>Levenshtein Distance:</b> Calculates the Levenshtein Distance of two given strings</item></enum></usage>
  <usage lang="zh-CN">StringOperations具有两个文本输入和两个数字输入。根据所使用的功能，这些输入具有不同的用法。它还具有文本输出，文本数组输出和数字输出。串联：仅需要文本输入。将给定的文本合并到一个newSubstring中：需要第一个文本输入和两个数字输入（X，Y）。返回X处文本输出处的长度为Y的子字符串To-Lowercase：将第一个文本输入的给定文本转换为仅包含小写字符的文本To-Uppercase：将第一个文本输入的给定文本转换为仅包含大写字符的文本：返回数字为number的第一个文本输入的文本的长度比较比较：比较两个给定文本，如果相等则返回0，如果文本“小于”文本则返回-1，如果文本“大于”则返回1。 &amp;#39;而不是文本twoTrim：从文本输入one的文本的开头和结尾（制表符，空格）中删除空格，并在文本中返回此文本outputIndexOf：给出文本输入2的出现在文本中的第一个索引文本输入数字中的一个输出等于：如果文本相等，则在数字输出中返回1，否则返回0替换：用第三输入字符串替换第一输入字符串中与第二输入字符串相同的所有子字符串，并返回新的字符串RegexR eplace：将第一个输入字符串的所有与第二个输入字符串提供的正则表达式匹配的子字符串替换为第三个输入字符串，并返回新的字符串。Split：将第一个输入的文本拆分为第二个文本输入给定的字符串（或字符（如果第二个输入为空），并在输出array处返回结果子字符串块：删除所有空格字符后，将给定的字符串格式化为块（使用设置“块大小”）反向：反转第一个文本输入的给定文本替换：在字符串的开头或结尾添加密码，并在字符串的其余部分删除该密码的所有出现的字符区别：从字符串中删除相同符号的所有重复出现两次：Levenshtein Distance：计算两个给定字符串的Levenshtein距离</usage>
  <usage lang="ru">У StringOperations есть два текстовых ввода и два ввода номера. В зависимости от используемой функции эти входы имеют различное использование. Он также имеет текстовый вывод, вывод текстового массива и вывод номера. Конкатенация: требуется только текстовые входы. Объединение заданных текстов в одну новую строку. Требуется первые текстовые входы и оба ввода номера (X, Y). Возвращает подстроку из X с длиной Y в тексте outputTo-Lowercase: преобразует заданный текст первого текстового ввода в текст только с строчными буквами. To-Uppercase: преобразует заданный текст первого текстового ввода в текст только с прописными буквамиLengthOf : Возвращает длину текста первого ввода текста на номере outputCompareTo: сравнивает оба заданных текста и возвращает 0, если они равны, -1, если текст один «меньше», чем текст 2, и 1, если текст один больше &amp;#39;than text twoTrim: удаляет пробелы с начала и конца (вкладка Leerzeichen) текста ввода текста один и возвращает этот текст в текст outputIndexOf: дает первый индекс заполнения текста текстового ввода два в тексте ввод текста один в число outputEquals: возвращает 1 на выходе номера, если тексты равны, в противном случае 0Replace: заменяет все подстроки первой входной строки, которые равны второй входной строке третьей входной строкой и возвращает новую строку RegexReplace: Заменяет все подстроки первой входной строки, которые соответствуют регулярному выражению, предоставленному второй входной строкой, третьей входной строкой и возвращает новую строкуSplit: разделяет текст первого ввода на строку, указанную во втором текстовом вводе ( или в новых строках, если ввод пуст) и возвращает полученные подстроки в выходном массивеBlock: Форматирует заданную строку в блоки (используя параметр «Размер блока») после удаления всех символов пробелов. Обороты: Обрабатывает заданный текст первого ввода текста. Заменяет пароль. : Добавляет пароль спереди или хвосту строки и удаляет все возникающие символы этого пароля в остальной части stringDistinct: удаляет все двойные вхождения одних и тех же символов из строкиLevenshtein Distance: вычисляет расстояние Levenshtein двух заданных строк</usage>
  <usage lang="de-DE">
    Die Zeichenketten-Operationen verfügen über zwei Texteingänge und zwei Zahleneingänge. Je nach gewählter Funktion werden diese Eingänge
    unterschiedlich verwendet. Außerdem besitzt die Komponente einen Textausgang, einen Text-Array-Ausgang und einen Zahlenausgang.
    <enum><item><b>Konkatenieren:</b> Benötigt nur die beiden Texteingänge. Verbindet die beiden Zeichenketten zu einer und gibt diese am Textausgang aus</item><item><b>Teilstring:</b> Benötigt den ersten Texteingang sowie beide Zahleneingänge (X,Y). Gibt die Zeichenkette von X der Länge Y am Textausgang aus</item><item><b>Kleinbuchstaben:</b> Wandelt den übergebenen Text des ersten Texteingangs in einen Text um, der nur aus Kleinbuchstaben besteht</item><item><b>Großbuchstaben:</b> Wandelt den übergebenen Text des ersten Texteingangs in einen Text um, der nur aus Großbuchstaben besteht</item><item><b>Länge:</b> Gibt die Textlänge (Anzahl der Zeichen) des Textes des ersten Textingangs am Zahlenausgang aus</item><item><b>Vergleichen:</b> Vergleicht die in beiden Texteingängen eingegebenen Texte und gibt 0 aus, falls diese identisch sind, -1, wenn der erste Text "kleiner" als der zweite ist, und 1, wenn der erste Text "größer" als der zweite ist</item><item><b>Trimmen:</b> Entfernt sogenannte Whitespaces (Tab, Leerzeichen) vom Anfang und Ende des Textes, der am ersten Texteingang übergeben wurde und gibt diesen am Textausgang aus</item><item><b>IndexVon:</b> Gibt den ersten Index des Vorkommens vom Text des Texteingangs zwei des Texteingangs eins am Zahlenausgang aus</item><item><b>Gleichheit:</b> Gibt 1 aus, wenn beide Texte identisch sind, andernfalls 0</item><item><b>Ersetzen:</b> Ersetzt alle Teiltexte des ersten Texteingangs mit dem Text des dritten Texteingangs, falls diese Teile gleich dem Text des Textes des zweiten Texteingangs sind</item><item><b>RegexErsetzen:</b> Ersetzt alle Teiltexte des ersten Texteingangs mit dem Text des dritten Texteingangs, falls diese den regulären Ausdruck des zweiten Texteingangs erfüllen</item><item><b>Trennen:</b> Trennt den Text am ersten Texteingang an der Zeichenkette, die am zweiten Texteingang anliegt (oder in Einzelzeichen, falls nichts anliegt), und gibt die resultierenden Teilstrings am Zeichenketten-Array-Ausgang aus</item><item><b>Block:</b> Formatiert den eingegangenen Text in Blöcke (unter Nutzung der Einstellung "Blockgröße"), nachdem alle Leerzeichen (Whitespaces) entfernt wurden</item><item><b>Umkehren:</b> Kehrt die Zeichenkette des ersten Texteingangs um</item><item><b>Passwortersetzung:</b>Fügt einem Text ein Passwort am Anfang oder Ende hinzu und entfernt alle Zeichen des Passwortes aus dem restlichen Text</item><item><b>Eindeutig:</b> Entfernt alle doppelten Vorkommen von gleichen Symbolen aus dem Text</item><item><b>Levenshtein-Distanz:</b> Berechnet die Levenshtein-Distanz von zwei gegebenen Texten</item></enum></usage>
  <presentation lang="en"></presentation>
  <presentation lang="de-DE"></presentation>
  <references>
    <linkReference>
      <link lang="en" url="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/String_%28computer_science%29" />
      <caption lang="en">String</caption>
      <link lang="de-DE" url="http://de.wikipedia.org/wiki/Zeichenkette" />
      <caption lang="de-DE">Zeichenkette</caption>
    </linkReference>
    <linkReference>
      <link lang="en" url="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Levenshtein_distance" />
      <caption lang="de-DE">Levenshtein Distance</caption>
      <link lang="en" url="http://de.wikipedia.org/wiki/Levenshtein-Distanz" />
      <caption lang="de-DE">Levenshtein-Distanz</caption>
    </linkReference>
  </references>
</documentation>