<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!-- You can edit this file manually or with the Util/CrypDocumentationEditor -->
<documentation>
  <language culture="en" />
  <language culture="de-DE" />
  <introduction lang="en">
    This plugin checks if an incoming message has a correct (PKCS#7) padding.<newline />
    In this padding scheme, the padding is appended after the message with as many bytes
    as required, and each byte has as value the total padding length. As an example it is assumed
    that the message 61 62 63 shall be padded to 8 bytes. The PKCS#7 scheme then goes: The
    number of required padding bytes (&gt; 0) is encoded with binary encoding in one byte. This
    byte is used one or several times to pad the message. Example: 61 62 63 05 05 05 05 05.
    <newline />
    The plugin then returns either true or false, depending on the result of the check.
    <newline />
    Notice: The plugin expects a 2-block message of anz size, so it automatically deletes the first block (aka the first half of the message).

  </introduction>
  <introduction lang="de-DE">
    Dieses Plugin überprüft, ob eine Nachricht ein gültiges (PKCS#7-konformes) Padding hat.<newline />
    Bei diesem Padding-Schema wird das Padding an das Ende der Nachricht gehängt. Es werden so viele
    Padding-Bytes hinzugefügt, dass es nur volle Nachrichten-Blöcke gibt. Die Werte der Padding-Bytes
    entsprechen dabei der Gesamt-Padding-Länge. Als Beispiel gehen wir davon aus, dass wir die Nachricht
    61 62 63 padden müssen, um eine 8-Byte lange Nachricht zu erhalten. Da wir dazu 5 Padding-Bytes brauchen,
    lautet die gepaddete Nachricht 61 62 63 05 05 05 05 05.
    <newline />
    Dieses Plugin gibt entweder true oder false zurück, abhängig vom Ergebnis der Überprüfung.
    <newline />
    Hinweis: Dieses Plugin erwartet eine Nachricht mit 2 Blöcken, d.h. der erste Block (die erste Hälfte der Nachricht) wird automatisch gelöscht.
  </introduction>
  <usage lang="en">
    This plugin is intended to be used with the Padding Oracle Attack Plugin, although it can be used with other plugins as well.
    It just requires a (decrypted) message as input.
  </usage>
  <usage lang="de-DE">
    Dieses Plugin wurde ursprünglich für das Padding Oracle Attack Plugin entwickelt. Es kann jedoch auch mit anderen Plugins benutzt werden.
    Das Plugin benötigt nur eine (entschlüsselte) Nachricht als Input.
  </usage>
  <presentation lang="en">
    The presentation view displays the second half (second block) of the input message. It also adds a green border to display which bytes should have the same value, according to the last byte.
    The validity of the padding is also displayed in the presentation.
    The presentation can only display 8 bytes at a time. If the message exceeds this value, the plugin allows the user to view all bytes by providing a scroll-functionality.
  </presentation>
  <presentation lang="de-DE">
    Die Präsentations-Ansicht zeigt die zweite Hälfte bzw. den zweiten Block der Input-Nachricht an. Es fügt zusätzlich einen grünen Rahmen hinzu, der darstellt, welche Bytes denselben Wert haben
    sollten. Diese Information basiert auf dem Wert des letzten Bytes. Die Gültigkeit des Paddings ist auch in der Präsentation dargestellt.
    Die Präsentation kann nur 8 Bytes gleichzeitig darstellen. Sollte die Nachricht diese Länge überschreiten, so kann der User trotzdem alle Bytes durch die Scroll-Funktion betrachten.
  </presentation>
  <references>
    <linkReference id="wikipedia">
      <link url="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/PKCS" lang="en" />
      <caption lang="en">Public-Key Cryptography Standards (Wikipedia)</caption>
      <link url="http://de.wikipedia.org/wiki/PKCS" lang="de-DE" />
      <caption lang="de-DE">Public-Key Cryptography Standards (Wikipedia)</caption>
    </linkReference>
    <linkReference id="rsalabs">
      <link url="http://www.rsa.com/rsalabs/node.asp?id=2129" lang="en" />
      <caption lang="en">PKCS #7: Cryptographic Message Syntax Standard</caption>
      <link url="http://www.rsa.com/rsalabs/node.asp?id=2129" lang="de-DE" />
      <caption lang="de-DE">PKCS #7: Cryptographic Message Syntax Standard (englisch)</caption>
    </linkReference>
  </references>
</documentation>