<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>

<!-- You can edit this file manually or with the Util/CrypDocumentationEditor -->
<documentation>
  <language culture="en"/>
  <language culture="de-DE"/>

  <introduction lang="en">
    The Hagelin M-209 is a portable cipher machine used by the U.S. Army during the World War II and until the Korean War.
    The original M-209 is fully analog and has a larger keyspace than the Enigma, the cipher machine used by the Germans in WW2.
    <newline/>
    This analyzer provides two kind of attacks: ciphertext-only and known-plaintext attack.
    <newline/>
    The ciphertext-only attack uses hill climbing and simulated annealing to search for optimal key settings.
    These methods are combinded using a hybrid nested approach. 
    A hill climbing process searches for optimal lug settings and an inner simulated annealing process searches for optimal pin settings for this lug setting.
    <newline/>
    The known-plaintext attack uses hill climbing in three nested loops.
    Each loop applies different kinds of transformations on the key to get the correct key.
    
  </introduction>

  <introduction lang="de-DE">
    Die Hagelin M-209 ist eine tragbare Chiffriemachine, welche vom US-Militär wären dem zweiten Weltkrieg und bis zum Korea Krieg verwendet wurde.
    Die originale M-209 ist vollständig analog und hat einen größeren Schlüsselraum als die Enigma, die von den Deutschen im zweiten Weltkrieg verwendet wurde.
    <newline/>
    Dieser Analysator stellt zwei Arten von Angriffen bereits: ciphertext-only und known-plaintext.
    <newline/>
    Der Ciphertext-Only Angriff verwendet Hillclimbing und Simulated Annealing um nach optimalen Schlüsseleinstellungen zu suchen.
    Diese Methoden werden in einem verschachteltem Hybrid-Ansatz verwendet.
    Ein Hillclimbing Prozess sucht nach optimalen Lug-Einstellungen und ein innerer Simulated Annealing Prozess sucht nach optimalen Pin-Einstellungen.
    <newline/>
    Der Known-Plaintext Angriff verwendet Hillclimbin in drei verschachtelten Schleifen.
    Jede Schleife wendet verschiedene Arten von Transformationen auf den Schlüssel an um den richtigen Schlüssel zu erhalten.
</introduction>

  <usage lang="en">
    In the general block, you can set some general and more commonly needed parameters.
    
    <newline/>
    At first you can select the kind of attack, for this you can choose between the ciphertext-only and the known-plaintext attack.
    <newline/>
    In the 'Cores used' input field, you can set how much cores the application can use for the attack.
    <newline/>
    In the 'Language' menu, you have to set the language of the texts, used for the attacks.
    <newline/>
    In the  'Letter count' menu, you set the number of letters in the used alphabet of the language.
    <newline/>
    In the 'Grams type' menu, you can choose what kind of grams should be used for the scoring function.
    <newline/>
    Using 'Expert mode' checkbox, you can hide and show further settings and parameters for experts.
    
  </usage>

  <usage lang="de-DE">
    Im 'Allgemein' Block kann man allgemeine und häufig genutzte Parameter einstellen.

    <newline/>
    Als erstes kann man die Angriffsart auswählen, dazu kann man zwischen Ciphertext-only und Known-Plaintext wählen.
    <newline/>
    Im 'Verwendete Kerne' Eingabefeld kann man einstellen, wie viele Kerne die Anwendung für den Angriff verwenden darf.
    <newline/>
    Im 'Sprache' Menü kann man die Sprache der Texte angeben, die anmgegriffen werden.
    <newline/>
    Im 'Buchstabenanzahl des Alphabets' Menu kann man die Zahl der Buchstaben der Sprache angeben.e.
    <newline/>
    Im 'Typ von Grams' Menü kann man auswählen, welche Art von Grams für die Auswertungsfunktion verwendet werden soll.
    <newline/>
    Mittels der 'Expertenmodus' Checkbox, kann man sich weitere Einstellungen bzw. Parameter für Experten anzeigen lassen.
  </usage>
  
  <presentation lang="en">
  </presentation>
  
  <presentation lang="de-DE">
  </presentation>
  
  <references>
    <linkReference id="wikipedia">
      <link url="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/M-209" lang="en" />
      <caption lang="en">M209 in Wikipedia</caption>
      <link url="http://de.wikipedia.org/wiki/M-209" lang="de-DE" />
      <caption lang="de-DE">M209 in Wikipedia</caption>
    </linkReference>
  </references>
</documentation>