<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<documentation>
  <language culture="en" />
  <language culture="de-DE" />
  <introduction lang="en">
    Whirlpool is a cryptographic hash function that was designed by the cryptographers Vincent Rijmen und Paulo S. L. M. Barreto in 2000.
    The Whirlpool algorithm calculates a hash value of 512 bits (64 bytes) length from its input. The input may be up to 2^256 bits long.
    No security weaknesses of Whirlpool are as yet known.
    <newline />
    Whirlpool is patent-free and is not subjected to any limitations of use.
    <newline />
    The hash has been recommended by the NESSIE project was also adopted by ISO and IEC as part of the joint ISO/IEC 10118-3 international standard.
  </introduction>
  <introduction lang="de-DE">
    Whirlpool ist eine kryptografische Hash-Funktion und wurde 2000 von den Kryptographen Vincent Rijmen und Paulo S. L. M. Barreto entworfen.
    Der Whirlpool-Algorithmus berechnet für Eingaben mit einer Länge von bis zu 2^256 bit einen Hashwert mit einer Länge von 512 Bits (64 Bytes).
    Bislang sind keine Schwächen des Algorithmus bekannt.
    <newline />
    Whirlpool ist patentfrei und unterliegt keinen Nutzungsbeschränkungen.
    <newline />
    Whirlpool gehört zu den vom Projekt NESSIE empfohlenen kryptografischen Algorithmen und wurde von der ISO mit ISO/IEC 10118-3:2004 standardisiert.
  </introduction>
  <usage lang="en">
    The Whirlpool component expects the data of which to calculate the hash value either as a byte array on the input labeled "Input Data" or as a data stream on the input labeled "Input Stream".
    The resulting hash value is provided at the outputs of the component, again as a byte array and as a data stream.
  </usage>
  <usage lang="de-DE">
    Die Whirlpool-Komponente erwartet die Daten, deren Hashwert berechnet werden soll, entweder als Byte-Array am Eingang "Eingabedaten" oder als Datenstrom am Eingang "Eingabedatenstrom".
    Der resultierende Hashwert wird an den Ausgängen der Komponente wiederum als Datenstrom und als Byte-Array bereitgestellt.
  </usage>
  <presentation lang="en"></presentation>
  <presentation lang="de-DE"></presentation>
  <references>
    <linkReference id="wikipedia">
      <link url="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Whirlpool_(cryptography)" lang="en" />
      <caption lang="en">Whirlpool (Wikipedia)</caption>
      <link url="http://de.wikipedia.org/wiki/Whirlpool_(Algorithmus)" lang="de-DE" />
      <caption lang="de-DE">Whirlpool (Wikipedia)</caption>
    </linkReference>
    <linkReference id="pbarreto">
      <link url="http://www.larc.usp.br/~pbarreto/WhirlpoolPage.html" lang="en" />
      <caption lang="en">The WHIRLPOOL Hash Function</caption>
      <link url="http://www.larc.usp.br/~pbarreto/WhirlpoolPage.html" lang="de-DE" />
      <caption lang="de-DE">The WHIRLPOOL Hash Function (englisch)</caption>
    </linkReference>
  </references>
</documentation>