<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<documentation>
  <language culture="en" />
  <language culture="zh-CN" />
  <language culture="ru" />
  <language culture="de-DE" />
  <introduction lang="en">
    The Berlekamp–Massey algorithm is an algorithm for finding the shortest linear feedback shift register (LFSR) with length L for a given output sequence.
    Equivalently, it will also find the minimal polynomial C of a linear recurrence sequence.
    <newline /><newline />
    The algorithm was designed by Elwyn Berlekamp and James Massey in the years 1968 and 1969.
    It became the key to practical application of the now ubiquitous Reed–Solomon code.
  </introduction>
  <introduction lang="zh-CN">Berlekamp–Massey算法是一种算法，用于为给定的输出序列找到长度为L的最短线性反馈移位寄存器（LFSR）。同样，它还会找到线性递归序列的最小多项式C。该算法是由Elwyn Berlekamp和James Massey在1968年和1969年设计的。它成为现在普遍使用的Reed-Solomon代码实际应用的关键。</introduction>
  <introduction lang="ru">Алгоритм Berlekamp-Massey представляет собой алгоритм поиска кратчайшего линейного сдвигового регистра обратной связи (LFSR) с длиной L для заданной выходной последовательности. Эквивалентно, он также найдет минимальный многочлен C линейной рекуррентной последовательности. Алгоритм был разработан Элвином Берлекампом и Джеймсом Масси в 1968 и 1969 годах. Он стал ключом к практическому применению теперь вездесущего кода Рида-Соломона.</introduction>
  <introduction lang="de-DE">
    Der Berlekamp-Massey-Algorithmus dient dazu, das kürzeste, linear rückgekoppelte Schieberegister (LFSR, linear feedback shift register) zu finden, das eine gegebene Folge von Symbolen ausgibt,
    oder, äquivalent dazu, das Minimalpolynom C einer linearen rekursiven Folge.
    <newline /><newline />
    Das Verfahren wurde von 1968 bis 1969 von Elwyn Berlekamp und James Massey entwickelt.
    Es wurde zum Schlüssel für die praktische Anwendung der heute allgegenwärtigen Reed-Solomon-Codes.
  </introduction>
  <usage lang="en">
    On the input of the component, a string consisting of "0" and "1" is expected, that represents the output of the linear feedback shift register whose minimal polynomial you want to determine.
    When the workspace is started, the component calculates the minimal polynomial and outputs it as a string (for example "x^5 + x^3 + 1") on the output labeled "Feedback polynomial C".
    The degree of the polynomial, that corresponds to the minimal length of a LFSR for the given input, is sent to the output "L".
  </usage>
  <usage lang="zh-CN">在组件的输入上，应包含由“ 0”和“ 1”组成的字符串，该字符串表示要确定其最小多项式的线性反馈移位寄存器的输出。当工作空间启动时，组件将计算最小多项式并将其作为字符串（例如“ x ^ 5 + x ^ 3 + 1”）输出到标记为“反馈多项式C”的输出上。多项式的次数（对应于给定输入的LFSR的最小长度）被发送到输出“ L”。</usage>
  <usage lang="ru">На входе компонента ожидается строка, состоящая из «0» и «1», которая представляет выход линейного сдвигового регистра обратной связи, минимальный полином которого вы хотите определить. Когда рабочая область запущена, компонент вычисляет минимальный многочлен и выводит его как строку (например, «x ^ 5 + x ^ 3 + 1») на выходе с надписью «Полином обратной связи C». Степень полинома, соответствующая минимальной длине LFSR для данного входа, отправляется на выход «L».</usage>
  <usage lang="de-DE">
    Geben Sie am Eingang die aus "0" und "1" bestehende Zeichenkette an, die die Ausgabe des linear rückgekoppelten Schieberegisters darstellt,
    dessen Minimalpolynom bestimmt werden soll.
    Nachdem der Arbeitsbereich gestartet wurde, berechnet die Komponente das Minimalpolynom und gibt dieses als Text am Ausgang "Feedback-Polynom C" aus (zum Beispiel "x^5 + x^3 + 1").
    Der Grad des Polynoms, der der minimalen Länge des für die Eingabe benötigten Schieberegisters entspricht, wird am Ausgang "L" ausgegeben.
  </usage>
  <presentation lang="en">
    The presentation view of the component displays the found minimum polynomial C and the minimal length L.
  </presentation>
  <presentation lang="zh-CN">组件的显示视图显示找到的最小多项式C和最小长度L。</presentation>
  <presentation lang="ru">Представление представления компонента отображает найденный минимальный многочлен C и минимальную длину L.</presentation>
  <presentation lang="de-DE">
    Wenn die Präsentationsansicht der Komponente geöffnet ist, werden das gefundene Minimalpolynom C und die minimale Länge L angezeigt.
  </presentation>
  <references>
    <linkReference id="wikipedia">
      <link url="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Berlekamp–Massey_algorithm" lang="en" />
      <caption lang="en">Berlekamp–Massey algorithm (Wikipedia)</caption>
      <link url="http://de.wikipedia.org/wiki/Berlekamp-Massey-Algorithmus" lang="de-DE" />
      <caption lang="de-DE">Berlekamp-Massey-Algorithmus (Wikipedia)</caption>
    </linkReference>
  </references>
</documentation>