<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<documentation>
  <language culture="en" />
  <language culture="zh-CN" />
  <language culture="ru" />
  <introduction lang="en">
    Salsa20 is one of seven symmetric stream ciphers that was chosen for the final eSTREAM portfolio of the ECRYPT Stream Cipher Project.
    It requires a 64 bits initialization vector (IV) and either a 128 or 256 bits secret key. The cipher is based on a strong cryptographic hash function that
    generates hash values consisting of 64 bytes.
    For each IV Salsa20 produces a sequence of at most 2^64 hash values. Thus, the maximum length of the key stream that Salsa20 can generate per IV is 64 * 2^64 = 2^70 bytes long.
    No attack faster than brute-force has been identified so far.
  </introduction>
  <introduction lang="zh-CN">Salsa20是为ECRYPT流密码项目的最终eSTREAM产品组合选择的七个对称流密码之一。它需要一个64位的初始化向量（IV）和一个128位或256位的秘密密钥。该密码基于强大的加密哈希函数，该函数生成由64个字节组成的哈希值。 Salsa20为每个IV生成最多2 ^ 64个哈希值的序列。因此，Salsa20每个IV可以生成的密钥流的最大长度为64 * 2 ^ 64 = 2 ^ 70字节长。到目前为止，还没有发现比蛮力还要快的攻击。</introduction>
  <introduction lang="ru">Salsa20 является одним из семи симметричных потоковых шифров, который был выбран для окончательного портфеля eSTREAM проекта ECHREPT Stream Cipher. Для этого требуется вектор инициализации 64 бит (IV) и либо секретный ключ 128 или 256 бит. Шифр основан на сильной криптографической хэш-функции, которая генерирует хеш-значения, состоящие из 64 байтов. Для каждого IV Salsa20 получается последовательность не более 2 ^ 64 хэш-значений. Таким образом, максимальная длина ключевого потока, который Salsa20 может генерировать на IV, составляет 64 * 2 ^ 64 = 2 ^ 70 байтов. До сих пор не было обнаружено атаки быстрее, чем грубая сила.</introduction>
  <usage lang="en">
    After dragging the Salsa20 component onto your workspace, you will
    have to attach the three input connectors 'Input', 'Key' and 'IV' to data sources.

    Additionally you have to connect a text output component to the 'Output' connector.
  </usage>
  <usage lang="zh-CN">将Salsa20组件拖到工作区后，必须将三个输入连接器“输入”，“键”和“ IV”连接到数据源。另外，您必须将文本输出组件连接到“输出”连接器。</usage>
  <usage lang="ru">После перетаскивания компонента Salsa20 в рабочее пространство вам необходимо будет подключить три входных разъема «Вход», «Ключ» и «IV» к источникам данных. Кроме того, вам необходимо подключить компонент вывода текста к разъему «Выход».</usage>
  <language culture="de-DE" />
  <introduction lang="de-DE">
    Salsa20 ist eine von sieben symmetrischen Stromchiffren, die für das finale eSTREAM Portfolio des ECRYPT Stream Cipher Project gewählt wurden.
    Sie benötigt einen 64 Bits Initialisierungsvektor (IV) und entweder einen 128 oder 256 Bits Schlüssel.
    Die Chiffre basiert auf einer starken kryptographischen Hash-Funktion, die Hashwerte von 64 Bytes Länge erzeugt.
    Für jeden IV generiert Salsa20 eine Folge von maximal 2^64 dieser Hashwerte. Daher ist der Schlüsselstrom, der aus einem IV erzeugt werden kann, maximal 64 * 2^64 = 2^70 Bytes lang. 
    Es wurde bisher kein Angriff gefunden, der schneller als Brute-Force ist.
  </introduction>
  <usage lang="de-DE">
    Nachdem Sie die Salsa20-Komponente auf den Arbeitsbereich gezogen
    haben, müssen Sie die Eingänge 'Eingabe', 'Schlüssel' und 'IV' mit Datenquellen verbinden.

    Außerdem muss der Ausgang mit einer Textausgabe-Komponente verbunden werden.
  </usage>
  <references>
    <linkReference>
      <link url="http://www.ecrypt.eu.org/stream/salsa20pf.html" lang="en" />
      <caption lang="en">Salsa20 at the eSTREAM Project</caption>
      <link url="http://www.ecrypt.eu.org/stream/salsa20pf.html" lang="de-DE" />
      <caption lang="de-DE">Salsa20 beim eSTREAM Project (englisch)</caption>
    </linkReference>
    <linkReference>
      <link url="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Salsa20" lang="en" />
      <caption lang="en">Salsa20 at Wikipedia</caption>
      <link url="http://de.wikipedia.org/wiki/RC4" lang="de-DE" />
      <caption lang="de-DE">Salsa20 bei Wikipedia (englisch)</caption>
    </linkReference>
  </references>
</documentation>