<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<documentation>
  <language culture="en" />
  <introduction lang="en">
    Salsa20 is one of seven symmetric stream ciphers that was chosen for the final eSTREAM portfolio of the ECRYPT Stream Cipher Project.
    It requires a 64 bits initialization vector (IV) and either a 128 or 256 bits secret key. The cipher is based on a strong cryptographic hash function that
    generates hash values consisting of 64 bytes.
    For each IV Salsa20 produces a sequence of at most 2^64 hash values. Thus, the maximum length of the key stream that Salsa20 can generate per IV is 64 * 2^64 = 2^70 bytes long.
    No attack faster than brute-force has been identified so far.
  </introduction>
  <usage lang="en">
    After dragging the Salsa20 component onto your workspace, you will
    have to attach the three input connectors 'Input', 'Key' and 'IV' to data sources.

    Additionally you have to connect a text output component to the 'Output' connector.
  </usage>
  <language culture="de-DE" />
  <introduction lang="de-DE">
    Salsa20 ist eine von sieben symmetrischen Stromchiffren, die für das finale eSTREAM Portfolio des ECRYPT Stream Cipher Project gewählt wurden.
    Sie benötigt einen 64 Bits Initialisierungsvektor (IV) und entweder einen 128 oder 256 Bits Schlüssel.
    Die Chiffre basiert auf einer starken kryptografischen Hash-Funktion, die Hashwerte von 64 Bytes Länge erzeugt.
    Für jeden IV generiert Salsa20 eine Folge von maximal 2^64 dieser Hashwerte. Daher ist der Schlüsselstrom, der aus einem IV erzeugt werden kann, maximal 64 * 2^64 = 2^70 Bytes lang. 
    Es wurde bisher kein Angriff gefunden, der schneller als Brute-Force ist.
  </introduction>
  <usage lang="de-DE">
    Nachdem Sie die Salsa20-Komponente auf den Arbeitsbereich gezogen
    haben, müssen Sie die Eingänge 'Eingabe', 'Schlüssel' und 'IV' mit Datenquellen verbinden.

    Außerdem muss der Ausgang mit einer Textausgabe-Komponente verbunden werden.
  </usage>
  <references>
    <linkReference>
      <link url="http://www.ecrypt.eu.org/stream/salsa20pf.html" lang="en" />
      <caption lang="en">Salsa20 at the eSTREAM Project</caption>
      <link url="http://www.ecrypt.eu.org/stream/salsa20pf.html" lang="de-DE" />
      <caption lang="de-DE">Salsa20 beim eSTREAM Project (englisch)</caption>
    </linkReference>
    <linkReference>
      <link url="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Salsa20" lang="en" />
      <caption lang="en">Salsa20 at Wikipedia</caption>
      <link url="http://de.wikipedia.org/wiki/RC4" lang="de-DE" />
      <caption lang="de-DE">Salsa20 bei Wikipedia (englisch)</caption>
    </linkReference>
  </references>
</documentation>