<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!-- You can edit this file manually or with the Util/CrypDocumentationEditor -->
<documentation>
  <language culture="en" />
  <introduction lang="en">
    A5/1 is a modern stream cipher that provides privacy for the GSM mobile phone system.
    It consists of three linear shift registers (LFSR) that are mixed with the secret key and the IV (initialization vector),
    in order to provide the keystream, which is later being XORed with the plaintext to give the ciphertext.
    The attack against this cipher takes into consideration all the cases when 2 or 3 feedback shift registers contain all zero values after
    the initialization process.
    In such cases, the keystream generated will be constant, consisting entirely of zeros (the case when the message sent is the plaintext)
    or of entirely ones (the case when the message sent is the complement of the plaintext). 
    This is not a desirable result, meaning that such scenario proves that we are dealing with a weak loaded state.
    When 3 registers are all zero, the IV alone defines the secret key bits. In cases when 2/3 LFSRs are all zero, the register in non-zero state
    together with the IV define the secret key bits. According to our attack, we have to divide the ciphertext into frames, each frame corresponds to one
    IV. Using this IV and guessing the secret key bits (for all the cases when 2 or 3 LFSRs are all zero), we try to decrypt the ciphertext and receive a trial
    plaintext. This trial plaintext is compared with the original plaintext to see if they match. If so, we decrypt the entire plaintext with the known IV and the 
    trial secret key (which happens to be the found key).
  </introduction>
  <usage lang="en">
    First, you have to drag the A5/1 component into the workspace and attach the three text input components (secret key, IV, and plaintext) to data sources.
    Then you have to connect a text output component to the "output" connector, which represents the ciphertext. After that, set the frame count
    in the A5/1 cipher settings.
    After dragging the A5/1 cipher component into the workspace and attaching the input and output connectors with the corresponding components, the user needs
    to drag the A5/1 attack component into the workspace as well. The IV, plaintext, ciphertext (produced with A5/1), and a text input component that represents
    the number of frames used for the attack, are used as input components for the A5/1 attack component. We should mention here that the plaintext is divided
    in frames and each frame corresponds to one known IV. IVs are increased by 1 in each upcoming frame. That's why a different number of frame counts gives
    different results.
    There are two text output components that represent the trial key that is guessed and the corresponding case. 
  </usage>
  <presentation lang="en"></presentation>
  <references>
    <linkReference>
      <link url="http://eprints.qut.edu.au/64105/1/AISC2014􀀀P aper3􀀀f inal:pdf" lang="en" />
      <caption lang="en"> Alhamdan, A., Bartlett H., Dawson E., Simpson L., Wong K. K. H. (2014), Weak key-IV Pairs in the A5/1 Stream Cipher </caption>
    </linkReference>
  </references>
</documentation>