<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<documentation>
  <language culture="en" />
  <introduction lang="en">
    The columnar transposition requires a codeword or a permuted number sequence as key. A matrix is generated, that has the same number of columns as the length of the key, and as many rows as are necessary to enter the entire plaintext
    into the cells of the matrix. Then the key is written over the columns of the matrix, one letter (or number) per column, and the plaintext is entered into the cells of the matrix, row by row.
    If the plaintext does not completely fill the last row of the matrix, the empty cells are either filled with placeholder characters (complete transposition), or they are left empty and are ignored in the further encryption process
    (incomplete transposition). If the key is a codeword, the columns are numbered according to the alphabetical order of the letters of the codeword. The ciphertext is then read out of the matrix row by row in the sequence of the numbering of the rows.
    <newline />
    For the decryption process the receiver of the ciphertext creates an empty matrix and writes the known key over the columns of the matrix. The columns are then numbered in the same way as in the encryption process.
    The ciphertext is then entered column by column in the columns of the matrix in the order of the column numbers. The plaintext can then be read out of the matrix row by row from top to bottom. In case of the incomplete transposition, one has to take 
    into account the number of empty cells in the last row of the matrix. When the ciphertext is entered rowwise, these cells must be left empty. The number Z of non-empty cells in the last row can be calculated from the message length M and the
    length K of the key:
    <newline />
    Z = M mod K
  </introduction>
  <usage lang="en">
    The encryption by transposition can be divided into three steps:

    <enum><item>read the plaintext into the matrix</item><item>transpose the columns/rows</item><item>read the ciphertext out of the matrix</item></enum>

    For each of these operations you can decide whether they should act on rows or columns of the matrix by adjusting it in the settings of the component.
    If you select to enter the ciphertext rowwise into the matrix, the ciphertext is entered into the rows from left to right, otherwise it is entered into the columns from top to bottom.
    Thus there are 8 possibilities to enter the ciphertext into the matrix, of which the complimentary settings generate identical results, leaving only 4 different results (for example read in by <b>column</b>, permute by <b>column</b> and read out by <b>row</b>
    will produce the same output as read in by <b>row</b>, permute by <b>row</b> and read out by <b>column</b>).
    <newline /><newline />
    In the settings of the component you can also select whether it should work in encryption or in decryption mode.
    When you choose decryption, the rows or columns will not be orderd according to the permutation that results from the keyword, but by its inverse.
    Furthermore, the reading-in and reading-out operations are swapped, allowing for the same operation settings for the encryption process as for the decryption process.
  </usage>
  <presentation lang="en">
    The presentation view of the component displays the three steps of the transposition.
    First, the keyword is shown in the center and its letters are numbered in alphabetical sequence, thus giving the sorting order of the rows/columns.
    The plaintext is then displayed on the left side of the presentation view, and later, after the third step, the resulting ciphertext will be shown on the right side.<newline />
    Next, the matrix cells are filled with the plaintext characters.<newline />
    After that, the rows/columns of the matrix are permuted according to the keyword-induced sorting order. The component will mark the two rows/columns it presently swaps as blinking.
    Then the ciphertext will be read out of the matrix and appended to result on the right side of the matrix.<newline />
    The three different phases of the process are also indicated by a label in the lower left of the display and a change of the background color.
    In the settings you can also adjust the speed of the presentation and the way the characters should be displayed during the processing (as ASCII or as hexadecimal numbers).
  </presentation>
  <language culture="de" />
  <introduction lang="de">
    Die Spaltentransposition benutzt als Schlüssel ein Codewort oder eine permutierte Zahlenfolge. Mit Hilfe des Schlüssels wird eine Matrix erzeugt, die die Länge des Schlüssels als Spaltenanzahl aufweist.
    Dann wird der Schlüssel über die Matrix geschrieben und die Buchstaben des Klartextes werden zeilenweise in diese eingetragen. Sollte die Matrix nicht komplett ausgefüllt sein, werden entweder in die leeren Zellen Platzhalter
    einfügt (vollständige Transposition), oder sie bleiben frei und werden im weiteren Verlauf nicht beachtet (unvollständige Transposition). Wird ein Codewort als Schlüssel benutzt, werden die Spalten der Matrix nach der alphabetischen
    Reihenfolge der Buchstaben des Codewortes nummeriert. Anschließend wird die Matrix spaltenweise in der Reihenfolge der Spaltennummerierung ausgelesen.
    <newline />
    Zur Entschlüsselung des Geheimtextes erstellt der Empfänger eine leere Matrix und schreibt den bekannten Schlüssel über diese. Nach dem gleichen Verfahren wie beim Verschlüsseln werden die Spalten der Matrix nummeriert.
    Der Geheimtext wird vom Empfänger spaltenweise nach der Nummerierung in die Matrix eingetragen und kann dann zeilenweise ausgelesen werden. Bei der unvollständigen Transposition muss darauf geachtet werden, wie viele Zellen der
    Matrix in der letzten Zeile bei der Verschlüsselung leer waren bzw. nicht beachtet wurden und beim Eintragen des Geheimtextes frei gelassen werden müssen. Die Anzahl Z der beschriebenen Zellen der letzten Zeile kann man aus der
    Länge N der Nachricht und der Länge S des Schlüssels berechnen:
    <newline />
    Z = N mod S
  </introduction>
  <usage lang="de">
    Der Prozess der Verschlüsselung durch die Transposition wird in drei Operationen unterteilt:

    <enum><item>das Einlesen in die Matrix</item><item>die Transposition der Spalten/Reihen</item><item>das Auslesen aus der Matrix</item></enum>

    Für jede dieser Operationen kann in den Einstellungen gewählt werden, ob diese reihen- oder spaltenweise erfolgen soll. Erfolgt die Einlese-Operation reihenweise, wird der Klartext von links nach rechts in die Matrix eingetragen;
    erfolgt sie spaltenweise, wird von oben nach unten eingelesen.
    Dadurch ergeben sich theoretisch acht verschiedene Möglichkeiten zur Einstellung. Allerdings liefern komplementäre Einstellungen jeweils dasselbe Ergebnis, so dass es real nur vier verschiedene Ergebnisse gibt (z.B. <b>spaltenweise</b> einlesen, <b>spaltenweise</b> Permutation
    und <b>zeilenweise</b> auslesen ergibt dieselbe Ausgabe wie <b>zeilenweise</b> einlesen, <b>zeilenweise</b> Permutation und <b>spaltenweise</b> auslesen).
    <newline /><newline />
    In der Einstellung "Aktion" kann gewählt werden, ob ver- oder entschlüsselt werden soll.
    Wenn "Entschlüsseln" gewählt ist, werden die Zeilen bzw. Spalten nicht gemäß der sich aus dem Schlüsselwort ergebenden Permutation, sondern der zu dieser inversen Permutation geordnet.
    Außerdem werden die Ein- und Auslese-Operation vertauscht.
    Dadurch ist es möglich, für die Entschlüsselung dieselben Operationseinstellungen wie für die Verschlüsselung zu verwenden.
  </usage>
  <presentation lang="de">
    Die Präsentation stellt die drei Operationen nacheinander dar. Zunächst wird in der Mitte das Schlüsselwort eingeblendet sowie die sich aus dem Schlüsselwort ergebende Sortierreihenfolge. Links davon erscheint der Klartext und
    rechts in der dritten Operation der verschlüsselte Text.<newline />
    In der Einlese-Operation wird die Matrix mit dem Klartext befüllt.<newline />
    Danach erfolgt die Transposition der Spalten/Reihen. Zwei Spalten/Reihen, die vertauscht werden sollen, werden markiert, ausgeblendet, vertauscht und wieder eingeblendet.
    Die Auslese-Operation erfolgt ähnlich wie das Einlesen. Eine Spalte/Reihe der Matrix wird ausgeblendet und dem Ausgabetext rechts hinzugefügt.<newline />
    Die Wechsel der einzelnen Operationen werden durch einen Wechsel der Hintergrundfarbe angedeutet. Die aktuelle Operation wird unten links in einem Anzeigefeld angezeigt.
    In den Einstellungen kann die Geschwindigkeit der Präsentation und die Darstellungsform der Zeichen (ASCII oder hexadezimal) gewählt werden.
  </presentation>
  <references>
    <linkReference>
      <link url="http://de.wikipedia.org/wiki/Transposition_(Kryptografie)" lang="de" />
      <caption lang="de">Transposition (Wikipedia)</caption>
      <link url="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Transposition_cipher" lang="en" />
      <caption lang="en">Transposition cipher (Wikipedia)</caption>
    </linkReference>
  </references>
</documentation>