<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<documentation>
  <language culture="en" />
  <language culture="de-DE" />
  <introduction lang="en">
    This plugin attempts to reconstruct some columns of the homophones table from a given ciphertext. The plugin delivers correct results, if the homophones used to encrypt the plaintext were sequentially selected during the encryption process. The implementation of the Spanish Strip Cipher (SSC) in CrypTool2 meets this condition.
    <newline /><section headline="Method">
      By means of the following ciphertext, we briefly outline the method used to reconstruct the columns:
      <newline /><b>27</b> 22 07 20 39 03 97 99 59 78 06 21 73 36 10 08 94 46 56 <b>27</b> 24 17 11 42 59 77 16 34 41 62 73 15 20 36 94 02 85 97 44 <b>27</b> 72 59 73 71 37 29 82 94 45 <b>27</b> 99
      <newline />
      Let’s suppose we want to find the other homophones which are in the same column as the homophone 27. To achieve this, we proceed as follows:
      <newline /><enum><item>
          First, we form sets with the homophones that are between all the homophones 27:
          <newline />
          S1 = {22, 07, 20, 39, 03, 97, 99, 59, 78, 06, 21, 73, 36, 10, 08, 94, 46, 56}
          <newline />
          S2 = {24, 17, 11, 42, 59, 77, 16, 34, 41, 62, 73, 15, 20, 36, 94, 02, 85, 97, 44}
          <newline />
          S3 = {72, 59, 73, 71, 37, 29, 82, 94, 45}.
        </item><item>
          Then, we apply the intersection operation with the sets defined above:
          <newline />
          S1 ∩ S2 ∩ S3 = {59, 73, 94}.
        </item></enum>
      From the result shown above, at least 2 homophones (in case that the homophone 27 is in a column with 3 homophones) or all (in case that the homophone 27 is in a column with 4 homophones) must belong to the same column as the homophone 27.
    </section></introduction>
  <usage lang="en">
    <enum>
      <item> Drag the "Spanish Strip Cipher Analyzer" component into the workspace.</item>
      <item>Drag an input connector into the workspace, and connect it to the left side of the Spanish Strip cipher Analyzer component.</item>
      <item>Drag an output connector into the workspace, and connect it to the right side of the Spanish Strip cipher Analyzer component.</item>
      <item>Enter some ciphertext into the input connector.</item>
      <item>Press the button "Play". In case of success, the reconstructed columns will be displayed at the output connector.</item>
    </enum>
  </usage>
  <introduction lang="de-DE">
    Dies Plug-in versucht, einige Spalten der Homophonen-Tabelle aus einem Chiffretext zu rekonstruieren. Das Plug-in liefert richtige Resultaten vorausgesetzt, dass die homophonen, die für die Verschlüsselung des Klartextes benutzt wurden, sequentiell ausgewählt wurden. Die Implementierung in CrypTool2 erfühlt diese Bedingung.
    <section headline="Method">
      Durch folgenden Chiffretext erklären wir kurz die Methode, die für Rekonstruktion der Spalten verwendet wurde.
      <newline /><b>27</b> 22 07 20 39 03 97 99 59 78 06 21 73 36 10 08 94 46 56 <b>27</b> 24 17 11 42 59 77 16 34 41 62 73 15 20 36 94 02 85 97 44 <b>27</b> 72 59 73 71 37 29 82 94 45 <b>27</b> 99
      <newline />
      Nehmen wir an, dass wir die anderen Homophone, die im selben Spalte mit dem Homophon 27 sind, finden wollen. Um das zu erreichen, wir gehen wie folgt vor:
      <newline /><enum><item>
          Zunächst bilden wir Mengen mit der Homophone, die zwischen aller Homophone 27 sind:
          <newline />
          S1 = {22, 07, 20, 39, 03, 97, 99, 59, 78, 06, 21, 73, 36, 10, 08, 94, 46, 56}
          <newline />
          S2 = {24, 17, 11, 42, 59, 77, 16, 34, 41, 62, 73, 15, 20, 36, 94, 02, 85, 97, 44}
          <newline />
          S3 = {72, 59, 73, 71, 37, 29, 82, 94, 45}.
        </item><item>
          Dann berechnen wir die Schnittmenge von S1, S2 und S3.
          <newline />
          S1 ∩ S2 ∩ S3 = {59, 73, 94}.
        </item></enum>
      Von dem oben gezeigten Resultat müssen mindestens 2 Homophone (im Fall, dass die Homophone 27 zu einer 3-Homophone-Spalte gehört) oder alle (im Fall, dass die Homophone 27 zu einer 4-Homophone-Spalte gehört) zu gleichen Spalte wie das Homophon 27 gehören.
    </section></introduction>
  <usage lang="de-DE">
    <enum>
      <item> Ziehen Sie die „Spanische Strip-Chiffre Analyzer“-Komponente in den Arbeitsbereich. </item>
      <item> Ziehen Sie einen Eingang-Konnektor in den Arbeitsbereich, und verbinden Sie diesen mit der linken Seite der „Spanischen Strip-Chiffre Analyzer“-Komponente. </item>
      <item> Ziehen Sie einen Ausgang-Konnektor in den Arbeitsbereich, und verbinden Sie diesen mit der rechten Seite der „Spanischen Strip-Chiffre Analyzer“-Komponente.</item>
      <item> Geben Sie einen Chiffretext in das Eingabefeld ein. </item>
      <item> Drücken Sie die Taste "Starten". Der rekonstruierte Spalten werden am Ausgang-Konnektor angezeigt.</item>
    </enum>
  </usage>
  <presentation lang="en"></presentation>
  <presentation lang="de-DE"></presentation>
  <references></references>
</documentation>