<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!-- You can edit this file manually or with the Util/CrypDocumentationEditor -->
<documentation>
  <language culture="en" />
  <language culture="zh-CN" />
  <language culture="ru" />
  <language culture="de-DE" />
  <introduction lang="en"> 
		The function KKDF SHA-256 is a key derivation function (KDF). This implementation uses the SHA-256 hash function with the counter-mode. The process is based on the so called HMAC-based Key Derivation Function (HKDF) [1][2]. The HKDF-KDF uses an 8-bit counter. Because of that, the maximum amount of output is limited (256 * length of the used hash function). In the configuration of the plugin you can choose between an implementation with 8-bit counter and one with a 32-bit counter. With the 32-bit counter you can create much longer outputs. <newline /><newline /><b>Attention:</b><newline /> The SHA-2 should not used with a key as prefix, because of a problem with the construction of the hash function (find details on length extension attack [3][4]). This implementation is only for demonstration purpose. The name KKDF is based on the official name of the HMAC-based key derivation functions HKDF. This expresses that the key is used as a key prefix in the pseudo-random function.
	  <section headline="Inputs and Outputs"><list><item><b>Source Key Material:</b> Specifies the source key material (SKM). It is used to calculate the key material.</item><item><b>Key:</b> The key for calculation of the key material. It must be secret.</item><item><b>Length of the output key material (in Byte):</b> Specifies the length of the output key material.</item><item><b>Key Material:</b> After the calculation, the generated key material (KM) is visible in this text field.</item><item><b>Calculation steps:</b> The intermediate steps of the calculation are displayed in this text field.</item></list></section><section headline="Pseudorandom functions and theoretical background">
	  The basics of pseudorandom functions can be found in this <internal ref="../Common/Key derivation functions based on pseudorandom functions_en.html">article</internal> within the CT2 online help.
	  </section></introduction>
  <introduction lang="zh-CN">功能KKDF SHA-256是密钥派生功能（KDF）。此实现将SHA-256哈希函数与计数器模式一起使用。该过程基于所谓的基于HMAC的密钥派生函数（HKDF）[1] [2]。 HKDF-KDF使用8位计数器。因此，最大输出量受到限制（256 *使用的哈希函数的长度）。在插件的配置中，您可以在带有8位计数器的实现和带有32位计数器的实现之间进行选择。使用32位计数器，您可以创建更长的输出。注意：由于散列函数的构造存在问题（找到有关长度扩展攻击的详细信息[3] [4]），SHA-2不应将密钥用作前缀。此实现仅用于演示目的。 KKDF名称基于基于HMAC的密钥派生功能HKDF的正式名称。这表示密钥在伪随机函数中用作密钥前缀。源密钥材料：指定源密钥材料（SKM）。密钥：用于计算密钥材料的密钥。输出密钥材料的长度（以字节为单位）：指定输出密钥材料的长度密钥材料：计算后，生成的密钥材料（KM）在此文本字段中可见计算步骤：计算的中间步骤显示在此文本字段中。伪随机函数的基础知识可以在本文的CT2在线帮助中找到。</introduction>
  <introduction lang="ru">Функция KKDF SHA-256 является ключевой функцией деривации (KDF). Эта реализация использует хэш-функцию SHA-256 с контр-режимом. Процесс основан на так называемой функции деривации ключа HMAC (HKDF) [1] [2]. HKDF-KDF использует 8-разрядный счетчик. Из-за этого максимальный объем вывода ограничен (256 * длина используемой хэш-функции). В конфигурации плагина вы можете выбирать между реализацией с 8-битным счетчиком и одним с 32-разрядным счетчиком. С 32-разрядным счетчиком вы можете создавать гораздо более длинные выходы. Внимание: SHA-2 не должен использоваться с ключом в качестве префикса из-за проблемы с построением хеш-функции (найти информацию об атаке расширения длины [3] [4]). Эта реализация предназначена только для демонстрационных целей. Название KKDF основано на официальном названии функций HKDF, основанных на HMAC. Это говорит о том, что ключ используется в качестве ключевого префикса в псевдослучайной функции. Материал исходного ключа: указывает материал исходного ключа (SKM). Он используется для расчета ключевого материала. Ключ: ключ для вычисления ключевого материала. Он должен быть секретом. Длина выходного ключевого материала (в байте): определяет длину выходного ключевого материала. Материал: после вычисления в этом текстовом поле видна сгенерированный ключевой материал (КМ). Происхождения: промежуточные этапы вычисления отображаются в этом текстовом поле. Основы псевдослучайных функций можно найти в этой статье.</introduction>
  <introduction lang="de-DE">
    Die Funktion KKDF SHA-256 ist eine Schlüsselgenerierungs-Funktion (Key Derivation Function, KDF). Diese Implementierung verwendet den SHA-256 im Counter-Mode. Das Verfahren orientiert sich an der so genannten HMAC-based Key Derivation Function (HKDF) [1][2]. Das HKDF-Verfahren verwendet einen 8-Bit-Zähler, wodurch die zu generierende Schlüssellänge begrenzt ist (256 * Hashlänge). In der Konfiguration des Plugins kann zwischen der Variante mit der Orientierung am HKDF-Verfahren (mit 8-Bit Zähler) und einer Variante mit 32-Bit Zähler gewählt werden. Mit der 32-Bit-Variante lassen sich wesentlich längere Ausgaben erzeugen. <newline /><newline /><b>Achtung:</b><newline /> Der SHA-2 sollte aus Konstruktionsgründen der Hashfunktion nicht mit einem Schlüssel (als Präfix) verwendet werden (siehe Erweiterungsangriff [3][4]). <b>Diese Implementierung dient deshalb ausschließlich zu Demonstrationszwecken</b>. Die Bezeichnung KKDF ist an die offizielle Bezeichnung der HMAC-basierenden Schlüsselgenerierungs-Funktionen HKDF angelehnt. Diese bringt zum Ausdruck, dass der Schlüssel als Key-Prefix in der Pseudozufallsfunktion verwendet wird.
    <section headline="Eingaben und Ausgaben"><list><item><b>Quellschlüssel-Material:</b> Spezifiziert das Quellschlüssel-Material (Source Key Material, SKM). Dieses wird zur Generierung des Schlüsselmaterials verwendet.</item><item><b>Schlüssel:</b> Der Schlüssel wird zur Generierung des Schlüsselmaterials verwendet. Dieser muss geheim sein.</item><item><b>Länge des Schlüsselmaterials (in Byte):</b> Spezifiziert die Länge des zu generierenden Schlüsselmaterials.</item><item><b>Schlüsselmaterial:</b> Nach der Berechnung ist das generierte Schlüsselmaterial (Key Material, KM) in diesem Textfeld zu sehen.</item><item><b>Zwischenschritte der Berechnung:</b> Die Zwischenschritte der Berechnung werden in diesem Textfeld angezeigt.</item></list><section headline=" Pseudozufallsfunktionen und theoretischer Hintergrund">
	  Die Grundlagen zu Pseudozufallsfunktionen können in diesem <internal ref="../Common/Key derivation functions based on pseudorandom functions_de.html">Artikel</internal> in der CT2 Online-Hilfe  gefunden werden.
	</section></section></introduction>
  <usage lang="en">
	The usable inputs and outputs will be explained in the presentation view of the component.
  </usage>
  <usage lang="zh-CN">可用的输入和输出将在组件的显示视图中进行说明。</usage>
  <usage lang="ru">Полезные входы и выходы будут объяснены в представлении о компоненте.</usage>
  <usage lang="de-DE">
	Die verwendeten Ein- und Ausgaben werden zu Beginn in der Präsentations-Ansicht der Komponente erklärt.
  </usage>
  <presentation lang="en">
	By double-clicking on the component "KKDF SHA-256" in the workspace, you can activate the visualization of the calculation. The design and operation of the function will be explained step by step.
  </presentation>
  <presentation lang="zh-CN">通过双击工作区中的组件“ KKDF SHA-256”，可以激活计算的可视化。该功能的设计和操作将逐步说明。</presentation>
  <presentation lang="ru">Дважды щелкнув по компоненту «KKDF SHA-256» в рабочей области, вы можете активировать визуализацию расчета. Конструкция и функционирование функции будут объясняться шаг за шагом.</presentation>
  <presentation lang="de-DE">
	Durch Doppelklick auf die Komponente "KKDF SHA-256" in der Arbeitsfläche können Sie die Visualisierung der Berechnung aktivieren. Dabei wird die ikonifizierte Komponente zu einem Fenster vergrößert, in dem die Konstruktion und die Arbeitsweise der Funktion Schritt für Schritt erklärt werden.
  </presentation>
  <references>
    <linkReference>
      <link url="https://tools.ietf.org/html/rfc5869" lang="en" />
      <caption lang="en">RFC 5869: Extract-and-Expand HKDF. Accessed 01-04-2018</caption>
      <link url="https://tools.ietf.org/html/rfc5869" lang="de-DE" />
      <caption lang="de-DE">RFC 5869: Extract-and-Expand HKDF. Aufgerufen am 01-04-2018</caption>
    </linkReference>
    <linkReference>
      <link url="https://eprint.iacr.org/2010/264.pdf" lang="en" />
      <caption lang="en">Cryptographic Extraction and Key Derivation: The HKDF Scheme. Accessed 01-04-2018</caption>
      <link url="https://eprint.iacr.org/2010/264.pdf" lang="de-DE" />
      <caption lang="de-DE">Cryptographic Extraction and Key Derivation: The HKDF Scheme. Aufgerufen am 01-04-2018</caption>
    </linkReference>
    <linkReference>
      <link url="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Length_extension_attack" lang="en" />
      <caption lang="en">Length extension attack. Accessed 01-04-2018</caption>
      <link url="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Length_extension_attack" lang="de-DE" />
      <caption lang="de-DE">Length extension attack. Aufgerufen am 01-04-2018</caption>
    </linkReference>
    <linkReference>
      <link url="https://www.cryptologie.net/article/417/how-did-length-extension-attacks-made-it-into-sha-2/" lang="en" />
      <caption lang="en">How did length extension attacks made it into SHA-2? Accessed 01-04-2018</caption>
      <link url="https://www.cryptologie.net/article/417/how-did-length-extension-attacks-made-it-into-sha-2/" lang="de-DE" />
      <caption lang="de-DE">How did length extension attacks made it into SHA-2? Aufgerufen am 01-04-2018</caption>
    </linkReference>
  </references>
</documentation>