<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!-- You can edit this file manually or with the Util/CrypDocumentationEditor -->
<documentation>
  <language culture="en" />
  <language culture="zh-CN" />
  <language culture="ru" />
  <introduction lang="en">
    A5/1 is a modern stream cipher that provides privacy for the GSM mobile phone system.
    It consists of three linear shift registers (LFSR) that are mixed with the secret key and the IV (initialization vector),
    in order to provide the keystream, which is later being XORed with the plaintext to give the ciphertext.
    The attack against this cipher takes into consideration all the cases when 2 or 3 feedback shift registers contain all zero values after
    the initialization process.
    In such cases, the keystream generated will be constant, consisting entirely of zeros (the case when the message sent is the plaintext)
    or of entirely ones (the case when the message sent is the complement of the plaintext). 
    This is not a desirable result, meaning that such scenario proves that we are dealing with a weak loaded state.
    When 3 registers are all zero, the IV alone defines the secret key bits. In cases when 2/3 LFSRs are all zero, the register in non-zero state
    together with the IV define the secret key bits. According to our attack, we have to divide the ciphertext into frames, each frame corresponds to one
    IV. Using this IV and guessing the secret key bits (for all the cases when 2 or 3 LFSRs are all zero), we try to decrypt the ciphertext and receive a trial
    plaintext. This trial plaintext is compared with the original plaintext to see if they match. If so, we decrypt the entire plaintext with the known IV and the 
    trial secret key (which happens to be the found key).
  </introduction>
  <introduction lang="zh-CN">A5 / 1是一种现代流密码，可为GSM移动电话系统提供隐私。它由三个线性移位寄存器（LFSR）组成，它们与密钥和IV（初始化向量）混合在一起，以提供密钥流，然后将其与纯文本进行异或以提供密文。在初始化过程之后，针对2个或3个反馈移位寄存器包含全零值的所有情况，都要考虑对这种密码的攻击。在这种情况下，生成的密钥流将是恒定的，完全由零（发送的消息是纯文本的情况）或全部由零（发送的消息是纯文本的补充）组成。这不是理想的结果，这意味着这种情况证明我们正在处理弱负载状态。当3个寄存器全为零时，仅IV定义秘密密钥位。在2/3 LFSR全部为零的情况下，处于非零状态的寄存器与IV一起定义了秘密密钥位。根据我们的攻击，我们必须将密文分成多个帧，每个帧对应一个IV。使用此IV并猜测秘密密钥位（对于2个或3个LFSR全部为零的所有情况），我们尝试解密密文并接收试用明文。将该试验明文与原始明文进行比较，看它们是否匹配。如果是这样，我们将使用已知的IV和试用秘密密钥（恰好是找到的密钥）解密整个明文。</introduction>
  <introduction lang="ru">A5 / 1 - это современный потоковый шифр, который обеспечивает конфиденциальность мобильной системы GSM. Он состоит из трех регистров линейного сдвига (LFSR), которые смешиваются с секретным ключом и IV (вектором инициализации), чтобы обеспечить ключевой поток, который позже будет XORed с открытым текстом, чтобы дать зашифрованный текст. Атака на этот шифр учитывает все случаи, когда 2 или 3 регистра сдвига с обратной связью содержат все нулевые значения после процесса инициализации. В таких случаях генерируемый поток ключей будет постоянным, состоящим целиком из нулей (случай, когда отправленное сообщение является открытым текстом) или полностью одно (случай, когда отправленное сообщение является дополнением к открытому тексту). Это не является желательным результатом, что означает, что такой сценарий доказывает, что мы имеем дело со слабо загруженным состоянием. Когда 3 регистра все равны нулю, только один IV определяет бит секретного ключа. В случаях, когда 2/3 LFSR все равны нулю, регистр в ненулевом состоянии вместе с IV определяет бит секретного ключа. Согласно нашей атаке, мы должны разделить зашифрованный текст на фреймы, каждый кадр соответствует одному IV. Используя этот IV и угадывая секретные ключи (для всех случаев, когда 2 или 3 LFSR все равны нулю), мы пытаемся расшифровать зашифрованный текст и получить пробный открытый текст. Этот пробный открытый текст сравнивается с исходным открытым текстом, чтобы увидеть, соответствуют ли они. Если это так, мы расшифровываем весь открытый текст с помощью известного IV и пробного секретного ключа (который, оказывается, является найденным ключом).</introduction>
  <usage lang="en">
    First, you have to drag the A5/1 component into the workspace and attach the three text input components (secret key, IV, and plaintext) to data sources.
    Then you have to connect a text output component to the "output" connector, which represents the ciphertext. After that, set the frame count
    in the A5/1 cipher settings.
    After dragging the A5/1 cipher component into the workspace and attaching the input and output connectors with the corresponding components, the user needs
    to drag the A5/1 attack component into the workspace as well. The IV, plaintext, ciphertext (produced with A5/1), and a text input component that represents
    the number of frames used for the attack, are used as input components for the A5/1 attack component. We should mention here that the plaintext is divided
    in frames and each frame corresponds to one known IV. IVs are increased by 1 in each upcoming frame. That's why a different number of frame counts gives
    different results.
    There are two text output components that represent the trial key that is guessed and the corresponding case. 
  </usage>
  <usage lang="zh-CN">首先，您必须将A5 / 1组件拖到工作区中，并将三个文本输入组件（秘密键，IV和纯文本）附加到数据源。然后，您必须将文本输出组件连接到代表密文的“输出”连接器。之后，在A5 / 1密码设置中设置帧数。将A5 / 1密码组件拖到工作区中并将输入和输出连接器与相应的组件连接后，用户也需要将A5 / 1攻击组件拖到工作区中。 IV，明文，密文（与A5 / 1一起生成）以及表示攻击所用帧数的文本输入组件用作A5 / 1攻击组件的输入组件。在这里我们应该提到，明文分为几帧，每一帧对应一个已知的IV。 IV在每个即将到来的帧中增加1。这就是为什么不同数量的帧计数产生不同结果的原因。有两个文本输出组件，它们代表猜测的试用密钥和相应的大小写。</usage>
  <usage lang="ru">Во-первых, вы должны перетащить компонент A5 / 1 в рабочую область и прикрепить к ним три компонента ввода текста (секретный ключ, IV и открытый текст). Затем вам нужно подключить текстовый выходной компонент к «выходному» разъему, который представляет зашифрованный текст. После этого установите количество кадров в настройках шифрования A5 / 1. После перетаскивания компонента шифрования A5 / 1 в рабочее пространство и присоединения входных и выходных разъемов с соответствующими компонентами, пользователь должен также перетащить компонент атаки A5 / 1 в рабочую область. IV, открытый текст, зашифрованный текст (созданный с помощью A5 / 1) и компонент ввода текста, который представляет количество кадров, используемых для атаки, используются в качестве входных компонентов для компонента атаки A5 / 1. Здесь мы должны упомянуть, что открытый текст делится на фреймы, и каждый кадр соответствует одному известному IV. IV увеличиваются на 1 в каждом предстоящем кадре. Вот почему различное количество отсчетов кадров дает разные результаты. Есть два текстовых выходных компонента, которые представляют собой пробный ключ, который догадается, и соответствующий случай.</usage>
  <presentation lang="en"></presentation>
  <references>
    <linkReference>
      <link url="http://eprints.qut.edu.au/64105/1/AISC2014􀀀P aper3􀀀f inal:pdf" lang="en" />
      <caption lang="en"> Alhamdan, A., Bartlett H., Dawson E., Simpson L., Wong K. K. H. (2014), Weak key-IV Pairs in the A5/1 Stream Cipher </caption>
    </linkReference>
  </references>
</documentation>