<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<documentation>
  <language culture="en" />
  <language culture="de-DE" />
  <introduction lang="en">
    RSA is an asymmetric algorithm devoloped 1977 by Ronald L. Rivest, Adi Shamir und Leonard Adleman at the Massachusetts Institute of
    Technology. It is known as the first published asymmetric algorithm. The security of RSA is based on the factorization
    problem and the assumption that there is no suitable algorithm to factorize a big number in suitable time
    (this means that a factorization is finished not in centuries but in realistic time like hours or days).
  </introduction>
  <introduction lang="de-DE"> 
    RSA ist ein asymmetrischer Algorithmus, der 1977 von Ronald L. Rivest, Adi Shamir und Leonard Adleman am Massachusetts Institute
    of Technology entwickelt wurde. Er ist als der erste asymmetrische Algorithmus bekannt. Die Sicherheit von RSA basiert auf dem
    Faktorisierungs-Problem und der Annahme, dass es keinen "schnellen" Algorithmus gibt, um große Zahlen in annehmbarer Zeit zu
    faktorisieren (also dass die Faktorisierung nicht in Jahrhunderten, sondern in einer 
    "realistischen" Zeit wie etwa Tagen oder Stunden durchgeführt werden kann).
  </introduction>
  <usage lang="en">
    The RSA plugin has two ways to be used (you can use only one or both simultaneously): The user can use RSA to encrypt 
    and decrypt numbers on the one hand or texts on the other hand.
    To encrypt/decrypt numbers, the user has to provide a number at the number input <b>m</b>/<b>c</b> of the plugin representing the message <b>m</b> or the ciphertext <b>c</b>. The
    resulting number is then provided at the number output connector <b>m</b>/<b>c</b> of the plugin.
    He also has to add a Number Input <b>N</b> representing the modulus <b>N</b> of the RSA algorithm. And the last input he has to add is a Number Input <b>e</b>/<b>d</b> which
    represents the public exponent or the private key depending on encryption or decryption. To encrypt/decrypt texts, the user has to add
    an input byte array and an output byte array. Also the direction (encrypt or decrypt) has to be set in the plugins options.
    He has also to add a Number Input <b>N</b> representing the <b>N</b> of the RSA algorithm. And the last input he has to add is
    a Number Input <b>e</b>/<b>d</b> which represents the public exponent or the private key depending on encryption or decryption.
  </usage>
  <usage lang="de-DE">
    Das RSA Plugin beinhaltet zwei Nutzungsarten (welche auch parallel genutzt werden können): Der Benutzer kann sowohl
    Zahlen als auch Texte ver- und entschlüsseln. Um eine Zahl zu ver- oder entschlüsseln
    muss der Benutzer den Zahleneingang <b>m</b>/<b>c</b>, der die Nachricht <b>m</b> oder den verschlüsselten Text <b>c</b> repräsentiert, verbinden. Desweiteren
    muss der Benutzer den Zahlenausgang <b>m</b>/<b>c</b> verbinden, an dem die ver- oder entschlüsselte Nachricht ausgegeben wird. Für die
    Berechnung müssen außerdem der Eingang <b>N</b> und der Schlüsseleingang <b>e</b>/<b>d</b> verbunden werden. <b>e</b> ist der für eine Verschlüsselung benötigte öffentliche Exponent
    und <b>d</b> der für eine Entschlüsselung benötigte private Schlüssel. Um einen ganzen Text zu ver- oder entschlüsseln, kann der Benutzer den Text an den Texteingang <b>m</b>/<b>c</b>
    anschließen und das Resultat am Textausgang <b>m</b>/<b>c</b> abgreifen. In den Einstellungen des Plugins muss zuletzt noch eingestellt werden, ob ver- oder entschlüsselt werden soll.
  </usage>
  <references>
    <linkReference>
      <link lang="en" url="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/RSA" />
      <caption lang="en">RSA in the English wikipedia</caption>
      <link lang="de-DE" url="http://de.wikipedia.org/wiki/RSA-Kryptosystem" />
      <caption lang="de-DE">RSA-Kryptosystem in der deutschen Wikipedia</caption>
    </linkReference>
  </references>
</documentation>