<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<sample>
  <title lang="en">XOR Cipher</title>
  <title lang="zh">异或密码</title>
  <title lang="ru">XOR Cipher</title>
  <summary lang="en">Usage of the <i>XOR</i> cipher</summary>
  <summary lang="zh">XOR密码的用法</summary>
  <summary lang="ru">Использование шифрования XOR</summary>
  <description lang="en">In cryptography, the one-time pad (OTP) is a type of encryption, which has been proven to be impossible to crack if used correctly. Each bit or character from the plaintext is encrypted by a modular addition with a bit or character from a secret random key (or pad) of the same length as the plaintext, resulting in a ciphertext. If the key is truly random, as large as or greater than the plaintext, never reused in whole or part, and kept secret, the ciphertext will be impossible to decrypt or break without knowing the key. It has also been proven that any cipher with the perfect secrecy property must use keys with effectively the same requirements as OTP keys.[1] However, practical problems have prevented one-time pads from being widely used.<newline /><newline /><external ref="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/One-time_pad" /></description>
  <description lang="zh">在密码术中，一次性密码（OTP）是一种加密类型，已被证明如果正确使用就不可能破解。来自明文的每个位或字符都通过模块化加法来加密，其中包含来自与该明文长度相同的秘密随机密钥（或填充）的位或字符，从而形成密文。如果密钥真正是随机的，大小等于或大于明文，永远不会全部或部分重用，并且是秘密的，那么在不知道密钥的情况下，密文将无法解密或破坏。还已经证明，具有完美保密性的任何密码都必须使用与OTP密钥有效要求相同的密钥。[1]但是，实际问题阻止了一次性垫的广泛使用。</description>
  <description lang="ru">В криптографии одноразовая панель (OTP) - это тип шифрования, который, как было доказано, невозможно взломать при правильном использовании. Каждый бит или символ из открытого текста зашифровывается модульным добавлением с битом или символом из секретного случайного ключа (или пэда) той же длины, что и открытый текст, что приводит к зашифрованному тексту. Если ключ действительно случайный, такой большой или большой, как обычный текст, он никогда не используется полностью или частично и не хранится в секрете, шифрованный текст будет невозможно расшифровать или разбить, не зная ключа. Также было доказано, что любой шифр с идеальным свойством секретности должен использовать ключи с теми же требованиями, что и ключи OTP. [1] Однако практические проблемы не позволили широко использовать одноразовые колодки.</description>
  <keywords>one-time, pad</keywords>
  <keywords lang="zh">一次性垫</keywords>
  <keywords lang="ru">одноразовая прокладка</keywords>
  <title lang="de">XOR-Chiffre</title>
  <summary lang="de">Benutzung der <i>XOR</i>-Chiffre</summary>
  <description lang="de">Das One-Time-Pad (Abkürzung: OTP, deutsch: Einmalverschlüsselung oder Einmalschlüssel-Verfahren, wörtlich Einmal-Block, nicht zu verwechseln mit dem Einmal-Passwort-Verfahren) ist ein symmetrisches Verschlüsselungsverfahren zur geheimen Nachrichtenübermittlung. Kennzeichnend ist, dass ein Schlüssel verwendet wird, der (mindestens) so lang ist wie die Nachricht selbst. Das OTP ist informationstheoretisch sicher und kann nachweislich nicht gebrochen werden – vorausgesetzt, es wird bestimmungsgemäß verwendet. Voraussetzung ist, dass dieser Schlüssel zufällig ist und nur einmal verwendet wird.<newline /><newline />
Das One-Time-Pad gehört zu den polyalphabetischen Substitutions-Verfahren, bei denen die einzelnen Buchstaben (oder Zeichen) in jeweils andere Buchstaben (oder Zeichen) umgewandelt (verschlüsselt) werden.<newline /><newline /><external ref="http://de.wikipedia.org/wiki/One-Time-Pad" /></description>
  <keywords lang="de">one-time, pad</keywords>
  <icon file="XOR.png" />
  <relevantPlugins>
    <plugin name="Xor" />
  </relevantPlugins>
  <replacements lang="de">
    <replacement key="$Plaintext$" value="Nachricht" />
    <replacement key="$Ciphertext (Hex)$" value="Geheimtext (Hex)" />
    <replacement key="$Decrypted Ciphertext$" value="Entschlüsselter Geheimtext" />
    <replacement key="$Key$" value="Schlüssel (Hex)" />
    <replacement key="$StringDecoder$" value="String-Decodierer" />
    <replacement key="$StringEncoder$" value="String-Codierer" />
    <replacement key="$XOR Encode$" value="XOR (verschlüsseln)" />
    <replacement key="$XOR Decode$" value="XOR (entschlüsseln)" />
  </replacements>
  <replacements lang="zh">
    <replacement key="$Plaintext$" value="信息" />
    <replacement key="$Ciphertext (Hex)$" value="密文（十六进制）" />
    <replacement key="$Decrypted Ciphertext$" value="解密密文" />
    <replacement key="$Key$" value="密钥（十六进制）" />
    <replacement key="$StringDecoder$" value="字符串解码器" />
    <replacement key="$StringEncoder$" value="字符串编码器" />
    <replacement key="$XOR Encode$" value="XOR（加密）" />
    <replacement key="$XOR Decode$" value="XOR（解密）" />
  </replacements>
  <replacements lang="ru">
    <replacement key="$Plaintext$" value="сообщение" />
    <replacement key="$Ciphertext (Hex)$" value="Шифрованный текст (Hex)" />
    <replacement key="$Decrypted Ciphertext$" value="Расшифрованный зашифрованный текст" />
    <replacement key="$Key$" value="Ключ (hex)" />
    <replacement key="$StringDecoder$" value="Строка декодера" />
    <replacement key="$StringEncoder$" value="Строка кодировщик" />
    <replacement key="$XOR Encode$" value="XOR (шифрование)" />
    <replacement key="$XOR Decode$" value="XOR (расшифровка)" />
  </replacements>
  <replacements lang="en">
    <replacement key="$Plaintext$" value="Plaintext" />
    <replacement key="$Ciphertext (Hex)$" value="Ciphertext (Hex)" />
    <replacement key="$Decrypted Ciphertext$" value="Decrypted Ciphertext" />
    <replacement key="$Key$" value="Key (Hex)" />
    <replacement key="$StringDecoder$" value="StringDecoder" />
    <replacement key="$StringEncoder$" value="StringEncoder" />
    <replacement key="$XOR Encode$" value="XOR Encode" />
    <replacement key="$XOR Decode$" value="XOR Decode" />
  </replacements>
</sample>