<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<documentation>
  <language culture="en" />
  <language culture="zh-CN" />
  <language culture="ru" />
  <introduction lang="en">
    Salsa20 is one of seven symmetric stream ciphers that was chosen for the final eSTREAM portfolio of the ECRYPT Stream Cipher Project.
    It requires a 64 bits initialization vector and either a 128 or 256 bits secret key. The cipher is based on a strong cryptographic hash function
    and the byte limit for the generated key stream from every IV is 2^70. No attack faster than brute-force has been identified so far.
  </introduction>
  <introduction lang="zh-CN">Salsa20是为ECRYPT流密码项目的最终eSTREAM产品组合选择的七个对称流密码之一。它需要一个64位的初始化向量和一个128位或256位的秘密密钥。该密码基于强大的加密哈希函数，每个IV生成的密钥流的字节限制为2 ^ 70。到目前为止，还没有发现比蛮力还要快的攻击。</introduction>
  <introduction lang="ru">Salsa20 является одним из семи симметричных потоковых шифров, который был выбран для окончательного портфеля eSTREAM проекта ECHREPT Stream Cipher. Для этого требуется вектор инициализации 64 бит и либо секретный ключ 128 или 256 бит. Шифр основан на сильной криптографической хэш-функции, а предел байта для генерируемого ключевого потока из каждого IV равен 2 ^ 70. До сих пор не было обнаружено атаки быстрее, чем грубая сила.</introduction>
  <usage lang="en">
    After dragging the Salsa20 component onto your workspace, you will
    have to attach the three input connectors 'Input', 'Key' and 'IV' to data sources.

    Additionally you have to connect a text output component to the 'Output' connector.
  </usage>
  <usage lang="zh-CN">将Salsa20组件拖到工作区后，必须将三个输入连接器“输入”，“键”和“ IV”连接到数据源。另外，您必须将文本输出组件连接到“输出”连接器。</usage>
  <usage lang="ru">После перетаскивания компонента Salsa20 в рабочее пространство вам необходимо будет подключить три входных разъема «Вход», «Ключ» и «IV» к источникам данных. Кроме того, вам необходимо подключить компонент вывода текста к разъему «Выход».</usage>
  <language culture="de-DE" />
  <introduction lang="de-DE">
    Salsa20 ist eine von sieben symmetrischen Stromchiffren, die für das finale eSTREAM Portfolio des ECRYPT Stream Cipher Project gewählt wurden.
    Sie benötigt einen 64 Bits Initialisierungsvektor und entweder einen 128 oder 256 Bits Schlüssel. Die Chiffre basiert auf einer starken kryptografischen
    Hash-Funktion und das Bytelimit für den generierten Schlüsselstrom aus jedem IV beträgt 2^70. Es wurde bisher kein Angriff gefunden, der schneller als Brute-Force ist.
  </introduction>
  <usage lang="de-DE">
    Nachdem Sie die Salsa20-Komponente auf den Arbeitsbereich gezogen
    haben, müssen Sie die Eingänge 'Eingabe', 'Schlüssel' und 'IV' mit Datenquellen verbinden.

    Außerdem muss der Ausgang mit einer Textausgabe-Komponente verbunden werden.
  </usage>
  <references>
    <linkReference>
      <link url="http://www.ecrypt.eu.org/stream/salsa20pf.html" lang="en" />
      <caption lang="en">Salsa20 at the eSTREAM Project</caption>
      <link url="http://www.ecrypt.eu.org/stream/salsa20pf.html" lang="de-DE" />
      <caption lang="de-DE">Salsa20 beim eSTREAM Project (englisch)</caption>
    </linkReference>
    <linkReference>
      <link url="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Salsa20" lang="en" />
      <caption lang="en">Salsa20 at Wikipedia</caption>
      <link url="http://de.wikipedia.org/wiki/RC4" lang="de-DE" />
      <caption lang="de-DE">Salsa20 bei Wikipedia (englisch)</caption>
    </linkReference>
  </references>
</documentation>