<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<documentation>
  <language culture="en" />
  <language culture="zh-CN" />
  <language culture="ru" />
  <introduction lang="en">
    The <i>Variable</i> component can store and load variables to and from memory. This makes it possible to transfer data between components on the workspace without having to directly connect them.
  </introduction>
  <introduction lang="zh-CN">Variable组件可以将变量存储到内存中或从内存中加载变量。这样就可以在工作空间上的组件之间传输数据，而不必直接连接它们。</introduction>
  <introduction lang="ru">Компонент Variable может хранить и загружать переменные в память и из нее. Это позволяет передавать данные между компонентами в рабочей области, не связывая их напрямую.</introduction>
  <usage lang="en">
    For using variables, pull a <i>Variable Store</i> component onto the workspace and enter the name you want to give to the variable in its settings (for example X).
    Connect the input of the <i>Variable</i> component with the output connector of the component, that delivers the value you want to save in the variable.
    Any data type is accepted as input.
    <newline /><newline />
    To use the stored variable on another place of the workspace, pull a <i>Variable Load</i> component onto the workspace and enter the name you want to give to the variable in the settings of the component.
    If a variable is stored or updated under the name "X" in one place of the worksapce by the <i>Variable Store</i> component, the new value of "X" is automatically available at the <i>Variable Load</i> components that reference "X".
  </usage>
  <usage lang="zh-CN">要使用变量，请将“变量存储”组件拉到工作空间上，然后在其设置中输入要赋予变量的名称（例如X）。将变量组件的输入与组件的输出连接器相连，该连接器将提供您要保存在变量中的值。可以接受任何数据类型作为输入。要在工作空间的另一个位置上使用存储的变量，请将“变量加载”组件拉到工作空间上，然后在组件的设置中输入要赋予变量的名称。如果变量由变量存储部件在工作区的一个位置以名称“ X”存储或更新，则在引用“ X”的变量加载部件中将自动获得新的“ X”值。</usage>
  <usage lang="ru">Для использования переменных вытащите компонент Variable Store в рабочую область и введите имя, которое вы хотите передать переменной в ее настройках (например, X). Подключите вход компонента Variable к выходному разъему компонента, который поставляет значение, которое вы хотите сохранить в переменной. В качестве входных данных принимается любой тип данных. Чтобы использовать сохраненную переменную в другом месте рабочей области, потяните компонент Variable Load в рабочую область и введите имя, которое вы хотите передать переменной в настройках компонента. Если переменная хранится или обновляется под именем «X» в одном месте рабочего компонента компонентом «Переменный магазин», новое значение «X» автоматически доступно в компонентах переменной Load, которые ссылаются на «X».</usage>
  <presentation lang="en"></presentation>
  <language culture="de-DE" />
  <introduction lang="de-DE">
    Mittels der Variablenkomponenten können Variablen im Speicher geschrieben und gelesen werden. So können auch Teile der Arbeitsfläche miteinander kommunizieren, die über keine direkte Verbindung miteinander verfügen.
  </introduction>
  <usage lang="de-DE">
    Um mit Variablen zu arbeiten, wird eine "Variable speichern"-Komponente auf den Arbeitsplatz gezogen. Über eine Einstellung kann der Variablenname eingegeben werden, über den eine "Variable lesen"-Komponente auf diesen Wert
    zugreifen kann.
    Der Variable kann ein Datum eines beliebigen Datentyps übergeben werden.
    <newline /><newline />
    Um an anderer Stelle den Wert der Variable zu nutzen, wird die "Variable lesen"-Komponente auf den Arbeitsplatz gezogen.
    Über eine Einstellung kann der Variablenname, unter dem die Variable zuvor gespeichert wurde, eingegeben werden (z.B. X). Sobald X nun an anderer Stelle im Arbeitsplatz gespeichert wird, gibt die "Variable lesen"-Komponente den
    Wert von X automatisch weiter.
  </usage>
  <presentation lang="de-DE"></presentation>
  <references>
    <linkReference>
      <link url="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Variable_(computer_science)" lang="en" />
      <caption lang="en">Variable (Wikipedia)</caption>
      <link url="http://de.wikipedia.org/wiki/Variable_%28Programmierung%29" lang="de-DE" />
      <caption lang="de-DE">Variable (Wikipedia)</caption>
    </linkReference>
  </references>
</documentation>