<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<documentation>
  <language culture="en" />
  <language culture="zh-CN" />
  <language culture="ru" />
  <language culture="de-DE" />
  <introduction lang="en">
    PRESENT is an example of an SP-network (substitution permutation network) and consists of 31 rounds. 
    The block length is 64 bits and two key lengths of 80 and 128 bits are supported. 
    PRESENT is an ultra-lightweight block cipher, designed to work in extremely constrained environments such as RFID tags and 
    sensor networks with both security and hardware efficiency in mind.
  </introduction>
  <introduction lang="zh-CN">PRESENT是SP网络（替代置换网络）的一个示例，由31个回合组成。块长度为64位，并且支持80和128位的两个密钥长度。 PRESENT是一种超轻量级分组密码，旨在兼顾安全性和硬件效率，在RFID标签和传感器网络等极端受限的环境中工作。</introduction>
  <introduction lang="ru">PRESENT является примером сети SP (сети перестановки подстановок) и состоит из 31 раунда. Длина блока составляет 64 бита, и поддерживаются две длины ключа 80 и 128 бит. PRESENT - это ультралегкий блочный шифр, предназначенный для работы в экстремально ограниченных средах, таких как RFID-теги и сенсорные сети с учетом соображений безопасности и аппаратного обеспечения.</introduction>
  <introduction lang="de-DE">
    PRESENT ist ein Beispiel für ein SP-Netzwerk (Substitutions-Permutations-Netzwerk) und besteht aus 31 Runden.
    Die Blocklänge beträgt 64 Bits, es werden zwei Schlüssellängen von 80 und 128 Bits unterstützt.
    PRESENT ist eine ultra-leichtgewichtige Blockchiffre, die darauf ausgelegt ist, in extrem Ressourcen-beschränkten Umgebungen, wie
    beispielsweise RFID-Tags und Sensornetzwerken, zu arbeiten. PRESENT berücksichtigt damit sowohl Aspekte der Sicherheit als auch der Hardwareeffizienz.
  </introduction>
  <usage lang="en">
    The PRESENT component has the two operation modes "Encryption" and "Decryption". You can switch between the modes in the settings of the component.
    <newline /><newline /><section headline="Encryption">
      In "Encryption" mode, the component expects the plaintext as a data stream on the input labeled "Input".
      If the size of the input is not a multiple of the block size, as many bytes as are necessary to achieve
      a multiple of the block size are padded. You can choose between several padding methods in the settings of the component.
      When decrypting a ciphertext, it is important to select the same padding method as was used for encryption.
      Otherwise the last block will be deciphered wrongly or not at all.
      The key is expected as a byte array on the input labeled "Key".
      If the selected key size does not correspond to the size of the entered key, an error message will be issued and the execution stops.
      The encrypted data block is sent to the output of the component as a data stream.
      <newline /><newline /></section><section headline="Decryption">
      In "Decryption" mode, the component expects the ciphertext that is to be decrypted on the input labeled "Input".
      The size of the input must be a multiple of the block size. Otherwise, the component stops with an error message.
      The key is entered in the same way as in "Encryption" mode.
      Finally, the plaintext will be sent to the output of the component as a data stream.
      <newline /><newline /></section><section headline="Cryptographic Mode">
      Block ciphers divide their input data into blocks of a fixed size and apply the encryption or decryption function on the blocks of the input.
      The chaining mode determines the way in which consecutive blocks, after being encrypted or decryted, are combined in order to achieve better security or error tolerance.
      The PRESENT component offers the following block chaining modes: ECB (Electronic Code Book), CBC (Cipher Block Chaining), CFB (Cipher Feedback) and OFB (Output Feedback).
      Select the appropriate chaining mode in the settings of the component.
      <newline />
      In ECB mode, each block is encrypted separately. In the other modes however, a plaintext block is combined with the previous ciphertext block.
      As there is no previous block for the first block, we must provide one for these modes. This extra block is given by the initialization vector (IV), which must be provided as a byte array
      on the input of the component. Thus the size of the IV must correspond to the block size. If the provided IV is too short, it is filled with null bytes. If it is too long, it is truncated.
      If no IV is given, the component will assume an IV consisting of null bytes.
    </section></usage>
  <usage lang="zh-CN">当前组件具有两种操作模式“加密”和“解密”。您可以在组件设置中的模式之间切换。在“加密”模式下，组件期望纯文本作为输入中标有“输入”的数据流。如果输入的大小不是块大小的倍数，则填充达到块大小的倍数所需的尽可能多的字节。您可以在组件的设置中选择几种填充方法。解密密文时，选择与加密相同的填充方法很重要。否则，最后一块将被错误地解密或根本不会被解密。该键应作为标有“键”的输入上的字节数组。如果所选的密钥大小与输入的密钥大小不符，则会发出错误消息，并停止执行。加密的数据块作为数据流发送到组件的输出。在“解密”模式下，组件期望在标记为“输入”的输入上解密的密文。输入的大小必须是块大小的倍数。否则，组件将停止并显示一条错误消息。密钥的输入方式与“加密”模式下的输入方式相同。最后，纯文本将作为数据流发送到组件的输出。分组密码将其输入数据划分为固定大小的块，并将加密或解密功能应用于输入的块。链接模式确定了对连续块进行加密或解密后对其进行组合的方式，以实现更好的安全性或容错性。 PRESENT组件提供以下块链接模式：ECB（电子代码簿），CBC（密码块链接），CFB（密码反馈）和OFB（输出反馈）。在组件的设置中选择适当的链接模式。在ECB模式下，每个块分别加密。但是，在其他模式下，明文块与先前的密文块组合在一起。由于第一个块没有先前的块，因此我们必须为这些模式提供一个。此额外的块由初始化向量（IV）给出，该向量必须在组件的输入上作为字节数组提供。因此，IV的大小必须与块大小相对应。如果提供的IV太短，则将其填充为空字节。如果太长，它将被截断。如果没有给出IV，则组件将假定IV由空字节组成。</usage>
  <usage lang="ru">Компонент PRESENT имеет два режима работы: «Шифрование» и «Расшифровка». Вы можете переключаться между режимами в настройках компонента. В режиме «Шифрование» компонент ожидает открытый текст как поток данных на входе с надписью «Вход». Если размер ввода не кратен размеру блока, столько байтов, сколько необходимо для достижения кратного размера блока, дополняются. В настройках компонента вы можете выбирать между несколькими способами заполнения. При расшифровке зашифрованного текста важно выбрать тот же метод заполнения, который использовался для шифрования. В противном случае последний блок будет дешифрован неправильно или вообще отсутствует. Ключ ожидается как массив байтов на входе с надписью «Ключ». Если выбранный размер ключа не соответствует размеру введенного ключа, будет выдано сообщение об ошибке, и выполнение прекратится. Зашифрованный блок данных отправляется на выход компонента в виде потока данных. В режиме «Расшифровка» компонент ожидает, что зашифрованный текст будет дешифрован на входе с надписью «Вход». Размер ввода должен быть кратным размеру блока. В противном случае компонент останавливается с сообщением об ошибке. Ключ вводится так же, как в режиме «Шифрование». Наконец, открытый текст будет отправлен на выход компонента в виде потока данных. Блочные шифры делят свои входные данные на блоки фиксированного размера и применяют функцию шифрования или дешифрования на блоках ввода. Режим цепочки определяет способ объединения последовательных блоков после их зашифрования или декомпозиции для обеспечения большей безопасности или допуска допуска ошибок. Компонент PRESENT предлагает следующие режимы цепочки блоков: ECB (электронная кодовая книга), CBC (цепочка блоков шифрования), CFB (обратная связь с шифрованием) и OFB (выходная обратная связь). Выберите подходящий режим цепочки в настройках компонента. В режиме ECB каждый блок зашифровывается отдельно. Однако в других режимах блок открытого текста объединяется с предыдущим блоком зашифрованного текста. Поскольку для первого блока нет предыдущего блока, мы должны предоставить один для этих режимов. Этот дополнительный блок задается вектором инициализации (IV), который должен быть представлен как байтовый массив на входе компонента. Таким образом, размер IV должен соответствовать размеру блока. Если предоставленный IV слишком короткий, он заполняется нулевыми байтами. Если он слишком длинный, он усечен. Если нет IV, компонент будет принимать IV, состоящий из нулевых байтов.</usage>
  <usage lang="de-DE">
    Die Komponente hat die zwei Betriebsarten "Verschlüsselung" und "Entschlüsselung", zwischen denen in den Einstellungen der Komponente umgeschaltet werden kann.
    <newline /><newline /><section headline="Verschlüsselung">
      In der Betriebsart "Verschlüsselung" erwartet die Komponente als Eingabe den zu verschlüsselnden Klartext als Datenstrom am Eingang "Eingabedatenstrom".
      Ist die Länge der Eingabe kein Vielfaches der Blockgröße, so müssen vor der Verschlüsselung so viele Bytes angehängt werden, bis sie ohne Rest in Blöcke der Blockgröße zerlegt werden kann.
      Diesen Vorgang nennt man 'Padding'. In den Einstellungen kann man zwischen verschiedenen Padding-Methoden wählen.
      Es ist wichtig, dass bei der Entschlüsselung eines Chiffretextes in den Einstellungen dieselbe Padding-Methode eingestellt wird, die bei der Verschlüsselung verwendet wurde,
      da der letzte Block sonst falsch oder gar nicht entschlüsselt wird.
      Der Schlüssel wird als Byte-Array am Eingang "Schlüssel" erwartet.
      Stimmt die Größe des eingegebenen Schlüssels nicht mit der erwarteten Schlüsselgröße überein, so wird eine Fehlermeldung ausgegeben und die Ausführung wird beendet.
      Der verschlüsselte Datenblock wird am Ausgang der Komponente als Datenstrom zur Verfügung gestellt.
      <newline /><newline /></section><section headline="Entschlüsselung">
      In der Betriebsart "Entschlüsselung" erwartet die Komponente den zu entschlüsselnden Geheimtext als Datenstrom am Eingang "Eingabedatestrom".
      Die Länge der Eingabe muss hierbei ein Vielfaches der Blockgröße sein, andernfalls wird die Berechnung mit einer Fehlermeldung abgebrochen.
      Der Schlüssel wird wie bei der Entschlüsselung eingegeben. Der entschlüsselte Klartext wird dann schließlich am Ausgang der Komponente als Datenstrom bereitgestellt.
      <newline /><newline /></section><section headline="Kryptographischer Modus">
      Blockverschlüsselungsverfahren unterteilen die Eingabedaten in Blöcke festgelegter Größen und
      wenden die Ver-/Entschlüsselungsfunktion dann fortlaufend auf diese Blöcke an. Der "kryptografische Modus", in dem
      eine Blockchiffre betrieben wird, gibt an, wie die Ergebnisse der Ver- bzw. Entschlüsselung aufeinanderfolgender Blöcke
      miteinander kombiniert werden, um z.B. größere Sicherheit oder Fehlertoleranz zu erzielen. Die PRESENT-Komponente bietet
      die kryptografischen Modi ECB (Electronic Code Book), CBC (Cipher Block Chaining), CFB (Cipher Feedback) und OFB (Output Feedback)
      an, die in den Einstellungen ausgewählt werden können.
      <newline />
      Beim ECB-Modus wird dabei jeder Block separat verschlüsselt. Bei den anderen Modi hingegen
      wird die Verschlüsselung eines Klartextblocks zusätzlich mit dem vorangehenden Geheimtextblock verknüpft. Da für den ersten
      Klartextblock kein vorangehender Geheimtextblock existiert, wird dieser mit einem Initialisierungsvektor verknüpft.
      Dieser muss die verwendete Blockgröße haben und wird am zugehörigen Eingang der Komponente
      als Byte-Array eingegeben. Ein zu kurzer Initialisierungsvektor wird mit Nullbytes aufgefüllt, ein zu langer auf die Blockgröße
      beschnitten. Wird der Eingang nicht verbunden, so wird ein Initialisierungsvektor bestehend aus Nullbytes verwendet.
    </section></usage>
  <presentation lang="en"></presentation>
  <presentation lang="de-DE"></presentation>
  <references>
    <linkReference>
      <link url="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/PRESENT_(cipher)" lang="en" />
      <caption lang="en">PRESENT in Wikipedia</caption>
      <link url="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/PRESENT_(cipher)" lang="en" />
      <caption lang="de-DE">PRESENT in der englischen Wikipedia</caption>
    </linkReference>
    <linkReference>
      <link url="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Substitution-permutation_network" lang="en" />
      <caption lang="en">Substitution permutation network in Wikipedia</caption>
      <link url="http://de.wikipedia.org/wiki/Substitutions-Permutations-Netzwerk " lang="de" />
      <caption lang="de">Substitutions-Permutations-Netzwerk in Wikipedia</caption>
    </linkReference>
    <linkReference>
      <link url="http://homes.esat.kuleuven.be/~abogdano/papers/present_ches07.pdf" lang="en" />
      <caption lang="en">A. Bogdanov, L.R. Knudsen, G. Leander, C. Paar, A. Poschmann, M.J.B. Robshaw, Y. Seurin, and C. Vikkelsoe: "PRESENT: An Ultra-Lightweight Block Cipher", 2007</caption>
    </linkReference>
    <linkReference>
      <link url="http://www.cosic.esat.kuleuven.be/publications/article-1234.pdf" lang="en" />
      <caption lang="en">Onur Özen, Kerem Varici, Cihangir Tezcan, and Celebi Kocair: Lightweight Block Ciphers Revisited:Cryptanalysis of Reduced Round PRESENT and HIGHT</caption>
    </linkReference>
  </references>
</documentation>