<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!-- You can edit this file manually or with the Util/CrypDocumentationEditor -->
<documentation>
  <language culture="en" />
  <language culture="zh-CN" />
  <language culture="ru" />
  <language culture="de-DE" />
  <introduction lang="en">
   Visual codes are a common way to provide information that should be easily read by machines. 
		 <newline />
		The first visual code was patented in 1952 by Norman Joseph Woodland[1] and was based on Morse code. 
		 <newline /><newline />
   There are two main types of visual codes: one-dimensional and two-dimensional.
   <newline />
		One-dimensional codes are also known as "Barcodes". They are mostly very limited in the amount of information they can provide. 
		Therefore, they are usually containing a number that should identify something (e.g.: a product in a supermarket).
		 <newline />
    The applications of two-dimensional visual codes are widely distributed due to their ability to provide much more information. 
		They can save a simple link to a website or entire contact information (see the Vcard template). 
		Other applications are advertisement (e.g.: providing additional information) or proof of payment (e.g.: train tickets, post stamps).
		 <newline /><newline />
    But be aware that visual codes can also contain harmful content, such as a link to a malicious website[2] or malicious code (e.g.: SQL-Injections).
		Though there are simple ways to authenticate the origin of a visual code (see the template "RSA signed QRCode"), almost all visual codes are not signed.
 </introduction>
  <introduction lang="zh-CN">可视代码是提供机器应易于阅读的信息的常用方法。第一个视觉代码是1952年由Norman Joseph Woodland [1]申请专利的，该代码基于莫尔斯电码。视觉代码主要有两种类型：一维和二维。一维代码也称为“条形码”。他们所能提供的信息量大多非常有限。因此，它们通常包含一个应标识事物的数字（例如：超市中的产品）。二维可视代码的应用由于其提供更多信息的能力而广泛分布。他们可以保存指向网站的简单链接或整个联系信息（请参阅Vcard模板）。其他应用是广告（例如：提供其他信息）或付款证明（例如：火车票，邮票）。但是请注意，可视代码还可能包含有害内容，例如指向恶意网站的链接[2]或恶意代码（例如：SQL-Injections）。尽管可以通过简单的方式对可视代码的来源进行身份验证（请参见模板“ RSA签名的QRCode”），但是几乎所有可视代码均未签名。</introduction>
  <introduction lang="ru">Визуальные коды - это общий способ предоставления информации, которая должна быть легко прочитана машинами. Первый визуальный код был запатентован в 1952 году Норман Джозефом Вудландом [1] и основывался на коде Морзе. Существует два основных типа визуальных кодов: одномерные и двумерные. Одномерные коды также известны как «штрих-коды». Они в основном очень ограничены в объеме информации, которую они могут предоставить. Поэтому они обычно содержат число, которое должно идентифицировать что-то (например: продукт в супермаркете). Приложения двумерных визуальных кодов широко распространены из-за их способности предоставлять гораздо больше информации. Они могут сохранить простую ссылку на веб-сайт или всю контактную информацию (см. Шаблон Vcard). Другие заявки - реклама (например, предоставление дополнительной информации) или подтверждение платежа (например: билеты на поезд, почтовые марки). Но имейте в виду, что визуальные коды могут также содержать вредный контент, такой как ссылка на вредоносный веб-сайт [2] или вредоносный код (например, SQL-инъекции). Хотя существуют простые способы аутентификации происхождения визуального кода (см. Шаблон «RSA, подписанный QRCode»), почти все визуальные коды не подписаны.</introduction>
  <introduction lang="de-DE">
    Visuelle Codes sind eine verbreitete Methode um Informationen, die einfach von Maschinen gelesen werden sollen, bereitzustellen. 
		 <newline />
		Der erste visuelle Code wurde 1952 von Norman Joseph Woodland patentiert[1] und basierte auf dem Morsecode.
		 <newline /><newline />
		Es gibt zwei Haupttypen von visuellen Codes, ein- und zweidimensionale.
		 <newline />
		Eindimensionale Codes sind auch als Barcodes bekannt. Sie können nur wenig Informationen speichern und beinhalten deswegen meist nur eine Nummer, die zur Identifikation dient (z.B.: Produkte im Supermarkt).
		 <newline />
		Das Einsatzgebiet von zweidimensionalen visuellen Codes ist weit gefächert, da sie mehr Informationen speichern können.
		Sie können einen einfachen Link zu einer Webseite oder vollständige Kontaktinformationen (siehe Vcard-Vorlage) enthalten. 
		Weitere Anwendungen sind Werbung (z.B. um zusätzliche Informationen bereitzustellen) oder Zahlungsnachweis (z.B. Bahntickets, Briefmarken).
		 <newline /><newline />
    Aber seien Sie sich bewusst, dass ein visueller Code auch schädliche Inhalte enthalten kann, wie zum Beispiel einen Link zu einer bösartigen Webseite [2] oder bösartigen Code (z.B.: SQL-Injektionen).
	 Trotz der Tatsache, dass es sehr einfache Möglichkeiten gibt, die Herkunft eines visuellen Codes zu authentifizieren (siehe die Vorlage "RSA signierter QRCode"), sind fast alle visuellen Codes unsigniert. 
  </introduction>
  <usage lang="en">
	After you drag the component onto your workspace, you have to select the type of the visual code you want to create in the settings of the component.
	 <newline />
  The component will now generate a visual code from your input.
  </usage>
  <usage lang="zh-CN">将组件拖到工作区后，必须在组件的设置中选择要创建的可视代码的类型。该组件现在将根据您的输入生成可视代码。</usage>
  <usage lang="ru">После перетаскивания компонента на рабочую область вы должны выбрать тип визуального кода, который вы хотите создать, в настройках компонента. Компонент теперь генерирует визуальный код из вашего ввода.</usage>
  <usage lang="de-DE">
	 Nachdem Sie die Komponente auf den Arbeitsbereich gezogen haben, müssen Sie in den Einstellungen die Art des Visuellen Codes wählen, den sie erstellen möchten.
	  <newline />
	 Die Komponente wird nun aus Ihrer Eingabe einen visuellen Code generieren.
  </usage>
  <presentation lang="en">
	The presentation displays the generated barcode.
	 <newline />
  If you would like additional information about the structure of the current barcode, you can simply press the "Explain" button.  
  </presentation>
  <presentation lang="zh-CN">演示文稿显示生成的条形码。如果您需要有关当前条形码结构的其他信息，只需按“说明”按钮即可。</presentation>
  <presentation lang="ru">В презентации отображается сгенерированный штрих-код. Если вам нужна дополнительная информация о структуре текущего штрих-кода, вы можете просто нажать кнопку «Объяснить».</presentation>
  <presentation lang="de-DE">
	Die Präsentation zeigt Ihnen den generierten Barcode. 
	 <newline />
  Zusätzliche Informationen über den Aufbau des aktuellen Barcodes erhalten Sie durch Drücken des "Erklären"-Knopfes.
  </presentation>
  <references>
    <linkReference>
      <link url="http://www.google.com/patents?id=vWJoAAAAEBAJ" lang="en" />
      <caption lang="en">first patent</caption>
      <link url="http://www.google.com/patents?id=vWJoAAAAEBAJ" lang="de-DE" />
      <caption lang="de-DE">erstes Patent</caption>
    </linkReference>
    <linkReference>
      <link url="http://www.securelist.com/en/blog/208193145/Its_time_for_malicious_QR_codes" lang="en" />
      <caption lang="en">malicious QRCode</caption>
      <link url="http://www.securelist.com/en/blog/208193145/Its_time_for_malicious_QR_codes" lang="de-DE" />
      <caption lang="de-DE">bösartigen QRCode</caption>
    </linkReference>
    <linkReference>
      <link url="http://www.securitytube.net/video/190" lang="en" />
      <caption lang="en">
        "Toying with Barcodes" at Defcon 16.
        Felix "FX" Lindner demonstrates security vulnerabilities in existing barcode implementations.
      </caption>
      <link url="http://www.securitytube.net/video/190" lang="de-DE" />
      <caption lang="de-DE">
        "Toying with Barcodes" auf der Defcon 16.
        Felix "FX" Lindner demonstriert Sicherheitslücken in existierenden Barcode-Anwendungen.
      </caption>
    </linkReference>
  </references>
</documentation>