<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!-- You can edit this file manually or with the Util/CrypDocumentationEditor -->
<documentation>
  <language culture="en" />
  <language culture="zh-CN" />
  <language culture="de-DE" />
  <introduction lang="en">
	Differential Cryptanalysis (DCA) is an attack method against symmetrical block ciphers. With this attack we try to iteratively restore the round keys. The main element of the DCA are pairs of ciphertext blocks whose plaintext differs in a certain difference. An attempt is made to determine the flow of the blocks through the cipher on the basis of probabilities and thus to find the round keys.
	<section headline="DCA PathFinder component">
	The DCA PathFinder component is the central component at DCA. The component has two functions: On the one hand it contains a presentation with the basics of DCA and on the other hand it controls the attack by examining ciphers for differentials and providing a configuration for the following components. There are three categories of settings in the component: There are tutorial options, speed options, and differential cryptanalysis options. In the tutorial options, the tutorial can be selected and the mode of the component determined. In tutorial mode, the DCA PathFinder displays slides. If this option is not set, the slides are skipped and the user can execute the DCA attack interactively. In automatic mode, no user input is necessary. In the speed options, the number of threads can be configured and whether the component should use precalculated data. In the options for the DCA, you can specify the number of message pairs and the search strategy with which the component search strategy should search the component for differentials or characteristics.
	</section><section headline="Search strategies">
		Four different search strategies are available for searching for differentials or characteristics. These are:
		<list><item>All characteristics by depth search (ACD)</item><item>Best characteristic (heuristic), then differential search (HGT)</item><item>Best characteristic (depth search, global threshold), then differential search (DGT)</item><item>Best characteristic (depth search, global maximum), then differential search (DGM)</item></list>
		ACD determines all characteristics by depth search. In order to save time during the search, a threshold value can be defined in the settings from which the search is aborted.
		HGT searches characteristics heuristiclly. The heuristic consists in the fact that only the difference with the highest probability is used when looking at the difference distribution table of the S-boxes. The characteristic with the highest probability is then used to form a differential. The differential search is a depth search that stops at a definable threshold value.
		DGT also determines characteristics by depth search. The search stops at a definable threshold (which should be higher than ACD). The characteristic with the highest probability is then used to form a differential. The differential search is a depth search that stops at a definable threshold value.
		DGM characteristics are also determined by depth search. The search determines the global maximum. The global maximum is then used to form a differential. The differential search is a depth search that stops at a definable threshold value.
	</section><section headline="Tutorials">
		The DCA tutorial is divided into 3 parts, each of which analyzes a different cipher as the difficulty level increases. 
		In each tutorial a certain part of the procedure is presented in small steps, so that at the end of tutorial 3 a good idea of the attack was given. 
		For each tutorial there is a template, whereby all components are contained with preset settings. 
		In tutorial 1 a cipher is attacked with one encryption round and two round keys. Tutorial 2 attacks a cipher with three encryption rounds and four round keys. 
		Tutorial 3 attacks a cipher with five encryption rounds and six round keys.
		There are two variants of each template: One with activated tutorial mode and one with activated automatic mode.
	</section><section headline="Further components">
	In addition to the DCA PathFinder component, four other components are used for DCA in CT2: DCA PathVisualizer, DCA Oracle, DCA ToyCipher and DCA KeyRecovery. Information on these components can be found in the CT2 online help.
	</section><section headline="Literature reference">
	A basic work for symmetric block ciphers is the book "The Block Cipher Companion" <ref id="TBC" /> by Lars Knudsen and Matthew Robshaw. This book gives a very comprehensive and basic overview of symmetric block ciphers and various attacks. The attack of differential cryptanalysis is fundamentally described.
	</section></introduction>
  <introduction lang="zh-CN">差分密码分析（DCA）是一种针对对称分组密码的攻击方法。通过这种攻击，我们尝试迭代地还原回合密钥。 DCA的主要元素是成对的密文块，其明文具有一定的差异。尝试基于概率来确定通过密码的块的流，从而找到循环密钥。 DCA PathFinder组件是DCA的核心组件。该组件具有两个功能：一方面，它包含有关DCA基础知识的演示；另一方面，它通过检查差异的密码并为以下组件提供配置来控制攻击。组件中有三类设置：有教程选项，速度选项和差分密码分析选项。在教程选项中，可以选择教程并确定组件的模式。在教程模式下，DCA PathFinder显示幻灯片。如果未设置此选项，则跳过幻灯片，并且用户可以交互方式执行DCA攻击。在自动模式下，无需用户输入。在速度选项中，可以配置线程数以及组件是否应使用预先计算的数据。在DCA的选项中，您可以指定消息对的数量和搜索策略，组件搜索策略应使用这些搜索策略搜索组件的差异或特征。四种不同的搜索策略可用于搜索差异或特征。它们是：通过深度搜索（ACD）的所有特征最佳特征（启发式），然后是差分搜索（HGT）最佳特征（深度搜索，全局阈值），然后是差分搜索（DGT）最佳特征（深度搜索，全局最大值），然后差分搜索（DGM）ACD通过深度搜索确定所有特征。为了节省搜索时间，可以在中止搜索的设置中定义一个阈值。 HGT试探性地搜索特征。启发式在于，当查看S盒的差异分布表时，仅使用概率最高的差异。然后将具有最高概率的特性用于形成微分。差分搜索是深度搜索，该深度搜索停止在可定义的阈值上。 DGT还通过深度搜索确定特征。搜索在可定义的阈值（应高于ACD）处停止。然后将具有最高概率的特性用于形成微分。差分搜索是深度搜索，该深度搜索停止在可定义的阈值上。 DGM特性也由深度搜索确定。搜索确定全局最大值。然后使用全局最大值来形成微分。差分搜索是深度搜索，该深度搜索停止在可定义的阈值上。 DCA教程分为3个部分，每个部分都随着难度级别的增加而分析不同的密码。在每个教程中，该过程的特定部分均以小步呈现，因此在教程3的末尾给出了很好的攻击思路。每个教程都有一个模板，其中所有组件都包含有预设设置。在教程1中，使用一轮加密和两轮密钥来攻击密码。教程2使用三个加密回合和四个回合密钥来攻击密码。教程3通过五个加密回合和六个回合密钥来攻击密码。每个模板有两种变体：一种具有激活的教程模式，另一种具有激活的自动模式。除了DCA PathFinder组件外，CT2中的DCA还使用其他四个组件：DCA PathVisualizer，DCA Oracle，DCA ToyCipher和DCA KeyRecovery。这些组件的信息可以在CT2联机帮助中找到。对称分组密码的基础著作是Lars Knudsen和Matthew Robshaw所著的“分组密码伴侣”。本书对对称分组密码和各种攻击进行了非常全面和基本的概述。从根本上描述了差分密码分析的攻击。</introduction>
  <introduction lang="de-DE">
  Differenzielle Kryptoanalyse (DKA) ist ein Angriffsverfahren gegen symmetrische Blockchiffren. Mit diesem Angriff versucht man, iterativ die Rundenschlüssel wiederherzustellen. Hauptelement der DKA sind Paare von Geheimtext-Blöcken, deren Klartexte sich in einer bestimmten Differenz unterscheiden. Es wird versucht, auf Basis von Wahrscheinlichkeiten den Fluss der Blöcke durch die Chiffre zu bestimmen und dadurch die Rundenschlüssel zu finden.
	<section headline="DKA-PfadFinder-Komponente">
	Die DKA-PfadFinder-Komponente ist die zentrale Komponente bei DKA. Die Komponente hat zwei Funktionen: Einerseits enthält sie eine Präsentation mit den Grundlagen zur DKA und anderseits steuert sie den Angriff, indem sie Chiffren nach Differenzialen untersucht und auf deren Basis eine Konfiguration für die nachfolgenden Komponenten bereitstellt. In der Komponente gibt es drei Kategorien von Einstellungen: Es gibt Tutorial-Optionen, Geschwindigkeitsoptionen und Optionen zur differenziellen Kryptoanalyse. In den Tutorial-Optionen kann das Tutorial ausgewählt und der Modus der Komponente bestimmt werden. Im Tutorialmodus zeigt der DKA-PfadFinder Slides an. Ist diese Option nicht gesetzt, werden die Slides übersprungen und der Anwender kann den DKA-Angriff interaktiv durchgeführen. Im automatischen Modus sind keine Eingaben seitens des Anwenders notwendig. In den Geschwindigkeitsoptionen kann die Anzahl der Threads konfiguriert werden und ob die Komponente vorberechnete Daten verwenden soll. In den Optionen zur DKA kann die Anzahl der Nachrichten-Paare spezifiziert werden und mit welcher Suchstrategie die Komponente Suchstrategie die Komponente nach Differenzialen bzw. Charakteristiken suchen soll.
	</section><section headline="Suchstrategien">
		Es stehen vier verschiedene Suchstrategien zur Suche nach Differenzialen bzw. Charakteristiken bereit. Diese sind:
		<list><item>Alle Charakteristiken mittels Tiefensuche (ACT) </item><item>Beste Characteristik (Heuristik, globaler Schwellwert), dann Differenzialsuche (HGS)</item><item>Beste Characteristik (Tiefensuche, globaler Schwellwert), dann Differenzialsuche (TGS)</item><item>Beste Characteristik (Tiefensuche, globales Maximum), dann Differenzialsuche (TGM)</item></list>
		ACT ermittelt alle Charakteristiken mittels Tiefensuche. Um Zeit bei der Suche zu sparen, kann in den Einstellungen ein Schwellwert definiert werden, ab dem die Suche abgebrochen wird.
		HGS sucht Charakteristiken heuristisch. Die Heuristik besteht darin, dass bei der Betrachtung der Differenzenverteilungstabelle der S-Boxen jeweils nur die Differenz verwendet wird, die die höchste Wahrscheinlichkeit hat. Anschließend wird die Charakteristik mit der höchsten Wahrscheinlichkeit verwendet, um ein Differenzial zu bilden. Die Differenzialsuche ist eine Tiefensuche, die bei einem definierbarem Schwellwert abbricht.
		TGS ermittelt Charakteristiken ebenfalls mittels Tiefensuche. Die Suche bricht bei einem definierbaren Schwellwert ab (dieser sollte höher sein als bei ACT). Anschließend wird die Charakteristik mit der höchsten Wahrscheinlichkeit verwendet, um ein Differenzial zu bilden. Die Differenzialsuche ist eine Tiefensuche, die bei einem definierbarem Schwellwert abbricht.
		TGM werden Charakteristiken ebenfalls mittels Tiefensuche. Die Suche ermittelt das globale Maximum. Anschließend wird das globale Maximum verwendet, um ein Differenzial zu bilden. Die Differenzialsuche ist eine Tiefensuche, die bei einem definierbarem Schwellwert abbricht.
	</section><section headline="Tutorials">
		Das Tutorial zur DKA gliedert sich in 3 Teile, die in ansteigendem Schwierigkeitsgrad jeweils eine andere Chiffre analysieren. 
		In jedem Tutorial wird ein bestimmter Teil des Verfahrens kleinschrittig präsentiert, sodass am Ende von Tutorial 3 eine gute Vorstellung des Angriffs vermittelt wurde. 
		Zu jedem Tutorial gibt es eine Vorlage, wobei alle Komponenten mit voreingestellten Einstellungen enthalten sind. 
		In Tutorial 1 wird eine Chiffre mit einer Verschlüsselungsrunde und zwei Rundenschlüsseln angegriffen. In Tutorial 2 wird eine Chiffre mit drei Verschlüsselungsrunden und vier Rundenschlüsseln angegriffen. 
		In Tutorial 3 wird eine Chiffre mit fünf Verschlüsselungsrunden und sechs Rundenschlüsseln angegriffen.
		Zu jeder Vorlage gibt es zwei Varianten: Einmal mit aktiviertem Tutorialmodus und einmal mit aktiviertem automatischem Modus.
	</section><section headline="Weitere Komponenten">
	Neben der DKA-PfadFinder-Komponente werden vier weitere Komponenten zur DKA in CT2 verwendet: DKA-PfadVisualisierer, DKA-Orakel, DKA-ToyCipher und DKA-KeyRecovery. Informationen zu diesen Komponenten sind in der CT2-Onlinehilfe zu finden.
	</section><section headline="Literaturhinweis">
	Ein Standardwerk für symmetrische Blockchiffren ist das Buch "The Block Cipher Companion" <ref id="TBC" /> von Lars Knudsen und Matthew Robshaw. Dieses Buch gibt einen sehr umfangreichen und grundlegenden Überblick über symmetrische Blockchiffren und verschiedene Angriffe. Der Angriff der differenziellen Kryptoanalyse wird grundlegend beschrieben.
	</section></introduction>
  <usage lang="en"></usage>
  <usage lang="de-DE"></usage>
  <presentation lang="en">
	The presentation leads the user through the attack of the DCA. By means of a presentation the basics of the DCA are explained. When attacking a cipher, the user can select S-boxes to control the attack.
  </presentation>
  <presentation lang="zh-CN">该演示将引导用户克服DCA的攻击。通过演示介绍了DCA的基础知识。攻击密码时，用户可以选择S盒来控制攻击。</presentation>
  <presentation lang="de-DE">
	Die Präsentation führt den Anwender durch den Angriff der DKA. Mittels einer Präsentation werden die Grundlagen der DKA vermittelt. Beim Angriff auf eine Chiffre können vom Anwender S-Boxen selektiert werden, um den Angriff zu steuern.
  </presentation>
  <references>
    <linkReference id="TBC">
      <link url="https://www.springer.com/de/book/9783642173417" lang="en" />
      <caption lang="en">The Block Cipher Companion</caption>
      <link url="https://www.springer.com/de/book/9783642173417" lang="de-DE" />
      <caption lang="de-DE">The Block Cipher Companion</caption>
    </linkReference>
  </references>
</documentation>