<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<documentation>
  <language culture="en" />
  <introduction lang="en">
    HC128 is one of seven symmetric stream ciphers that was chosen for the final eSTREAM portfolio of the ECRYPT Stream Cipher Project.
    HC128 is the simplified version of the HC256 stream cipher with a key and initialization vector length of 128 bits.
    The cipher is based on two secret tables each consisting of 512 32-bit elements and a non-linear feedback function.
    Each key/IV pair produces up to 2^64 key stream bits though in practice there is no need to restrict the length as the effect of
    a longer stream is negligible for the security of the message. No attack faster than brute-force has been identified so far.
  </introduction>
  <usage lang="en">
    After dragging the HC128 component onto your workspace, you will
    have to attach the three input connectors 'Input', 'Key' and 'IV' to data sources.

    Additionally you have to connect a text output component to the 'Output' connector.
  </usage>
  <language culture="de" />
  <introduction lang="de">
    HC128 ist eine von sieben symmetrischen Stromchiffren, die für das finale eSTREAM Portfolio des
    ECRYPT Stream Cipher Project gewählt wurden. HC128 ist eine vereinfachte Ausführung der HC256 Stromchiffre mit einem Schlüssel und
    Initialisierungsvektor der Länge 128 Bits. Die Chiffre basiert auf zwei geheimen Tabellen mit je 512 32-bit Elementen und einer
    nicht-linearen Feedback-Funktion. Jedes Schlüssel/IV-Paar produziert bis zu 2^64 Schlüsselstrombits, aber in der Praxis ist es nicht
    notwendig die Länge zu begrenzen, da die Auswirkungen eines längeren Schlüsselstroms für die Sicherheit der Nachricht vernachlässigbar sind.
    Es wurde bisher kein Angriff gefunden, der schneller als Brute-Force ist.
  </introduction>
  <usage lang="de-DE">
    Nachdem Sie die HC128-Komponente auf den Arbeitsbereich gezogen
    haben, müssen Sie die Eingänge 'Eingabe', 'Schlüssel' und 'IV' mit Datenquellen verbinden.

    Außerdem muss der Ausgang mit einer Textausgabe-Komponente verbunden werden.
  </usage>
  <references>
    <linkReference>
      <link url="http://www.ecrypt.eu.org/stream/hcpf.html" lang="en" />
      <caption lang="en">HC128 at the eSTREAM Project</caption>
      <link url="http://www.ecrypt.eu.org/stream/hcpf.html" lang="de-DE" />
      <caption lang="de-DE">HC128 beim eSTREAM Project (englisch)</caption>
    </linkReference>
    <linkReference>
      <link url="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/HC-256" lang="en" />
      <caption lang="en">HC256 at Wikipedia</caption>
      <link url="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/HC-256" lang="de-DE" />
      <caption lang="de-DE">HC256 bei Wikipedia (englisch)</caption>
    </linkReference>
  </references>
</documentation>