<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!-- You can edit this file manually or with the Util/CrypDocumentationEditor -->
<documentation>
  <language culture="en" />
  <language culture="de-DE" />
  <introduction lang="en">    
  In cryptography, Treyfer is a block cipher/MAC designed in 1997 by Gideon Yuval.
  Aimed at smart card applications, the algorithm is extremely simple and compact; it can be implemented in just 29 bytes of 8051 machine code.
  Treyfer has a rather small key size and block size of 64 bits each. 
  All operations are byte-oriented, and there is a single 8×8-bit S-box. 
  The S-box is left undefined; the implementation can simply use whatever data is available in memory. 
  In each round, each byte has added to it the S-box value of the sum of a key byte and the previous data byte, then it is rotated left one bit. 
  The design attempts to compensate for the simplicity of this round transformation by using a large number of rounds (32 in this case).
  </introduction>
  <introduction lang="de-DE"></introduction>
  <usage lang="en">
    The plugin for the Treyfer attack implemented in CrypTool 2 takes three inputs: the plaintext, the key (both must be of length 8), and an
    integer value indicating the number of rounds. The 'number of rounds' parameter must have a positive integer value (up to 32) for the plugin to run.
    Plaintext and key could be any ASCII character. After providing these two parameters and running the algorithm, the ciphertext is produced as output in the field connected to output port of Treyfer.
    Rotation of bits (as it appears in the proposed algorithm) is not employed.
    A simple 8x8 S-box is implemented in the code.
  </usage>
  <usage lang="de-DE"></usage>
  <presentation lang="en"></presentation>
  <presentation lang="de-DE"></presentation>
  <references>
    <linkReference>
      <link url="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Treyfer" lang="en" />
      <caption lang="en">Treyfer (Wikipedia)</caption>
    </linkReference>
    <bookReference>
      <author lang="en">David Wagner, Alex Biryukov</author>
      <publisher lang="de-DE">In: Knudsen L. (eds) Fast Software Encryption. FSE 1999. Lecture Notes in Computer Science, vol 1636. Springer, Berlin, Heidelberg</publisher>
      <name lang="en">Slide Attacks</name>
    </bookReference>
  </references>
</documentation>