<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>

<!-- You can edit this file manually or with the Util/CrypDocumentationEditor -->
<documentation>
  <language culture="en" />
  <language culture="zh-CN" />
  <language culture="ru" />
  <language culture="de-DE" />

  <introduction lang="en">
    The Josse cipher is a cipher invented by Major H. D. Josse (1852-1929). It was developed in France for the Franco-Prussian War (1870-1871) and was used on the battlefield to transmit messages in a secure manner. The cipher was studied and described by Rémi Géraud-Stewart and David Naccache in 2020. <ref id="jossecipherpaper" />. There is also a bachelor thesis in German describing the cipher and its implementation <ref id="weimann_thesis" />.
  </introduction>

  <introduction lang="de-DE">
    Die Josse-Chiffre ist eine Chiffre, die von Major H. D. Josse (1852-1929) erfunden wurde. Sie wurde in Frankreich für den Deutsch-Französischen Krieg (1870-1871) entwickelt und auf dem Schlachtfeld eingesetzt, um Nachrichten sicher zu übermitteln. Die Chiffre wurde von Rémi Géraud-Stewart und David Naccache im Jahr 2020 untersucht und beschrieben. <ref id="jossecipherpaper" />. Es gibt auch eine Bachelorarbeit auf Deutsch, die die Chiffre und ihre Implementierung beschreibt <ref id="weimann_thesis" />.
  </introduction>

  <introduction lang="ru">
    Шифр Жосса - это шифр, изобретенный майором Х. Д. Жоссом (1852-1929). Он был разработан во Франции для франко-прусской войны (1870-1871 гг.) и использовался на поле боя для безопасной передачи сообщений. Шифр был изучен и описан Реми Жеро-Стюартом и Давидом Наккашем в 2020 году. <ref id="jossecipherpaper" />. Существует также бакалаврская работа на немецком языке, описывающая шифр и его реализацию<ref id="weimann_thesis" />.
  </introduction>

  <introduction lang="zh-CN">
    乔塞密码是由H.D.乔塞少校（1852-1929）发明的一种密码。它是在法国为普法战争（1870-1871）开发的，在战场上用于安全地传输信息。Rémi Géraud-Stewart和David Naccache在2020年研究和描述了该密码。<ref id="jossecipherpaper" />。还有一篇德语学士论文描述了该密码及其实现<ref id="weimann_thesis" />。
  </introduction>

  <usage lang="en">
    First, add the Josse Cipher component to your workspace. Next, connect a data source to the input 'text input' and a text output component to the output 'text output'. In the component settings, select a keyword that consists of the characters of the alphabet (note: the character 'w' is not part of the alphabet). If the keyword contains duplicate characters, the component removes the second occurrence and shows a corresponding warning.<newline /><newline />
    If you also want so see a list of the individual calculation steps, additionally connect a text output component with the output 'Calculation steps'. In the settings of the text output component, select the option 'Manual font setting' and choose a mono-spaced font so that the output is displayed correctly. Examples for a mono-spaced font: 'Courier New', 'Consolas', or 'Lucida Console'.
  </usage>

  <usage lang="de-DE">
    Fügen Sie zunächst die Komponente Josse-Chiffre Ihrem Arbeitsbereich hinzu. Verbinden Sie dann eine Texteingabekomponente mit dem Eingang "Texteingabe" und eine Textausgabekomponente mit dem Ausgang "Textausgabe". Wählen Sie in den Komponenteneinstellungen ein Schlüsselwort, das aus den Buchstaben des Alphabets besteht (Hinweis: Der Buchstabe 'w' ist nicht Teil des Alphabets). Enthält das Schlüsselwort doppelte Buchstaben, so entfernt die Komponente deren zweite Vorkommen und zeigt eine entsprechende Warnung an.<newline /><newline />
    Wenn Sie auch eine Liste der einzelnen Berechnungsschritte sehen wollen, schließen Sie zusätzlich eine Textausgabekomponente an dem Ausgang 'Berechnungsschritte' an. Wählen Sie in den Einstellungen der Textausgabekomponente die Option 'Manuelle Schriftart' und wählen Sie eine Mono-Spaced-Schrift, damit die Ausgabe korrekt dargestellt wird. Beispiele für Mono-Spaced-Schriftarten: 'Courier New', 'Consolas' und 'Lucida Console'.
  </usage>

  <usage lang="ru">
    Сначала добавьте компонент Josse Cipher в рабочее пространство. Затем подключите источник данных к входу 'text input' и компонент вывода текста к выходу 'text output'. В настройках компонента выберите ключевое слово, состоящее из символов алфавита (примечание: символ "w" не является частью алфавита). Если ключевое слово содержит дублирующиеся символы, компонент удаляет второе вхождение и показывает соответствующее предупреждение.<newline /><newline />.
    Если вы хотите также видеть список отдельных шагов расчета, дополнительно подключите компонент вывода текста с выводом 'Шаги расчета'. В настройках компонента вывода текста выберите опцию 'Ручная установка шрифта' и выберите шрифт с моноширинным интервалом, чтобы вывод отображался правильно. Примеры моноширинного шрифта: 'Courier New', 'Consolas' или 'Lucida Console'.
  </usage>

  <usage lang="zh-CN">
    首先，将Josse Cipher组件添加到你的工作区。接下来，将一个数据源连接到输入 "text input"，将一个文本输出组件连接到输出 "text output"。在组件设置中，选择一个由字母表中的字符组成的关键词（注意：字符'w'不属于字母表的一部分）。如果关键词包含重复的字符，组件会删除第二次出现的字符并显示相应的警告。<newline />newline />
    如果你还想看到单个计算步骤的列表，可以另外连接一个文本输出组件，输出为 "计算步骤"。在文本输出组件的设置中，选择 "手动字体设置 "选项，并选择一个单行字体，以便正确显示输出。单行字体的例子："Courier New"，"Consolas"，或 "Lucida Console"。
  </usage>
  
  <presentation lang="en">
    The presentation of the component shows in two tabs on the one hand the substitution table that is generated during the execution of the procedure and on the other hand the assignment of the individual letters to the respective digits.
  </presentation>
  
  <presentation lang="de-DE">
    Die Präsentation der Komponente zeigt in zwei Registerkarten zum Einen die Ersetzungstabelle, die während der Ausführung des Verfahrens erzeugt wird und zum Anderen die Zuordnung der einzelnen Buchstaben zu den jeweiligen Ziffern.
  </presentation>

  <presentation lang="ru">
    Представление компонента показывает на двух вкладках, с одной стороны, таблицу замен, которая генерируется во время выполнения процедуры, а с другой - присвоение одиночных букв соответствующим цифрам.
  </presentation>

  <presentation lang="zh-CN">
    该组件的演示在两个标签中显示，一方面是在执行程序过程中产生的替换表，另一方面是将单个字母分配给相应的数字。
  </presentation>
  
  <references>
    <linkReference id="jossecipherpaper">
      <link url="https://doi.org/10.1080/01611194.2020.1753265" lang="de-DE"/>
      <caption lang="de-DE">Rémi Géraud-Stewart, David Naccache. „A French cipher from the late 19thcentury“</caption>
      <link url="https://doi.org/10.1080/01611194.2020.1753265" lang="ru"/>
      <caption lang="ru">Rémi Géraud-Stewart, David Naccache. „A French cipher from the late 19thcentury“</caption>
      <link url="https://doi.org/10.1080/01611194.2020.1753265" lang="en"/>
      <caption lang="en">Rémi Géraud-Stewart, David Naccache. „A French cipher from the late 19thcentury“</caption>
      <link url="https://doi.org/10.1080/01611194.2020.1753265" lang="zh-CN"/>
      <caption lang="zh-CN">Rémi Géraud-Stewart, David Naccache. „A French cipher from the late 19thcentury“</caption>
    </linkReference>
    <linkReference id ="weimann_thesis">
      <link url="https://www.cryptool.org/assets/ctp/documents/BA_Weimann.pdf" lang="de-DE"/>
      <caption lang="de-DE">Niklas Weimann. „Implementierung und Visualisierung verschiedener kryptografischer Handverfahren und Codes in CrypTool 2“. 2021</caption>      
      <link url="https://www.cryptool.org/assets/ctp/documents/BA_Weimann.pdf" lang="ru"/>
      <caption lang="ru">Niklas Weimann. „Implementierung und Visualisierung verschiedener kryptografischer Handverfahren und Codes in CrypTool 2“. 2021</caption>      
      <link url="https://www.cryptool.org/assets/ctp/documents/BA_Weimann.pdf" lang="en"/>
      <caption lang="en">Niklas Weimann. „Implementierung und Visualisierung verschiedener kryptografischer Handverfahren und Codes in CrypTool 2“. 2021</caption>      
      <link url="https://www.cryptool.org/assets/ctp/documents/BA_Weimann.pdf" lang="zh-CN"/>
      <caption lang="zh-CN">Niklas Weimann. „Implementierung und Visualisierung verschiedener kryptografischer Handverfahren und Codes in CrypTool 2“. 2021</caption>
    </linkReference>    
  </references>
</documentation>