<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<documentation>
  <language culture="en" />
  <language culture="zh-CN" />
  <language culture="ru" />
  <introduction lang="en">
    Grain v0 is a stream cipher which is based on two shift registers and a non-linear output function.
    The key size is 80 bits and the size of the initialization vector is 64 bits. 
  </introduction>
  <introduction lang="zh-CN">粒度v0是基于两个移位寄存器和一个非线性输出函数的流密码。密钥大小为80位，初始化向量的大小为64位。</introduction>
  <introduction lang="ru">Grain v0 - это потоковый шифр, основанный на двух сдвиговых регистрах и нелинейной выходной функции. Размер ключа - 80 бит, а размер вектора инициализации - 64 бита.</introduction>
  <usage lang="en">
    After dragging the Grain v0 component onto your workspace, you will
    have to attach the two text input components to the connectors 'Key' and 'IV'. Also, you need to attach one "Number Input" component 
    which indicates the keystream length in bytes.
   
    After that, drag into the workspace one "Text Input" component where you should enter the plaintext and one "XOR" component that is going to be
    used to XOR the plaintext with the output of the cipher (keystream). The result of the XOR is the ciphertext.
    Additionally you have to connect a text output component to the 'Output' connector of the cipher, which is going to represent the keystream.
  </usage>
  <usage lang="zh-CN">将Grain v0组件拖到工作区后，必须将两个文本输入组件连接到连接器“键”和“ IV”。另外，您需要附加一个“数字输入”组件，以字节为单位指示密钥流长度。之后，将一个“文本输入”组件拖到工作区中，在其中应输入纯文本，然后将一个“ XOR”组件拖入工作区，以将明文与密码（密钥流）输出进行异或。 XOR的结果是密文。另外，您必须将文本输出组件连接到密码的“输出”连接器，该连接器将代表密钥流。</usage>
  <usage lang="ru">После перетаскивания компонента Grain v0 в рабочую область вам придется прикрепить два текстовых компонента ввода к ключевым словам и «разъемам» разъемов. Кроме того, вам необходимо подключить один компонент «Количество ввода», который указывает длину ключа в байтах. После этого перетащите в рабочую область один компонент «Text Input», в который вы должны ввести открытый текст и один компонент «XOR», который будет использоваться для XOR открытого текста с выходом шифрования (ключевой поток). Результатом XOR является зашифрованный текст. Кроме того, вам необходимо подключить компонент вывода текста к разъему «Выход» шифра, который будет представлять поток ключей.</usage>
  <references>
    <linkReference>
      <link url="https://eprint.iacr.org/2009/109.pdf" lang="en" />
      <caption lang="en"> Haina Zhang and Xiaoyun Wang, Cryptanalysis of Stream Cipher Grain Family
      </caption>
    </linkReference>
  </references>
</documentation>