<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<documentation>
  <language culture="en" />
  <language culture="zh-CN" />
  <language culture="ru" />
  <language culture="de-DE" />
  <introduction lang="en">
    Mickey 2.0 is a hardware-efficient , synchronous stream cipher. Mickey 2.0 is a part of the eSTREAM portfolio from the ECRYPT Stream Cipher Project.
    The cipher has a key length of 80 bits, and takes an initial value (IV) ranging from 0 to 80 bits in length.
  </introduction>
  <introduction lang="zh-CN">Mickey 2.0是一种硬件高效的同步流密码。 Mickey 2.0是ECRYPT流密码项目的eSTREAM产品组合的一部分。密码的密钥长度为80位，其初始值（IV）的范围为0到80位。</introduction>
  <introduction lang="ru">Mickey 2.0 - это аппаратно-эффективный синхронный потоковый шифр. Mickey 2.0 является частью портфеля eSTREAM из проекта ECRYPT Stream Cipher. Шифр имеет длину ключа 80 бит и принимает начальное значение (IV) в диапазоне от 0 до 80 бит в длину.</introduction>
  <introduction lang="de-DE">
    Mickey 2.0 ist eine Hardware-effiziente, synchrone Stromchiffre. Mickey 2.0 ist ein Teil des eSTREAM-Portfolio des ECRYPT Stream Cipher Projektes.
    Die Chiffre hat eine Schlüssellänge von 80 Bits und benötigt einen Initialsierungsvektor (IV), der zwischen 0 und 80 Bits lang ist.
  </introduction>
  <usage lang="en">
    After dragging the Mickey 2.0 component onto your workspace, you will
    have to attach the three input connectors 'Input', 'Key' and 'IV' to data sources.

    Additionally you have to connect a text output component to the 'Output' connector.
  </usage>
  <usage lang="zh-CN">将Mickey 2.0组件拖到工作区后，必须将三个输入连接器“输入”，“键”和“ IV”连接到数据源。另外，您必须将文本输出组件连接到“输出”连接器。</usage>
  <usage lang="ru">После перетаскивания компонента Mickey 2.0 в рабочее пространство вам необходимо будет подключить три входных разъема «Вход», «Ключ» и «IV» к источникам данных. Кроме того, вам необходимо подключить компонент вывода текста к разъему «Выход».</usage>
  <usage lang="de-DE">
    Nachdem Sie die Mickey 2.0-Komponente auf den Arbeitsbereich gezogen
    haben, müssen Sie die Eingänge 'Eingabe', 'Schlüssel' und 'IV' mit Datenquellen verbinden.

    Außerdem muss der Ausgang mit einer Textausgabe-Komponente verbunden werden.
  </usage>
  <references>
    <linkReference>
      <link url="http://www.ecrypt.eu.org/stream/mickeypf.html" lang="en" />
      <caption lang="en">Mickey 2.0 at the eSTREAM Project</caption>
      <link url="http://www.ecrypt.eu.org/stream/mickeypf.html" lang="de-DE" />
      <caption lang="de-DE">Mickey 2.0 beim eSTREAM Project (englisch)</caption>
    </linkReference>
    <linkReference>
      <link url="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/MICKEY" lang="en" />
      <caption lang="en">Mickey 2.0 at Wikipedia</caption>
      <link url="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/MICKEY" lang="de-DE" />
      <caption lang="de-DE">Mickey 2.0 bei Wikipedia (englisch)</caption>
    </linkReference>
  </references>
</documentation>