<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<documentation>
  <language culture="en" />
  <language culture="de-DE" />
  <introduction lang="en">
    SHA (secure hash algorithm) is a group of cryptographic hash functions that were published by the National Institute of Standards and Technology (NIST).
    This component implements the variants SHA-1, SHA-256, SHA-384 and SHA-512.
    SHA-1 calculates a hash value of 160 bits (20 bytes), SHA-256 of 256 bits (32 bytes), SHA-384 of 384 bits (48 bytes) and SHA-512 of 512 bits (64 bytes).
    For SHA-1 and SHA-256, the input may be up to 2^64 bits long, for SHA-384 and SHA-512 it may be up to 2^128 bits long.
  </introduction>
  <introduction lang="de-DE">
    SHA ("secure hash algorithm", englisch für "sicherer Hash-Algorithmus") bezeichnet eine Gruppe kryptologischer Hashfunktionen, die vom National Institute of Standards and Technology (NIST) veröffentlicht wurden.
    Diese Komponente implementiert die Varianten SHA-1, SHA-256, SHA-384 und SHA-512.
    SHA-1 erzeugt einen Hashwert von 160 Bits (20 Bytes) Länge, SHA-256 von 256 Bits (32 Bytes), SHA-384 von 384 Bits (48 Bytes), und SHA-512 von 512 Bits (64 Bytes).
    Für SHA-1 und SHA-256 beträgt die maximale Länge der Eingabe 2^64 Bits, und für SHA-384 und SHA-512 beträgt sie 2^128 Bits.
  </introduction>
  <usage lang="en">
    In the settings of the component you can select the SHA version you want to use.
    The component provides the variants SHA-1, SHA-256, SHA-384 und SHA-512.
    <newline /><newline />
    The component expects the data of which to calculate the hash value as a data stream on the input labeled "Input stream".
    The resulting hash value is provided at the outputs of the component as a byte array and as a data stream.
  </usage>
  <usage lang="de-DE">
    Wählen Sie in den Einstellungen der Komponente die SHA-Version, die Sie verwenden möchten.
    Es stehen die Varianten SHA-1, SHA-256, SHA-384 und SHA-512 zur Verfügung.
    <newline /><newline />
    Die Komponente erwartet die Daten, deren Hashwert berechnet werden soll, als Datenstrom am Eingang "Eingabedatenstrom".
    Der resultierende Hashwert wird an den Ausgängen der Komponente als Datenstrom und als Byte-Array bereitgestellt.
  </usage>
  <presentation lang="en"></presentation>
  <presentation lang="de-DE"></presentation>
  <references>
    <linkReference id="wikipedia">
      <link url="http://de.wikipedia.org/wiki/Secure_Hash_Algorithm" lang="en" />
      <caption lang="en">Secure Hash Algorithm (Wikipedia)</caption>
      <link url="http://de.wikipedia.org/wiki/Secure_Hash_Algorithm" lang="de-DE" />
      <caption lang="de-DE">Secure Hash Algorithm (Wikipedia)</caption>
    </linkReference>
    <linkReference id="fips">
      <link url="http://csrc.nist.gov/publications/fips/fips180-2/fips180-2withchangenotice.pdf" lang="en" />
      <caption lang="en">FIPS: Secure Hash Standard (PDF)</caption>
      <link url="http://csrc.nist.gov/publications/fips/fips180-2/fips180-2withchangenotice.pdf" lang="de-DE" />
      <caption lang="de-DE">FIPS: Secure Hash Standard (PDF, englisch)</caption>
    </linkReference>
  </references>
</documentation>